<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cumulus NetQ Image and Provisioning Management User Guide on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cumulus NetQ Image and Provisioning Management User Guide on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IPM Preface</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/IPM-Preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/IPM-Preface/</guid>
      <description>A variety of resources are available for you to become familiar with Cumulus Linux and Cumulus NetQ applications. These resources are identified here along with information about how the document contents are presented.
What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus NetQ 1.4.0 Cumulus NetQ 1.4.0 includes the following new features:
 Added
 support for monitoring up to 200 Cumulus Linux nodes 
 validation of symmetric VXLAN routes through CLI
 validation of forward error correction (FEC) operation through NetQL</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPM Command Line Overview</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/IPM-Command-Line-Overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/IPM-Command-Line-Overview/</guid>
      <description>The IPM CLI (TIPCTL) **** behaves in a similar manner to the other Cumulus CLIs . It provides help for commands and options, but it does not support TAB completion of commands  . The commands support four functional categories–configuration, DHCP (dynamic host control protocol), network OS (operating system), and ZTP (zero-touch provisioning): 
 config: sets the network interface the service is bound to (either eth0 or eth1) and the IP address where it publishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activate and Initialize IPM</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/Activate-and-Initialize-IPM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/Activate-and-Initialize-IPM/</guid>
      <description>There is no need to install the IPM software as it comes pre-installed on the NetQ Telemetry Server when NetQ is installed. However, there are a few simple steps needed to activate and configure the application for your environment. These are described in this topic.
Activation and Initialization Task Flow The following steps are required to fully activate and perform the initial configuration needed to run the IPM application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure and Manage DHCP Options</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/Configure-and-Manage-DHCP-Options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/Configure-and-Manage-DHCP-Options/</guid>
      <description>The default DHCP configuration uses the eth0 interface on which to listen and uses an address pool of 10.255.0.0/24. A default directory is provided for the ONIE installer script and the default ZTP script. Domain name, NTP, and web servers have assigned IP addresses. No reservations are configured. While not required, you may want to s pecify a DHCP address pool more well-suited for your environment or set up reservations for interfaces that require unchanging IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Network Operating System Images</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/Manage-Network-Operating-System-Images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/Manage-Network-Operating-System-Images/</guid>
      <description>You can manage your network operating system (NOS) images with the NetQ Image and Provisioning Management (IPM) application. On initial installation, IPM points to the latest image of the Cumulus Linux operating system and a default ONIE script. You can add additional NOS images, add images, map switches to particular images, as well as view the available images and their mappings.
Command Overview 
IPM enables you to add, delete, and view all of the DHCP configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Zero-Touch Provisioning Scripts</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/Manage-Zero-Touch-Provisioning-Scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-141/Cumulus-NetQ-Image-and-Provisioning-Management-User-Guide/Manage-Zero-Touch-Provisioning-Scripts/</guid>
      <description>You can manage your zero-touch provisioning (ZTP) scripts with the NetQ Image and Provisioning Management (IPM) application. IPM uses a default ZTP script to provision and configure the basic network information needed to add them to your data center network automatically during the first boot of a switch. After that, you can have more than one script and assign each to selected switches.
To take advantage of the ZTP script management feature, you must be running Cumulus Linux 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>