<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cumulus NetQ UI User Guide on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cumulus NetQ UI User Guide on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UI Preface</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/UI-Preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/UI-Preface/</guid>
      <description>A variety of resources are available for you to become familiar with Cumulus NetQ and to take advantage of its monitoring and analytic capabilities. These resources are identified here along with information about how the content is presented.
What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus NetQ 2.2 Cumulus NetQ is now available as a cloud service, making it even easier to scale with your network growth. Just like Cumulus NetQ deployed in your premises, real-time data collection and fabric-wide performance analysis are available through the cloud service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetQ User Interface Overview</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/NetQ-User-Interface-Overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/NetQ-User-Interface-Overview/</guid>
      <description>The NetQ 2.2 graphical user interface (UI)  enables you to access NetQ capabilities through a web browser as opposed to through a terminal window using the Command Line Interface (CLI). Visual representations of the health of the network, inventory, and system events make it easy to both find faults and misconfigurations and to fix them. 
The UI is accessible in both on-site and cloud deployments. It is supported on Google Chrome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetQ Management</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/NetQ-Management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/NetQ-Management/</guid>
      <description>As an administrator, you can manage access to and various application-wide settings for the NetQ UI from a single location.
Individual users have the ability to set preferences specific to their workspaces. This information is covered separately. Refer to User Settings  .
NetQ Management Workbench The NetQ Management workbench is accessed from the main menu and from the header of an open workbench. For the user or users responsible for maintaining the application, this is a good place to start each day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Switches</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-Switches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-Switches/</guid>
      <description>With the NetQ UI, you can monitor individual switches separately from the network. You are able to view the status of services they are running, health of its various components, and connectivity performance. Being able to monitor switch component inventory aids in upgrade, compliance, and other planning tasks. Viewing individual switch health helps isolate performance issues.
For network-wide monitoring, refer to Monitor the Network.
Monitor Switch Performance Viewing detail about a particular switch is essential when troubleshooting performance issues.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>