<tables>
<table name="Open Issues in 5.15.1">
<tr>
<th> Issue ID </th>
<th> Description </th>
<th> Affects </th>
<th> Fixed </th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4776502</td>
<td>When you configure a VRF that does not exist for NTP, the switch attempts to start the NTP service in that VRF and fails instead of indicating that the VRF does not exist. The configuration change does not take effect and NTP continues to work in the current VRF.</td>
<td>5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4776470</td>
<td>In Cumulus Linux 5.15.0, NTP and DNS configuration commands changed from {{nv set service}} to {{nv set system}}. However, after upgrading the switch to Cumulus Linux 5.15.1, the {{nv set service}} command might still appear in the configuration output because a stale {{nv set service}} command remains after the configuration is translated during the upgrade. If you save the configuration with the {{nv config show -o commands}}, then reapply the configuration with {{nv config replace}}, the command fails if the stale {{nv set service}} command is present.To workaround this issue, before applying the configuration with {{nv config replace}}, remove any stale {{nv set service}} commands from the saved configuration file, then reapply the configuration with the {{nv config replace &lt;config-file&gt;}} command.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4771875</td>
<td>When you poll optical module data with {{ethtool -m}}, {{switchd}} might crash due to a firmware timeout that triggers a fatal health-check failure.</td>
<td>5.11.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4771874</td>
<td>When you poll optical module data with {{ethtool -m}}, {{switchd}} might crash due to a firmware timeout that triggers a fatal health-check failure.</td>
<td>5.11.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4771785</td>
<td>NVUE drop counters and ethtool output do not show the packets discarded because the destination MAC address does not match the router MAC address.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4751060</td>
<td>If the switch filesystem is overloaded or memory is exhausted, you see very slow responses from the filesystem and the SDK might fail with a fatal error similar to:
sxd_kernel: Health-Check: new failure (dev=1, severity='Fatal', cause=10 ['SDK thread issue'], irisc=255, desc='Health check: SDK thread [sxSniffer] TID [0x7f81cffff6c0] bit [4] does not respond [5] seconds')</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4748176</td>
<td>Unsupported hardware modules might cause SDK and firmware health event and traffic loss.</td>
<td>5.12.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4740606</td>
<td>When you configure a port with a 802.1x IPv6 profile, then remove 802.1x, the port might block all ingress and egress traffic, including LLDP frames. This behavior is unintended and might impact network visibility and connectivity.To restore normal traffic flow on the affected port, remove the residual traffic-control filters by running the following commands:
tc qdisc del dev &lt;swp port&gt; clsact 2&gt;/dev/null
tc qdisc del dev &lt;swp port&gt; ingress 2&gt;/dev/null
tc qdisc del dev &lt;swp port&gt; egress 2&gt;/dev/null</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4734606</td>
<td>Physical interface based static IPv6 address assignment does not work for DHCPv6 with inbound DHCP requests (discover packets) on an SVI interface. To work around this issue, configure the IPv6 pool for the subnet to assign the IPv6 address from the pool.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4734374</td>
<td>The SNMP AgentX subsystem crashes with a segmentation fault when trying to cancel events from within event callbacks due to multiple Agentx reconnecting one after the other on the device.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4732298</td>
<td>If you enable debugging for graceful-restart, the BGP service crashes during restart.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4732177</td>
<td>On the NVIDIA SN5610 switch, the {{nv show platform transceiver}} command output for 3rd party optics is missing fields such as {{rx-los}} and {{tx-los}}.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4722369</td>
<td>Certain platforms with a SATA disk for NCQ might cause IO errors sending the SSD into read-only mode. You might see ports going down until the switch reboots. There is no observable performance impact due to this issue.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4721298</td>
<td>When node or VM migration occurs between the MLAG pair and the EVPN-MH pair, the MLAG MAC database becomes out of sync with kernel FDB. The migrated MAC addresses remain as local in MLAG MAC database whereas in the kernel, all MAC addresses are updated correctly as remote with the layer 2 next hop ID. To work around this issue, flap the MLAG bond interface to clear the MLAG local database.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4714845</td>
<td>The switch installs suboptimal routes in the routing table and advertises them out.</td>
<td>5.9.2-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4709579</td>
<td>Using package upgrade in Cumulus Linux 5.15 and earlier might show syslog errors similar to {{BTF: failed to validate kernel module -22}}. These syslog errors are largely inconsequential and occur when loading new modules on an older kernel. Kernel modules still function correctly but BTF debug information might be unavailable until the switch reboots after upgrade.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4707967</td>
<td>When you use NVUE to configure a user with a username that is used as a group name in the system, you see the following error message:
User name {} is already in use as OS group name 'and could not be used as username.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4707930</td>
<td>When you configure a high number of 802.1x IPv6 profiles, the {{nv show system dot1x ipv6-profile}} command might return {{no data}}. To work around this issue, run the {{nv show system dot1x ipv6-profile --applied}} command.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4706305</td>
<td>The gNMI interface statistics collector reports the error {{Failed to get SRv6 no sid drop counter: No-SID counter not available in syslog}} even when SRv6 is disabled.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4706274</td>
<td>When {{switchd}} terminates (on system shutdown or service restart), the switch does not clean up PBR ACL rules that reference ECMP groups before the SDK de-initializes. This causes SDK errors in the cleanup sequence.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4704406</td>
<td>TACACS authentication mode is not configured correctly in PAM common authentication and TACACS configuration files, which makes {{login}} the authentication mode regardless of the NVUE configuration.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4702667</td>
<td>When you run the {{nv show vrf default router rib}} command, NVUE returns an ItemDoesNotExist error. This error occurs because the vtysh {{show ip route vrf default brief json}} command does not return any output, which propagates through NVUE. To work around this issue, run the {{nv show vrf default router rib ipv6}} and {{nv show vrf default router rib ipv6 route}} commands instead.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4692400</td>
<td>You see the error {{Failed to get SRv6 no sid drop counter: No-SID counter not available in syslog}} even when SRv6 is disabled.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4691719</td>
<td>NVUE allows you create more than the maximum of 64 destination NAT rules, which results in a configuration error.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4687371</td>
<td>On the spectrum-5, switch when a single traffic class is given 100% dwrr, the default global scheduler profile shows traffic class 5,6,7 as dwrr even though the scheduling mode is strict priority. There is no functional impact with this issue.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4667792</td>
<td>Usernames longer than 32 characters do not authenticate against the switch. Avoid using long usernames.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4662854</td>
<td>If you configure a DSCP match as {{ANY}}, the gNMI subscription does not show DSCP as {{ANY}}. The OpenConfig model supports only integer DSCP values.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4657192</td>
<td>On NVIDIA SN5640 switches, after you configure a port as unsplit, links do not come up while optics are in use. To work around this issue, use copper cables.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4648833</td>
<td>Interfaces using PAM4 DAC cables on switches with Spectrum-4 and later might not come up after a link flap or reboot if auto-negotiation is disabled. Auto-negotiation is required for PAM4 DAC cables on these switches.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4608614</td>
<td>When setting up SSH keys, you have to run {{nv config apply}} twice for the configuration to take effect.</td>
<td>5.11.3-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4582679</td>
<td>If a node has Suppress Route Advertisement enabled and routes are re-learned; for example, when a peer sends the route again due to route policy changes, or you enable or disable graceful shutdown, not all routes are offloaded, which might cause discrepancies in traffic. </td>
<td>5.9.4-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4579237</td>
<td>If interface statistics telemetry is running on the switch, an {{interface_stats_collector}} core file might generate during statistics collection.</td>
<td>5.11.3-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4556982</td>
<td>In the Spanning Tree PVRST environment, when one bridge interface goes down, it causes all the other bridge interfaces to enter a blocking state for approximately ten seconds. Even though the down port is not the root port, all the other bridge ports are flushed and not in service for about ten seconds.</td>
<td>5.13.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4551249</td>
<td>The NVUE service might fail during switch upgrade. To work around this issue, stop the {{sysmonitor}} with the {{sudo systemctl stop sysmonitor}} command, then upgrade the switch with the {{nv action upgrade system packages to latest}} command.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4549896</td>
<td>When you try to set a VXLAN with a bridge, you see the error {{sx_sdk: 22985 [BRIDGE] [ERROR  ]: Port(0x200A000D)) already added to a bridge}}. You can safely ignore this error as it doesn't impact switch functionality. </td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4548514</td>
<td>When a connected route for an SVI interface with VRR configured is installed by FRR, the route might be installed with the next hop interface of the VRR device instead of the SVI. For example, instead of interface {{vlan10}}, the route might install against {{vlan10-v0}}. This prevents next-hop tracking and route installation into hardware.
This issue can occur in the following conditions:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;When initially configuring VRF route leaking, the target VRF might not install a route into hardware when leaking directly connected routes for SVI interfaces with VRR enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In an MLAG and VRR configuration, static routes fail to install when the route is resolved through a connected route and the interface of the connected route undergoes a link state change for any reason, such as link flaps, interface bring-up, {{clagd}} restart, {{switchd}} restart, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
To work around this issue, restart the FRR service using the {{sudo systemctl restart frr.service}} command. </td>
<td>5.9.1-5.9.3, 5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td>5.9.4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4548512</td>
<td>When a connected route for an SVI interface with VRR configured is installed by FRR, the route might be installed with the next hop interface of the VRR device instead of the SVI. For example, instead of interface {{vlan10}}, the route might install against {{vlan10-v0}}. This prevents next-hop tracking and route installation into hardware.
This issue can occur in the following conditions:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;When initially configuring VRF route leaking, the target VRF might not install a route into hardware when leaking directly connected routes for SVI interfaces with VRR enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In an MLAG and VRR configuration, static routes fail to install when the route is resolved through a connected route and the interface of the connected route undergoes a link state change for any reason, such as link flaps, interface bring-up, {{clagd}} restart, {{switchd}} restart, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
To work around this issue, restart the FRR service using the {{sudo systemctl restart frr.service}} command. </td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4547463</td>
<td>When you try to run {{nv action boot-next}} commands during optimized image upgrade, the commands time out. This does not necessarily mean an issue occurred; the system might still be executing the action.To check that the action command completed before going to the next step to reboot the system:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find the Request ID for the REST API invocation corresponding to the {{nv action boot-next}} command by doing a grep for {{ActionKey.*boot-next}} in the /var/log/nvued.log}} file. For example, the value 3 in the {{Ran Job running ActionKey('@boot-next', '/system/image', (), 3, (('partition', 'partition1'),))}} line indicates the Request ID.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the {{curl -u '&lt;username&gt;:&lt;password&gt;'  -X GET https://127.0.0.1:8765/nvue_v1/action/&lt;Request ID&gt; -k}} command from the shell to show the status of the action command. If the value of {{state}} is {{action_success}}, the action command completed successfully. If the value of {{state}} is {{running}}, the system is still processing. If the value of {{state}} is {{action_error}}, the system encountered an error.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4535806</td>
<td>After a factory reset, the switch does not clear the {{/var/tmp}} directory, which the switch uses for temporary files.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4535749</td>
<td>The {{uc-discards}} field in the {{nv show interface &lt;interface&gt; counters qos egress-queue-stats}} command output is actually the number of packets discarded per queue, but it is wrongly interpreted as bytes. To work around this issue, convert the data shown in bytes to packets by multiplying by 1024 if the data is in KB, 1024x1024 if the data is in MB, and 1024x1024x1024 if the data is in GB.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4535699</td>
<td>When you configure the RADIUS authentication order with {{local}} first and {{radius second}}, the RADIUS user is authenticated as a default user name. </td>
<td>5.11.3-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4535696</td>
<td>When you configure the RADIUS authentication order with {{local}} first and {{radius second}}, the RADIUS user is authenticated as a default user name. </td>
<td>5.12.1-5.15.1</td>
<td>5.9.4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4534357</td>
<td>During Cumulus Linux upgrade or downgrade, {{rsyslog}} might crash because the management (eth0) port is unavailable, which triggers a use-after-free fault and  produces a cl-support file as a response.</td>
<td>5.13.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4531960</td>
<td>The GNMI Subscription to xpath {{interfaces/interface[name=swp61s0]/state/counters/out-pkts}} with a high sample interval results in an initial response of zero but in subsequent updates, the value is correct. You do not see this issue when the sample interval is 1 second.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4509255</td>
<td>In PTP two-step, the hardware incorrectly modifies the SYNC message correction field.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4508830</td>
<td>Cumulus Linux allows you to add bond ports of mismatched speeds (such as 10G and 25G) to the same LACP bond without error and the bond reports UP. </td>
<td>5.11.2-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4501632</td>
<td>NVIDIA recommends you wait for approximately 60 seconds after running {{nv config apply}} before power cycling the switch so that NVUE database has time to sync to the filesystem. </td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4495383</td>
<td>NVUE configuration yaml file translation converts unset commands to set commands because the translation logic expects only set commands. </td>
<td>5.13.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4495231</td>
<td>If the hardware clock date is later than 2038-01-19 03:14:07 UTC, the image might fail to install due to a grub-install failure on the EFI filesystem, which is a VFAT filesystem.  As a result, you see the grub prompt immediately after reboot.  To work around this issue, reboot from the grub prompt to go into ONIE.  From ONIE, use the date command to set a date before 2038-01-19, then run the {{hwclock --systohc}} command to add it to the hardware clock.  You can then use {{onie-nos-install}} to install the image.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4475401</td>
<td>External input such as Ctrl+\ might trigger core dumps on the serial console from {{/bin/login}}. This behavior is caused by external sources, such as console servers or automation tools, and does not reflect a fault in the operating system. As a potential result, the serial console might become unresponsive.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4475111</td>
<td>When you try to convert a layer 3 port that is part of ECMP to a bond member,  you might see a failure in the {{switchd}} logs. This issue does not have any functional impact.</td>
<td>5.11.2-5.15.1</td>
<td>5.9.4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4440766</td>
<td>When you try to delete a trusted ca key, Cumulus Linux shows an incorrect error message. To remove a trusted ca key, you must unset the key ID, not the key literal.</td>
<td>5.13.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4423248</td>
<td>If you unset an interface static IP address when the interface IP gateway is configured, the {{nv config apply}} command fails with an {{ifreload.service}} error. To work around this issue, unset both the static IP address and gateway together.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4423244</td>
<td>When you enable, then disable adaptive routing, the BGP neighbors might go down because of an unresolved MAC address. To work around this issue, configure another attribute on the interface.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4423175</td>
<td>When you configure an API port with a TCP port already in use, the {{nginx}} server fails to restart.</td>
<td>5.13.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4413589</td>
<td>A MAC-only EVPN type-2 route is wrongly advertised with the layer 3 VNI label in the BGP NLRI (Network Layer Reachability Information). Although this does not have any functional impact, it is not the desired RFC behavior.</td>
<td>5.13.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4337278</td>
<td>In certain cases, statically configured VXLAN entries age out after a peerlink flap.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4329931</td>
<td>In previous releases, Cumulus Linux incorrectly allowed SyncE and PPS In features to be enabled at the same time. Upgrading systems with both features configured using NVUE to 5.12.0 or higher results in a failure to apply the startup configuration as part of the first boot of the upgraded version. To work around the issue, unset one of the features before you upgrade.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4309876</td>
<td>When you configure an invalid switch port (swp), NVUE adds the invalid configuration instead of rejecting it. The invalid interface in the configuration does not have any functional impact.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4308857</td>
<td>When you use {{tls_crlcheck}} in the {{/etc/nslcd.conf}} file, the optional {{nslcd}} service fails due to a missing library.</td>
<td>5.9.2-5.9.3, 5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td>5.9.4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4294156</td>
<td>After you clear the RoCE counters with the {{nv action clear interface &lt;interface-id&gt; qos roce counters}} command, the {{buffer-max-usage}} counters in the {{nv show interface &lt;interface-id&gt; qos roce counters}} command output do not show updated (cleared) values.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4277042</td>
<td>On the NVIDIA SN5600 switch, you see low power alarms immediately after a reboot. The alarms disappear after showing up initially. Certain modules typically show low power alarms on initialization. No action is needed.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4249096</td>
<td>Binary upgrade from Cumulus Linux 4.3.1 to 5.12.0 and later is not supported. To work around this issue, perform a binary upgrade from Cumulus Linux 4.3.1 to 5.9.0, then perform a binary upgrade from Cumulus Linux 5.9.0 to 5.12.0 or later.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4236419</td>
<td>On the Spectrum-3 switch, the PTP offset for 25GbE fluctuates within a range of plus or minus 50 nanoseconds beyond the expected values.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4214678</td>
<td>Changes to open telemetry configuration or export states restarts the telemetry service and resets all health metrics.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4177067</td>
<td>When performing a package upgrade, {{nslcd}} installation might open an interactive dialog to configure {{nslcd.conf }}.To avoid this interactive dialog, set the {{DEBIAN_FRONTEND}} environment variable to {{noninteractive}}. For example:
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo apt-get update
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo DEBIAN_FRONTEND=noninteractive apt-get -y -o "Dpkg::Options::=--force-confdef" -o "Dpkg::Options::=--force-confold" upgrade</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4154839</td>
<td>When you run certain SDK commands (such as {{sudo sx_api_port_counter_dump_all.py}} or {{sx_api_fdb_dump}}) first as the cumulus user, then with {{sudo}}, you see the following error:
PermissionError: Errno 13] Permission denied: '/tmp/python_err_log.txt'
To resolve this issue, run the {{rm -rf /tmp/python_err_log.txt}} command.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4142857</td>
<td>The switch drops PTP packets received with extra ethernet padding and you see syslog {{[ptp4l.ERR] messages.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4139511</td>
<td>When you generate the cl-support file on the Spectrum-4 switch, the following messages appear on the serial console. You can safely ignore this issue.[ 1903.595131] mlxsw_minimal 2-0048: Could not acquire lock
[ 1903.601089] mlxsw_minimal 2-0048: Reg cmd access failed (reg_id=900a(mtmp),type=query)
[ 1903.609961] hwmon hwmon28: Failed to query module temperature thresholds
[ 1903.846724] mlxsw_minimal 2-0048: Could not acquire lock
[ 1903.852689] mlxsw_minimal 2-0048: Reg cmd access failed (reg_id=900a(mtmp),type=query)
[ 1903.861573] hwmon hwmon28: Failed to query module temperature</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4134447</td>
<td>The journal logs might include the error message {{ERR kernel: [    7.453789] usb usb2-port2: connect-debounce failed}}. You can safely ignore this log message.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4129757</td>
<td>If you include a comma in the BGP community list, extended community list, or large community list regex expression of a routing policy, you see error messages and FRR reload fails. Make sure the regex expression does not contain a comma. For example, instead of {{^65550:([0-9]{1,2}|[1-9][1-9]):.*$}}, specify {{^65550:([0-9]|[0-9][0-9]):.*$}} and instead of {{^65550:([0-4]{1,2}|[7-9][8-9]):.*$}}, specify {{^65550:([0-4]|[0-4][0-4]|[7-9][8-9]):.*$}}.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4124376</td>
<td>The SN3700C-S, SN5400, and SN5600 secure boot switch running Cumulus Linux 5.11.0 or later boots with shim 15.8 that adds entries to the SBAT revocations to prevent the switch from booting shim 15.7 or earlier (included in Cumulus Linux 5.10 and earlier).To downgrade a secure boot switch from Cumulus Linux 5.11.0 or later, or to recover a downgraded switch that does not boot, follow the steps in &lt;a href="https://docs.nvidia.com/networking-ethernet-software/cumulus-linux/Installation-Management/Upgrading-Cumulus-Linux/#downgrade-a-secure-boot-switch"&gt;Downgrade a Secure Boot Switch&lt;/a&gt;.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4118970</td>
<td>When running PTP, the performance for 100Gx2 and 400Gx8 can have a high offset in up to 1.5% of the sampling. </td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4105127</td>
<td>Any sFlow configuration changes that require an {{hsflowd}} restart are operational only after an initial delay of 60 seconds.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4100629</td>
<td>NVUE show command outputs show LLDP neighbor changes only after the LLDP update frequency multiplied by the hold time.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4082210</td>
<td>When you change the CPU resource limit with the {{nv set service control rsyslog resource-limit cpu &lt;value&gt;}} command, the {{rsyslog}} agent does not start. To work around this issue, increase the CPU resource limit, then restart the service manually.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4077921</td>
<td>You cannot use package upgrade to upgrade from Cumulus Linux 5.9.2 to Cumulus Linux 5.10.1 or later. You must install the Cumulus Linux image instead.</td>
<td>5.10.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4049213</td>
<td>When there are routes that point to a single next hop, an ECMP entry is created in the SDK. After the single next hop from the route is removed, the ECMP entry might stay in the SDK until the time the next hop is present in the kernel.</td>
<td>5.9.2-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4047798</td>
<td>Packet distribution based on ECMP hash is not working for VXLAN on top of rack switches where it is encapped. To work around this issue, enable lag hashing with gtp-teid to distribute the VXLAN encapped packets across egress interfaces.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4030380</td>
<td>When you roll back interface configuration to the default setting with the {{nv unset interface}} command, NVUE removes the complete entry for the interface from the {{/etc/network/interface}} file, and puts the interface in admin down. As a result, you cannot configure FEC on the interface at the lower layers.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4005422</td>
<td>When you upgrade Cumulus Linux 5.9.1 to Cumulus Linux 5.10 or later with package upgrade, the NTP service stops. To restart the NTP service, enable, then restart the service in the VRF in which it was running with the {{systemctl enable ntpsec@&lt;vrf&gt;}} and {{systemctl restart ntpsec@&lt;vrf&gt;}} commands.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3985682</td>
<td>On Spectrum-4 switches, multicast flows containing packets smaller than 512 bytes might not reach full line rate. Cumulus Linux supports 512 byte and larger multicast packets.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3966312</td>
<td>When connecting the SN5xxx switch to third party test equipment (such as IXIA) using copper cables at 100GbE, 200GbE, 400GbE, or 800GbE, links do not come up.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3948068</td>
<td>On the SN3700 and SN3700c switch, the {{nv show platform environment voltage}} command output shows a failed state for the {{PSU-n-12V-RAIL-OUT}} sensors.  This is a known hardware limitation that cannot be corrected by the PSU vendor.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3915878</td>
<td>If you configure remote syslog export through a non-default VRF, you might see repeated error logs from the {{rsyslog}} process while the switch is booting:
rsyslogd: create UDP socket bound to device failed: No such device [v8.2302.0]
rsyslogd: No UDP socket could successfully be initialized, some functionality may be disabled.  [v8.2302.0]
The logs occur because the {{rsyslog}} service starts before the networking service creates the configured VRF for syslog export. There is no functional impact with this issue.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3879717</td>
<td>Running {{snmpwalk}} on the switch with the management IP address does not work. To work around this issue, use the localhost option ({{snmpwalk -v 2c -c public28 localhost 1.3.6.1.2.1.14}}) or create a control plane ACL whitelist rule.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3878394</td>
<td>When ZTP runs a script that contains {{wget}}, ZTP fails and you see a message similar to the following:
ZTP: ZTP DHCP: Unexpected error: 'ascii' codec can't decode byte 0xe2 in position 181: ordinal not in range(128)
ZTP: Script returned failure 
To work around this issue, use the {{-q}} option with {{wget}}.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3877516</td>
<td>When you connect two NVIDIA switches and configure 400G speed in force mode, links don't come up.To work around this issue, make sure auto-negotiation is always on when connecting NVIDIA to NVIDIA in PAM4.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3875373</td>
<td>When you run the {{nv config apply empty}} command, NVUE removes the {{cumulus user}}. If you are logged in as the {{cumulus}} user when you run the {{nv config apply empty}} command, the command fails.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3861745</td>
<td>On UEFI hardware (where the {{/sys/firmware/efi}} directory exists), using the update-grub program might generate a {{/boot/grub/grub.cfg}} that is incorrect for booting ONIE if the ONIE option is selected on the console while booting. To work around this issue, run {{mount LABEL="EFI System" /boot/efi}} before using update-grub.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3855796</td>
<td>When configuring a Unicast Master Table for clients, the server addresses must be reachable and the route to the destination must exist. The unicast table can have one directly-connected port for a client. This restriction is only for directly connected ports and doesn't apply to Unicast Servers on other devices or switches.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3847439</td>
<td>In rare cases on the Spectrum 1 switch, where a dual connected host transmits all traffic flows to only one switch in a connected MLAG pair, and the host changes behavior to hash all flows to the other MLAG switch, there might be traffic loss if the MAC FDB entry on the original switch ages out.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3819945</td>
<td>When you connect an NVIDIA SN4410, SN4700, or SN5600 switch to any Spectrum 1, Spectrum-2, or Spectrum-3 peer switch (with four lanes) using a 4x breakout configuration and the default lanes per port setting, links do not come up. To work around this issue, provide the lanes per port configuration shown below:
cumulus@switch:~$ nv set interface &lt;interface&gt; link breakout 4x lanes-per-port 1</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3818545</td>
<td>The terminal monitoring software SecureCRT has a known issue when running on both Windows and Mac systems where it gets stuck when monitoring the serial port of the switch as Cumulus Linux boots up.  When this occurs, the serial port stops as shown below and SecureCRT is unable to receive any more serial data from the switch (it is able to transmit).

Mounting dev-hugepages.mount - Huge Pages File System...
Mounting dev-mqueue.mount
</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3774274</td>
<td>When you manually configure the {{/etc/cumulus/datapath/qos/qos_features.conf}} file without applying the QoS configuration with NVUE, running the {{nv config apply empty}} command later does not clean up the QoS configuration. If the QoS configuration includes breakout ports, the {{nv config apply empty}} command fails due to a {{switchd}} reload trigger failure. To work around this issue, clean up the configuration manually in the {{/etc/cumulus/datapath/qos/qos_features.conf}}, then run the {{nv config apply empty}} command.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3773177</td>
<td>When you try to upgrade a switch from Cumulus Linux before 5.6.0 with package upgrade, you might see errors for expired GPG keys that prevent you from upgrading. To work around this issue, install the new keys with the following commands, then upgrade the switch.

cumulus@switch:~$ wget https://download.nvidia.com/cumulus/apt.cumulusnetworks.com/repo/pool/cumulus/c/cumulus-archive-keyring/cumulus-archive-keyring_4-cl5.6.0u5_all.deb
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo apt install ./cumulus-archive-keyring_4-cl5.6.0u5_all.deb
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo apt update
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo apt upgrade
</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3771168</td>
<td>When you perform an ISSU upgrade on a Spectrum 1 switch, the {{switchd}} service might crash.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3677533</td>
<td>Due to resource constraints on the Spectrum 1 switch, {{staticd}} performance drops and  takes longer to read static routes compared to the time BGP takes to complete a graceful restart and advertise routes and EOR to its helpers. As a result, static routes are advertised after the EOR is sent to graceful restart helpers, which delete the stale static routes and relearn them after receiving the EOR from the restarting node. Temporary traffic loss might occur.</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3655681</td>
<td>When you disable, then enable STP auto-edge on a port, the port might not transition to the operational edge even though the port does not receive bpdus. To work around this issue, configure the port as an admin-edge port.</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3637444</td>
<td>Applying an inbound control plane ACL on the eth0 management interface does not take effect. To work around this issue, apply the ACL on the {{mgmt}} interface; for example, {{nv set interface mgmt acl &lt;acl-id&gt; inbound control-plane}}.</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3591918</td>
<td>The {{nv action disconnect system aaa user}} command does not clear all open sessions. To work around this issue, run the command as many times as the number of sessions.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3587393</td>
<td>If you use the NVIDIA SN5600 (Spectrum-4) switch with Ixia test equipment, you might experience delayed link up due to intermittent link flaps. 
To work around this issue when using copper cables:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use Ixia IxOS version 9.37 with HF002156, or version 9.39 or later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the DAC cable on ports 10 through 50.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use NVIDIA cables with the recommended firmware revision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure AN on the Cumulus Linux switch and AN/LT on Ixia.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
To work around this issue when using fiber cables:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Configure 800g/Force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the recommended NVIDIA optical adapters.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3556762</td>
<td>On rare occasions, SPT switchover might not happen cleanly in PIM resulting in some dropped packets. If you use PIM-SM to replicate EVPN BUM traffic, you might see a brief drop of multicast traffic before recovering due to normal PIM-SM traffic timeout.</td>
<td>5.5.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3540510</td>
<td>400Gx8 ports only support traffic line rate with packets that are larger than 172 bytes.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3538321</td>
<td>In rare cases, an STP topology change on PTP over a VLAN can result in the switch losing the slave state and one of the ports might remain in an uncalibrated state. To work around this issue, toggle the port that is in the uncalibrated state up and down so that one of the ports is selected as the slave.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3497622</td>
<td>When you remove PSUs, then plug them back in, you might   experience traffic loss and some ports might be in a down state.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3472163</td>
<td>On a switch with the Spectrum-4 ASIC, packets that are smaller than 256 bytes are not included in multicast flows.  Multicast flows support packets that are 256 bytes or larger.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3444490</td>
<td>Migration from ONYX to Cumulus Linux is supported and tested with ONYX version 3.10.4302 GA only.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3442569</td>
<td>When trying to access the NVUE API, user accounts authenticated with a newly-configured external service, such as TACACS, RADIUS, or LDAP, receive a 401 forbidden error. To work around this issue, after enabling a new authentication service, make sure to restart both {{nginx.service}} and {{nvued.service}} to begin authenticating users against the new authentication service.</td>
<td>5.5.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3430430</td>
<td>When you configure PTP on 50G ports, the offset correction might be higher, which can affect the time synchronization of the node. To work around this issue, configure PTP on 100G ports, or on 10G or 1G ports with PTP shaper enabled.</td>
<td>5.5.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3424967</td>
<td>{{sudo}} for TACACS+ users with privilege level 15 does not work when reaching the TACACS+ server through the {{default}} VRF. To work around this issue, specify the interface name that the {{default}} VRF uses in the {{vrf=}} setting of the {{/etc/tacplus_servers}} file or run the NVUE {{nv set system aaa tacacs vrf}} command. If you don't run either command, a TACACS+ user with privilege level 15 can run {{vrf task exec default sudo ...}} to execute the {{sudo}} command.</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3420056</td>
<td>
The ADVA 5401 SFP module with hardware revision 5.01 does not come up at layer 1 when you use 10G QSA adaptors. To work around this issue, use 25G QSA adaptors.</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3414866</td>
<td>Each VLAN is represented as a bitmap on the underlying port and when you add multiple VLANs together, Cumulus Linux iterates over the existing ones and updates the diff. However, in few corner cases, the same bitmap might be repeated again causing the following error.
sx_sdk: 22985 [BRIDGE] [ERROR  ]: Port(0x200A000D)) already added to a bridge
You can ignore this error; it has no impact on switch functionality.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3362113</td>
<td>If you restore an NVUE {{startup.yaml}} file or run the {{nv config patch}} command after an upgrade that includes breakout ports with QoS configuration, the NVUE configuration fails to apply. Subsequent attempts to run {{nv config apply}} fail with a message similar to {{Invalid config [rev_id: 11] qos config is not supported on the following invalid interface: swp1s0. Supported on swp and bond interface types}}. To work around this issue, run {{nv unset}} on the configured QoS settings, then apply the breakout port configuration before you configure QoS. Alternatively, you can remove the QoS configuration from the {{yaml}} file and patch it separately after applying the breakout configuration.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3347538</td>
<td>When connecting NVIDIA-to-NVIDIA in PAM4, you must enable auto-negotiation.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3341214</td>
<td>If you use the NVUE REST API to configure a local user with a hashed password, the user cannot log in and the {{/etc/nvue.d/startup.yaml}} file shows the password as plain text.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3329518</td>
<td>When using TACACS+, if the {{/etc/nsswitch.conf}} file specifies {{passwd: files tacplus}} (files is listed before tacplus), a user that is present in both the local {{/etc/passwd}} file and the TACACS+ server cannot log into the switch. NVIDIA recommends that when using TACACS+, you list {{tacplus}} before {{files}} in {{/etc/nsswitch.conf}}.  When using NVUE, ensure that {{tacacs}} has priority over {{local}}.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3327477</td>
<td>If you use {{su}} to change to a user specified through TACACS+, the user becomes the local tacacs0 thru tacacs15 user instead of the named user to run {{sudo}} commands. As a result, the named user password might not match the local tacacs0 thru tacacs15 user password.</td>
<td>3.7.0-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3326659</td>
<td>If you have a large number of MAC addresses, they do not age out at the MAC ageing timeout value configured on the switch. It might take up to 30 seconds more for the MAC addresses to age out and be deleted from the hardware. To work around this issue, wait for the ageing timeout value plus 30 seconds.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3253218</td>
<td>Auto-negotiation isn't supported on Spectrum-2 and Spectrum-3 switches using the 1G SFP-T module; FORCE 1G is configured instead. </td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3241567</td>
<td>When you apply switch configuration for the first time on a freshly booted switch and you run the {{nv config apply}} command after setting the hostname with {{nv set system hostname}}, you might see the error message {{Failed to start Hostname Service}}. To work around this issue, run the {{nv config apply}} command a second time.</td>
<td>5.3.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3226506</td>
<td>The {{l1-show eth0}} command does not show port information and is not supported in this release. </td>
<td>5.3.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3225117</td>
<td>Occasionally, packet loss might occur on 25G ports when the link is raised without FEC.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3172504</td>
<td>When you connect the NVIDIA SN4600C switch to a Spectrum 1 or Spectrum-3 switch with a 40GbE passive copper cable (Part Number: MC2210126-005) on edge ports 1-4 and 61-64, there is an Effective BER of 1E-12 in PHY.</td>
<td>5.2.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3147782</td>
<td>You cannot use NVUE to configure an SNMP view to include a subtree beginning with a period. For example:

cumulus@switch:~$ nv set service snmp-server viewname cumulusOnly included .1.3.6.1.4.1.40310
Error: GET /nvue_v1/service/snmp-server/viewname/cumulusOnly/included?pointers=%5B%22%2Fparameters%22%2C+%22%2Fpatch%2FrequestBody%2Fcontent%2Fapplication~1json%2Fschema%22%2C+%22%2Fpatch%2Fparameters%22%2C+%22%2Fpatch%2Fresponses%2F200%2Flinks%22%5D responded with 404 NOT FOUND

To work around this issue, reference the OID without the preceding period ( {{.}} ) in the command.</td>
<td>5.3.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3145869</td>
<td>On a Spectrum-3 switch, the PTP offset in 10GbE changes between plus or minus 27. The average offset is around 7.</td>
<td>5.2.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3135952</td>
<td>PAM4 split cables (such as 2x100G, 4x100G, and 4x50G) do not work with a forced speed setting (when auto-negotiation is off) as the default speed enabled is for NRZ mode (such as 100G_4X). To work around this issue,  set the appropriate lanes for forced speed (with auto-negotation off) with the {{ethtool -s swpX speed &lt;port_speed&gt; autoneg off lanes &lt;no_of_lanes&gt;}} command. For example: 

cumulus@switch:~$ sudo ethtool -s swp1 speed 100000 autoneg off lanes 2
</td>
<td>5.2.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3115242</td>
<td>When you configure two VNIs in the same VLAN, ifupdown2  shows a {{vlan added to two or more VXLANS}} warning, which is only issued after the VNI is already added to the bridge. This leaves the new VNI in the PVID even if there is already an existing VNI configured in that PVID.</td>
<td>5.1.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3103821</td>
<td>On the NVIDIA SN4700 switch, inserting and removing the PSU might cause loss of frames.</td>
<td>5.2.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3084476</td>
<td> After you disable traffic shaping in the {{/etc/cumulus/datapath/qos/qos_features.conf}} file, the default QOS traffic shaping configuration does not restore. To work around this issue, restart {{switchd}}.</td>
<td>4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td>4.4.4-4.4.5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3084027</td>
<td>Under a high load, you might see ingress drop counters increase. The drops are classified as {{HwIfInDiscards}} in ethtool and shown as {{ingress_general}} in hardware.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3071652</td>
<td>On rare occasions, after you reboot or restart {{switchd}} on a Spectrum 1 switch, any 25G connections with Direct Attach Copper (DAC) cables that connect from the switch to a non-NVIDIA device might flap continuously. To work around this issue, bring the affected link administratively down for a few seconds on the non-NVIDIA device, then bring the link back up.</td>
<td>4.4.4-4.4.5, 5.1.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3061656</td>
<td>When the CPU load is high during a warm boot, bonds with a slow LACP rate fail to forward layer 2 traffic for up to 60 seconds (depending on the duration of the CPU load) and static bonds fail to forward layer 2 traffic for up to 5 seconds.</td>
<td>5.1.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2972540</td>
<td>With RADIUS enabled for user shell authentication, there might be a delay in local user authentication for non cumulus user accounts.</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2951110</td>
<td>The {{net show time ntp servers}} command does not show any output with the management VRF.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.1.1-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2904450</td>
<td>When you run the {{ethtool -m}} or the {{l1-show}} command, the 400G interface optical values do not show. 

</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2885305</td>
<td>Certain Murata PSU attributes show intermittently in the sensors command output. To work around this issue, upgrade to the latest PSU firmware on Murata.</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2867042</td>
<td>When connecting the NVIDIA SN4600 switch to another NVIDIA Spectrum switch, you must use auto-negotiation mode (not force mode); otherwise the switch might use the wrong Tx configuration.</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2823307</td>
<td>Cumuls Linux does not support a bond with more than 64 ports.  Any configuration with more than 64 ports in a bond changes all ports to down when you apply the configuration. </td>
<td>5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2736108</td>
<td>When you change the VRRP advertisement interval on the master, the {{master advertisement interval}} field in the {{show vrrp}} command output does not show the updated value.</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2684925</td>
<td>The NVUE {{nv show vrf default router bgp peer}} command produces a 404 not found error.</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2671652</td>
<td>In VXLAN routing environments, you might experience sub-optimal route convergence delays (longer than five seconds) when a prefix transitions to a new ECMP next-hop group. This condition might occur when a VTEP loses ECMP routes through all uplink peerings, then installs the routes through a different path, such as an MLAG peerlink.</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.5.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</table>
<table name="Fixed Issues in 5.15.1">
<tr>
<th> Issue ID </th>
<th> Description </th>
<th> Affects </th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4769275</td>
<td>During power cycles and GPIO events, link initialization might fail due to a race condition during switch configuration. To work around this issue, set the service port to {{admin UP}}.</td>
<td>5.15.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4769258</td>
<td>After upgrading the switch with {{onie-install -t}}, NTP configuration is missing and does not work. This issue does not occur with package or optimized image upgrade.</td>
<td>5.15.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4769256</td>
<td>Low fan speed alarm events occur while the corresponding fan modules are amber physically. </td>
<td>5.15.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4769255</td>
<td>When using the CPU port as the SPAN destination, the switch might become unresponsive and, or reboot. To work around this issue, use SPAN to a local port instead of the CPU port.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4738956</td>
<td>When a Spectrum-4 or Spectrum-5 switch (local device) is connected to a ConnectX-7 or ConnectX-8 NIC, or a Spectrum-4 or Spectrum-5 (peer device) that performs a soft reset, adaptive routing and Spectrum-X features fail to start on the interface. To work around this issue, flap the interface on the Spectrum-4 or Spectrum-5 switch.</td>
<td>5.15.0</td>
</tr>
</table>
<table name="Open Issues in 5.15.0">
<tr>
<th> Issue ID </th>
<th> Description </th>
<th> Affects </th>
<th> Fixed </th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4875599</td>
<td>When you configure authentication for a BGP dynamic neighbor, removing the configuration does not bring back the sessions.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4873853</td>
<td>TACACS authentication is not working with flat files. The Cumulus Linux user guide is missing the {{sudo pam-auth-update --enable tacplus}} command.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4859201</td>
<td>When the VNI changes on a VRF, from the old VNI to the new VNI, the VNI in the SVD VNI hash table or in the single‑VNI (SVD) in the VNI info is deleted. Therefore, when there are further updates to the old VNI, the lookup fails and causes the zebra core to crash. </td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4850551</td>
<td>The switch installs suboptimal routes in the routing table and advertises them out.</td>
<td>5.9.2-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4850188</td>
<td>Signal quality degradation is observed during SR4-100G to 4×25G breakout using an adapter.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4838527</td>
<td>On a high port scale system, streaming telemetry for interface and buffer statistics (GNMI or OTEL) together with the PFC watchdog feature, causes samples of telemetry data to fail to export from the system periodically and kernel memory use might increase.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4835058</td>
<td>When you add or remove bond members, the sflow state and rate are incorrect. </td>
<td>5.13.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4830305</td>
<td>After an optimized image upgrade, certain disabled {{systemd}} services that are replaced with VRF-based services are reenabled. This results in multiple instances of the applications running, where they either fail to start or run with incorrect configuration. This issue occurs with, but is not limited to SSH, NTP and streaming telemetry services running with a custom VRF configuration. To work around this issue, after the upgrade, stop and disable the incorrect services, then restart the correct ones as required.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4826181</td>
<td>When you apply EVPN layer 3 VNI and BGP AS configurations together for a VRF, an internal AS number inconsistency might occur between the FRR running configuration and the {{/etc/frr/frr.conf}} file. When you try to apply any configuration using f{{rr-reload}}, NVUE detects this pre-existing inconsistency and triggers an unnecessary FRR restart, causing BGP session flaps. To work around this issue, apply BGP configuration before EVPN layer 3 VNI configuration in separate commits. </td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4823999</td>
<td>When making interface changes with NVUE, you might see the following message after you run the {{nv config apply}} command:
 update-ports returned with error (code 254): switchd ports.conf node status not ready switchd validate_node is absent/not ready 
ports configuration(ports.conf/ports_width.conf) is invalid</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4813804</td>
<td>The {{nv config show}} command output shows each egress buffer configuration separately for each traffic class instead of in a single line configuration.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4813159</td>
<td>The {{nv config show}} command output shows each egress buffer, ingress buffer, and latency configuration separately for each traffic class or port group instead of in single line configuration.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4807528</td>
<td>On certain platforms, the {{nv show platform transceiver &lt;port&gt;}} command shows module flags (for example, CMIS‑style fault/LOS flags) as False for legacy, non‑CMIS optics (such as older QSFP+, QSFP28, and QSFP56 modules) even when the module does not implement these flags. This issue has no functional impact.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4804084</td>
<td>On switches at scale with OTEL enabled, an {{interface_stats_collector}} crash might occur with the following logs:
{{interface_stats_collector[3429270]: ERROR buffer_stats_collector.go:1875 SDK bulk counter read failed
interface_stats_collector[3429270]: fatal error: concurrent map iteration and map write
interface_stats_collector[3429270]: goroutine 5610 gp=0xc007814c40 m=16 mp=0xc000552808 [running]:}}</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4799272</td>
<td>When {{nvued.log}} triggers log rotation, it also forces rotation of all three logs ({{nvued}}, {{nv-cli}}, and {{nv-api}}). As a result, the {{nv-cli}} logs are rotated unnecessarily, which might eventually lead to missing {{nv-cli.log}} entries due to excessive rotations.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4797691</td>
<td>The message that the switch displays when you generate a cl-support file or as a post login banner contains an invalid Cumulus Support email address, which is no longer the formal channel for reporting support issues.</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4789562</td>
<td>A switch running Nvidia Cumulus Linux may improperly forward routed packets out of an access port or on the native vlan of a trunk with an 802.1Q tag imposed on the packet.</td>
<td>5.12.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4789339</td>
<td>The {{interface_stats}} process might crash when a transceiver has non-ASCII data in EEPROM fields, such as vendor name or part number. </td>
<td>5.13.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4789097</td>
<td>The switch deletes a static blackhole route even when the blackhole type specified in the delete command does not match the configured type.</td>
<td>5.9.4-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4783824</td>
<td>RoCE ingress reserved pools do not display correct values for ports that are not operationally UP. Switch ports that were never operational or not operational after setting RoCE mode do not have RoCE reserved pool buffers allocated but the {{nv show interface &lt;interface&gt; qos roce status}} command displays an invalid buffer size.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4781499</td>
<td>The 802.1X RADIUS shared secret is limited to 32 characters instead of 256 characters.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4781498</td>
<td>When you use a text-based patch file with {{nv config patch cmd.txt}} or {{nv config replace cmd.txt}}, if the {{cmd.txt}} file contains any of the following CLI commands, the patch operation fails and triggers an exception in NVUE:
nv set system aaa auth order radius &lt;array&gt;
nv set system ssh-server ciphers &lt;array&gt;
nv set system ssh-server macs &lt;array&gt;
nv set system ssh-server kex-algorithms &lt;array&gt;
nv set system ssh-server pubkey-accepted-algorithms &lt;array&gt;
nv set system ssh-server host-key-algorithms &lt;array&gt; 
To work around this issue, use a YAML file instead of a text-based patch file or run the {{nv set}} commands manually.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4776471</td>
<td>In Cumulus Linux 5.15.0, NTP and DNS configuration commands changed from {{nv set service}} to {{nv set system}}. However, after upgrading the switch to Cumulus Linux 5.15.1, the {{nv set service}} command might still appear in the configuration output because a stale {{nv set service}} command remains after the configuration is translated during the upgrade. If you save the configuration with the {{nv config show -o commands}}, then reapply the configuration with {{nv config replace}}, the command fails if the stale {{nv set service}} command is present.To workaround this issue, before applying the configuration with {{nv config replace}}, remove any stale {{nv set service}} commands from the saved configuration file, then reapply the configuration with the {{nv config replace &lt;config-file&gt;}} command.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4776470</td>
<td>In Cumulus Linux 5.15.0, NTP and DNS configuration commands changed from {{nv set service}} to {{nv set system}}. However, after upgrading the switch to Cumulus Linux 5.15.1, the {{nv set service}} command might still appear in the configuration output because a stale {{nv set service}} command remains after the configuration is translated during the upgrade. If you save the configuration with the {{nv config show -o commands}}, then reapply the configuration with {{nv config replace}}, the command fails if the stale {{nv set service}} command is present.To workaround this issue, before applying the configuration with {{nv config replace}}, remove any stale {{nv set service}} commands from the saved configuration file, then reapply the configuration with the {{nv config replace &lt;config-file&gt;}} command.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4776444</td>
<td>In rare cases when telemetry is configured on a switch with high interface scale, the following log message might be generated and lead to a kernel crash event:

interface_stats_collector[27979]: ERROR intf_stats_collector.go:485 WaitBulkCounterDone error: unable to receive trap info after 15 iterations
</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4776390</td>
<td>gNMI subscription changes for interface counters, buffer, packet trim, latency or any other statistics produced by the {{prometheus-sdk-stats}} service leads to a change in the service configuration file causing the load interval configuration to be removed. This results in a rate calculation done with an interval of 60s instead of the interval configured in NVUE.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4771875</td>
<td>When you poll optical module data with {{ethtool -m}}, {{switchd}} might crash due to a firmware timeout that triggers a fatal health-check failure.</td>
<td>5.11.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4771865</td>
<td>When you change the RADIUS privilege level, all affected existing RADIUS users are not updated in the next session to the relevant privilege level.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4771785</td>
<td>NVUE drop counters and ethtool output do not show the packets discarded because the destination MAC address does not match the router MAC address.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4771521</td>
<td>Layer 3 multicast traffic does not forward when OMF (Optimized Multicast Flooding) and PIM is enabled. To work around this issue, flap the router port.</td>
<td>5.9.2-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4769275</td>
<td>During power cycles and GPIO events, link initialization might fail due to a race condition during switch configuration. To work around this issue, set the service port to {{admin UP}}.</td>
<td>5.15.0</td>
<td>5.15.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4752986</td>
<td>Warm reboot results in approximately 14 second traffic loss.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4751060</td>
<td>If the switch filesystem is overloaded or memory is exhausted, you see very slow responses from the filesystem and the SDK might fail with a fatal error similar to:
sxd_kernel: Health-Check: new failure (dev=1, severity='Fatal', cause=10 ['SDK thread issue'], irisc=255, desc='Health check: SDK thread [sxSniffer] TID [0x7f81cffff6c0] bit [4] does not respond [5] seconds')</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4748963</td>
<td>In an MLAG configuration with PVRST spanning tree mode configured on both switches, when the primary switch comes back up after a reboot, PVRST mode briefly changes to RSTP, then back to PVRST.</td>
<td>5.13.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4748176</td>
<td>Unsupported hardware modules might cause SDK and firmware health event and traffic loss.</td>
<td>5.12.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4743814</td>
<td>The switch clears the QoS buffer max usage values in the {{nv show interface &lt;interface&gt; qos buffer egress-traffic-class}} command output when a gNMI client subscribes to any QoS buffer metrics.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4740671</td>
<td>Low fan speed alarm events occur while the corresponding fan modules are amber physically. </td>
<td>5.15.0</td>
<td>5.15.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4740606</td>
<td>When you configure a port with a 802.1x IPv6 profile, then remove 802.1x, the port might block all ingress and egress traffic, including LLDP frames. This behavior is unintended and might impact network visibility and connectivity.To restore normal traffic flow on the affected port, remove the residual traffic-control filters by running the following commands:
tc qdisc del dev &lt;swp port&gt; clsact 2&gt;/dev/null
tc qdisc del dev &lt;swp port&gt; ingress 2&gt;/dev/null
tc qdisc del dev &lt;swp port&gt; egress 2&gt;/dev/null</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4734606</td>
<td>Physical interface based static IPv6 address assignment does not work for DHCPv6 with inbound DHCP requests (discover packets) on an SVI interface. To work around this issue, configure the IPv6 pool for the subnet to assign the IPv6 address from the pool.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4734395</td>
<td>{{mlxlink}} output sometimes displays additional special characters while still reporting valid data.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4734374</td>
<td>The SNMP AgentX subsystem crashes with a segmentation fault when trying to cancel events from within event callbacks due to multiple Agentx reconnecting one after the other on the device.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4732298</td>
<td>If you enable debugging for graceful-restart, the BGP service crashes during restart.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4732177</td>
<td>On the NVIDIA SN5610 switch, the {{nv show platform transceiver}} command output for 3rd party optics is missing fields such as {{rx-los}} and {{tx-los}}.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4729839</td>
<td>In an MLAG configuration, when you reboot the primary MLAG switch with PVRST spanning tree mode configured on both MLAG switches, PVRST mode briefly changes to RSTP, then back to PVRST when the primary switch comes back up.</td>
<td>5.11.3-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4726412</td>
<td>When a Spectrum-4 or Spectrum-5 switch interface is connected to a ConnectX-7 NIC that performs a soft reset, adaptive routing and Spectrum-X features fail to start on the interface. To work around this issue, flap the interface.</td>
<td>5.15.0</td>
<td>5.15.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4722680</td>
<td>If you install RADIUS client packages when rolling back a two partition upgrade, the {{/var/lib/nvue}}, {{/var/lib/ntpsec}}, and {{/var/lib/snmp}} directories might have incorrect ownership after rollback and the {{nvued}} service might fail to start up. To work around this issue, run the following commands:
sudo chown -R nvue /var/lib/nvue
sudo chown -R ntpsec /var/lib/ntpsec
sudo chown -R Debian-snmp /var/lib/snmp
sudo reboot</td>
<td>5.11.4-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4722539</td>
<td>Optimized image upgrade with warm boot mode is supported in Cumulus Linux 5.13 and later. When you try to run the {{nv action boot-next}} command during optimized image upgrade in Cumulus Linux 5.12 and earlier to any target release while the system is in warm boot mode, the {{boot-next}} operation fails with the following error:
cumulus@switch:~$ nv action boot-next system image other
Error: Action failed with the following issue:&gt;br&gt;
  Failed to set boot-next due to Unknown error
To work around this issue, verify system boot mode with the {{nv show system reboot}} command before you perform optimized image upgrade and switch to cold boot mode if necessary with the {{nv set system reboot mode cold}} command. You can then proceed with the optimized image upgrade {{boot-next}} operation.</td>
<td>5.11.4-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4722449</td>
<td>NVUE uses a git repository to store configurations, which over time, can grow very large, sometimes filling up all available disk space on the system. When this happens, NVUE commands become very slow or fail entirely due to lack of disk space. In severe cases, NVUE stops working completely. To work around this issue, restart the nvued service to trigger a deep cleanup of the git repository.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4722369</td>
<td>Certain platforms with a SATA disk for NCQ might cause IO errors sending the SSD into read-only mode. You might see ports going down until the switch reboots. There is no observable performance impact due to this issue.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4721298</td>
<td>When node or VM migration occurs between the MLAG pair and the EVPN-MH pair, the MLAG MAC database becomes out of sync with kernel FDB. The migrated MAC addresses remain as local in MLAG MAC database whereas in the kernel, all MAC addresses are updated correctly as remote with the layer 2 next hop ID. To work around this issue, flap the MLAG bond interface to clear the MLAG local database.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4717888</td>
<td>When using the CPU port as a SPAN destination, the switch might become unresponsive and, or reboot. To work around this issue, use SPAN to a local port instead of the CPU port.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.0</td>
<td>5.15.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4717494</td>
<td>When you run the {{nv show vrf default router rib}} command, NVUE returns an {{ItemDoesNotExist }} error. To work around this issue, run the following commands to retrieve IPv6 routing information:
nv show vrf default router rib ipv6
nv show vrf default router rib ipv6 route</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4716836</td>
<td>After upgrading the switch with {{onie-install -t}}, NTP configuration is missing and does not work. This issue does not occur with package or optimized image upgrade.</td>
<td>5.15.0</td>
<td>5.15.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4714845</td>
<td>The switch installs suboptimal routes in the routing table and advertises them out.</td>
<td>5.9.2-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4714618</td>
<td>On switches at scale with OTEL enabled, an {{interface_stats_collector}} crash might occur with the following logs:
{{interface_stats_collector[3429270]: ERROR buffer_stats_collector.go:1875 SDK bulk counter read failed
interface_stats_collector[3429270]: fatal error: concurrent map iteration and map write
interface_stats_collector[3429270]: goroutine 5610 gp=0xc007814c40 m=16 mp=0xc000552808 [running]:}}</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4709579</td>
<td>Using package upgrade in Cumulus Linux 5.15 and earlier might show syslog errors similar to {{BTF: failed to validate kernel module -22}}. These syslog errors are largely inconsequential and occur when loading new modules on an older kernel. Kernel modules still function correctly but BTF debug information might be unavailable until the switch reboots after upgrade.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4707967</td>
<td>When you use NVUE to configure a user with a username that is used as a group name in the system, you see the following error message:
User name {} is already in use as OS group name 'and could not be used as username.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4707930</td>
<td>When you configure a high number of 802.1x IPv6 profiles, the {{nv show system dot1x ipv6-profile}} command might return {{no data}}. To work around this issue, run the {{nv show system dot1x ipv6-profile --applied}} command.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4706305</td>
<td>The gNMI interface statistics collector reports the error {{Failed to get SRv6 no sid drop counter: No-SID counter not available in syslog}} even when SRv6 is disabled.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4706274</td>
<td>When {{switchd}} terminates (on system shutdown or service restart), the switch does not clean up PBR ACL rules that reference ECMP groups before the SDK de-initializes. This causes SDK errors in the cleanup sequence.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4704406</td>
<td>TACACS authentication mode is not configured correctly in PAM common authentication and TACACS configuration files, which makes {{login}} the authentication mode regardless of the NVUE configuration.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4702667</td>
<td>When you run the {{nv show vrf default router rib}} command, NVUE returns an ItemDoesNotExist error. This error occurs because the vtysh {{show ip route vrf default brief json}} command does not return any output, which propagates through NVUE. To work around this issue, run the {{nv show vrf default router rib ipv6}} and {{nv show vrf default router rib ipv6 route}} commands instead.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4693175</td>
<td>There is a mismatch between NVUE and gNMI telemetry for latency-measurement data on network interfaces with high sample intervals. For example, when you remove traffic class configurations from interfaces, NVUE correctly updates to reflect only active traffic classes; however, gNMI telemetry continues to report stale latency-measurement entries for the removed traffic classes. The stale entries include outdated error-type responses (TIMEOUT) with timestamps from previous runs. These stale entries persist across multiple polling cycles.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4692400</td>
<td>You see the error {{Failed to get SRv6 no sid drop counter: No-SID counter not available in syslog}} even when SRv6 is disabled.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4691719</td>
<td>NVUE allows you create more than the maximum of 64 destination NAT rules, which results in a configuration error.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4687371</td>
<td>On the spectrum-5 switch when a single traffic class is given 100% dwrr, the default global scheduler profile shows traffic class 5,6,7 as dwrr even though the scheduling mode is strict priority. There is no functional impact with this issue.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4685693</td>
<td>When you configure the RADIUS authentication order for RADIUS then local, and you grant sudo access for users with privilege level 1, Cumulus Linux also grants sudo access for users with privilege level 0.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4683616</td>
<td>When you configure the same 802.1X port ID on multiple ports using the same IPv6 profile, the switch might assign duplicate IPv6 addresses to those ports. To work around this issue, configure a unique port ID for each port with an IPv6 profile or omit the explicit port ID configuration to allow the system to assign a unique 802.1X port ID automatically.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4683370</td>
<td>On scale systems with OTEL enabled, you might see an {{interface_stats_collector}} crash with the following logs:
{{interface_stats_collector[41358]: unexpected fault address 0x7fbb941d9110
interface_stats_collector[41358]: fatal error: fault
interface_stats_collector[41358]: [signal SIGSEGV: segmentation violation code=0x1addr=0x7fbb941d9110 pc=0x55124a]}}</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4667792</td>
<td>Usernames longer than 32 characters do not authenticate against the switch. Avoid using long usernames.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4662854</td>
<td>If you configure a DSCP match as {{ANY}}, the gNMI subscription does not show DSCP as {{ANY}}. The OpenConfig model supports only integer DSCP values.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4662695</td>
<td>In an EVPN-MH environment, when you flap all interfaces on a switch or the bridge interface, stale VXLAN route entries might remain installed for locally connected hosts. To work around this issue, flap individual SVI interfaces for the affected routes.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4657192</td>
<td>On the NVIDIA SN5640 switch, after you configure a port as unsplit, links do not come up while optics are in use. To work around this issue, use copper cables.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4650961</td>
<td>When you bring a bond down, then up with the {{ifdown}} and {{ifup}} commands, the sflow rate is not configured correctly after the bond comes up and the sflow sample is not generated. To work around this issue, bring the member port down, then up.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4648833</td>
<td>Interfaces using PAM4 DAC cables on switches with Spectrum-4 and later might not come up after a link flap or reboot if auto-negotiation is disabled. Auto-negotiation is required for PAM4 DAC cables on these switches.</td>
<td>5.15.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4643073</td>
<td>Concurrent {{mlxfwmanager --query}} executions triggered by gNMI telemetry polling might cause MFT deadlock, resulting in repeated core dumps, {{nvued}} restarts, and control plane unresponsiveness. </td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4608614</td>
<td>When setting up SSH keys, you have to run {{nv config apply}} twice for the configuration to take effect.</td>
<td>5.11.3-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4582679</td>
<td>If a node has Suppress Route Advertisement enabled and routes are re-learned; for example, when a peer sends the route again due to route policy changes, or you enable or disable graceful shutdown, not all routes are offloaded, which might cause discrepancies in traffic. </td>
<td>5.9.4-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4579237</td>
<td>If interface statistics telemetry is running on the switch, an {{interface_stats_collector}} core file might generate during statistics collection.</td>
<td>5.11.3-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4556982</td>
<td>In the Spanning Tree PVRST environment, when one bridge interface goes down, it causes all the other bridge interfaces to enter a blocking state for approximately ten seconds. Even though the down port is not the root port, all the other bridge ports are flushed and not in service for about ten seconds.</td>
<td>5.13.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4551249</td>
<td>The NVUE service might fail during switch upgrade. To work around this issue, stop the {{sysmonitor}} with the {{sudo systemctl stop sysmonitor}} command, then upgrade the switch with the {{nv action upgrade system packages to latest}} command.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4549896</td>
<td>When you try to set a VXLAN with a bridge, you see the error {{sx_sdk: 22985 [BRIDGE] [ERROR  ]: Port(0x200A000D)) already added to a bridge}}. You can safely ignore this error.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4548514</td>
<td>When FRR installs a connected route for an SVI interface with VRR, the route might install with the next hop interface of the VRR device instead of the SVI. For example, instead of interface {{vlan10}}, the route might install against {{vlan10-v0}}. This prevents next-hop tracking and route installation into hardware.
This issue can occur in the following conditions:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;When initially configuring VRF route leaking, the target VRF might not install a route into hardware when leaking directly connected routes for SVI interfaces with VRR enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In an MLAG and VRR configuration, static routes fail to install when the route is resolved through a connected route and the interface of the connected route undergoes a link state change for any reason, such as link flaps, interface bring-up, {{clagd}} restart, {{switchd}} restart, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
To work around this issue, restart the FRR service using the {{sudo systemctl restart frr.service}} command. </td>
<td>5.9.1-5.9.3, 5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td>5.9.4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4548512</td>
<td>When a connected route for an SVI interface with VRR configured is installed by FRR, the route might be installed with the next hop interface of the VRR device instead of the SVI. For example, instead of interface {{vlan10}}, the route might install against {{vlan10-v0}}. This prevents next-hop tracking and route installation into hardware.
This issue can occur in the following conditions:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;When initially configuring VRF route leaking, the target VRF might not install a route into hardware when leaking directly connected routes for SVI interfaces with VRR enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In an MLAG and VRR configuration, static routes fail to install when the route is resolved through a connected route and the interface of the connected route undergoes a link state change for any reason, such as link flaps, interface bring-up, {{clagd}} restart, {{switchd}} restart, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
To work around this issue, restart the FRR service using the {{sudo systemctl restart frr.service}} command. </td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4547463</td>
<td>When you try to run {{nv action boot-next}} commands during optimized image upgrade, the commands time out. This does not necessarily mean an issue occurred; the system might still be executing the action.To check that the action command completed before going to the next step to reboot the system:
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find the Request ID for the REST API invocation corresponding to the {{nv action boot-next}} command by doing a grep for {{ActionKey.*boot-next}} in the /var/log/nvued.log}} file. For example, the value 3 in the {{Ran Job running ActionKey('@boot-next', '/system/image', (), 3, (('partition', 'partition1'),))}} line indicates the Request ID.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the {{curl -u '&lt;username&gt;:&lt;password&gt;'  -X GET https://127.0.0.1:8765/nvue_v1/action/&lt;Request ID&gt; -k}} command from the shell to show the status of the action command. If the value of {{state}} is {{action_success}}, the action command completed successfully. If the value of {{state}} is {{running}}, the system is still processing. If the value of {{state}} is {{action_error}}, the system encountered an error.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4535806</td>
<td>After a factory reset, the switch does not clear the {{/var/tmp}} directory, which the switch uses for temporary files.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4535749</td>
<td>The {{uc-discards}} field in the {{nv show interface &lt;interface&gt; counters qos egress-queue-stats}} command output is actually the number of packets discarded per queue, but it is wrongly interpreted as bytes. To work around this issue, convert the data shown in bytes to packets by multiplying by 1024 if the data is in KB, 1024x1024 if the data is in MB, and 1024x1024x1024 if the data is in GB.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4535699</td>
<td>When you configure the RADIUS authentication order with {{local}} first and {{radius second}}, the RADIUS user is authenticated as a default user name. </td>
<td>5.11.3-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4535696</td>
<td>When you configure the RADIUS authentication order with {{local}} first and {{radius second}}, the RADIUS user is authenticated as a default user name. </td>
<td>5.12.1-5.15.1</td>
<td>5.9.4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4534357</td>
<td>During Cumulus Linux upgrade or downgrade, {{rsyslog}} might crash because the management (eth0) port is unavailable, which triggers a use-after-free fault and  produces a cl-support file as a response.</td>
<td>5.13.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4531960</td>
<td>The GNMI Subscription to xpath {{interfaces/interface[name=swp61s0]/state/counters/out-pkts}} with a high sample interval results in an initial response of zero but in subsequent updates, the value is correct. You do not see this issue when the sample interval is 1 second.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4509255</td>
<td>In PTP two-step, the hardware incorrectly modifies the SYNC message correction field.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4508830</td>
<td>Cumulus Linux allows you to add bond ports of mismatched speeds (such as 10G and 25G) to the same LACP bond without error and the bond reports UP. </td>
<td>5.11.2-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4501632</td>
<td>NVIDIA recommends you wait for approximately 60 seconds after running {{nv config apply}} before power cycling the switch so that NVUE database has time to sync to the filesystem. </td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4495383</td>
<td>NVUE configuration yaml file translation converts unset commands to set commands because the translation logic expects only set commands. </td>
<td>5.13.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4495231</td>
<td>If the hardware clock date is later than 2038-01-19 03:14:07 UTC, the image might fail to install due to a grub-install failure on the EFI filesystem, which is a VFAT filesystem.  As a result, you see the grub prompt immediately after reboot.  To work around this issue, reboot from the grub prompt to go into ONIE.  From ONIE, use the date command to set a date before 2038-01-19, then run the {{hwclock --systohc}} command to add it to the hardware clock.  You can then use {{onie-nos-install}} to install the image.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4475401</td>
<td>External input such as Ctrl+\ might trigger core dumps on the serial console from {{/bin/login}}. This behavior is caused by external sources, such as console servers or automation tools, and does not reflect a fault in the operating system. As a potential result, the serial console might become unresponsive.</td>
<td>5.14.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4475111</td>
<td>When you try to convert a layer 3 port that is part of ECMP to a bond member,  you might see a failure in the {{switchd}} logs. This issue does not have any functional impact.</td>
<td>5.11.2-5.15.1</td>
<td>5.9.4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4440766</td>
<td>When you try to delete a trusted ca key, Cumulus Linux shows an incorrect error message. To remove a trusted ca key, you must unset the key ID, not the key literal.</td>
<td>5.13.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4423248</td>
<td>If you unset an interface static IP address when the interface IP gateway is configured, the {{nv config apply}} command fails with an {{ifreload.service}} error. To work around this issue, unset both the static IP address and gateway together.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4423244</td>
<td>When you enable, then disable adaptive routing, the BGP neighbors might go down because of an unresolved MAC address. To work around this issue, configure another attribute on the interface.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4423175</td>
<td>When you configure an API port with a TCP port already in use, the {{nginx}} server fails to restart.</td>
<td>5.13.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4413589</td>
<td>A MAC-only EVPN type-2 route is wrongly advertised with the layer 3 VNI label in the BGP NLRI (Network Layer Reachability Information). Although this does not have any functional impact, it is not the desired RFC behavior.</td>
<td>5.13.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4337278</td>
<td>In certain cases, statically configured VXLAN entries age out after a peerlink flap.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4329931</td>
<td>Cumulus Linux incorrectly allows SyncE and PPS to be enabled at the same time. Upgrading systems with both features configured using NVUE to 5.12.0 or later results in a failure to apply the startup configuration as part of the first boot of the upgraded version. To work around the issue, unset one of the features before you upgrade.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4309876</td>
<td>When you configure an invalid switch port (swp), NVUE adds the invalid configuration instead of rejecting it. The invalid interface in the configuration does not have any functional impact.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4308857</td>
<td>When you use {{tls_crlcheck}} in the {{/etc/nslcd.conf}} file, the optional {{nslcd}} service fails due to a missing library.</td>
<td>5.9.2-5.9.3, 5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td>5.9.4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4294156</td>
<td>After you clear the RoCE counters with the {{nv action clear interface &lt;interface-id&gt; qos roce counters}} command, the {{buffer-max-usage}} counters in the {{nv show interface &lt;interface-id&gt; qos roce counters}} command output do not show updated (cleared) values.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4277042</td>
<td>On the NVIDIA SN5600 switch, you see low power alarms immediately after a reboot. The alarms disappear after showing up initially. Certain modules typically show low power alarms on initialization. No action is needed.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4249096</td>
<td>Binary upgrade from Cumulus Linux 4.3.1 to 5.12.0 and later is not supported. To work around this issue, perform a binary upgrade from Cumulus Linux 4.3.1 to 5.9.0, then perform a binary upgrade from Cumulus Linux 5.9.0 to 5.12.0 or later.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4236419</td>
<td>On the Spectrum-3 switch, the PTP offset for 25GbE fluctuates within a range of plus or minus 50 nanoseconds beyond the expected values.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4214678</td>
<td>Changes to open telemetry configuration or export states restarts the telemetry service and resets all health metrics.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4177067</td>
<td>When performing a package upgrade, {{nslcd}} installation might open an interactive dialog to configure {{nslcd.conf }}.To avoid this interactive dialog, set the {{DEBIAN_FRONTEND}} environment variable to {{noninteractive}}. For example:
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo apt-get update
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo DEBIAN_FRONTEND=noninteractive apt-get -y -o "Dpkg::Options::=--force-confdef" -o "Dpkg::Options::=--force-confold" upgrade</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4154839</td>
<td>When you run certain SDK commands (such as {{sudo sx_api_port_counter_dump_all.py}} or {{sx_api_fdb_dump}}) first as the cumulus user, then with {{sudo}}, you see the following error:
PermissionError: Errno 13] Permission denied: '/tmp/python_err_log.txt'
To resolve this issue, run the {{rm -rf /tmp/python_err_log.txt}} command.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4142857</td>
<td>The switch drops PTP packets received with extra ethernet padding and you see syslog {{[ptp4l.ERR] messages.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4139511</td>
<td>When you generate the cl-support file on the Spectrum-4 switch, the following messages appear on the serial console. You can safely ignore this issue.[ 1903.595131] mlxsw_minimal 2-0048: Could not acquire lock
[ 1903.601089] mlxsw_minimal 2-0048: Reg cmd access failed (reg_id=900a(mtmp),type=query)
[ 1903.609961] hwmon hwmon28: Failed to query module temperature thresholds
[ 1903.846724] mlxsw_minimal 2-0048: Could not acquire lock
[ 1903.852689] mlxsw_minimal 2-0048: Reg cmd access failed (reg_id=900a(mtmp),type=query)
[ 1903.861573] hwmon hwmon28: Failed to query module temperature</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4134447</td>
<td>The journal logs might include the error message {{ERR kernel: [    7.453789] usb usb2-port2: connect-debounce failed}}. You can safely ignore this log message.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4129757</td>
<td>If you include a comma in the BGP community list, extended community list, or large community list regex expression of a routing policy, you see error messages and FRR reload fails. Make sure the regex expression does not contain a comma. For example, instead of {{^65550:([0-9]{1,2}|[1-9][1-9]):.*$}}, specify {{^65550:([0-9]|[0-9][0-9]):.*$}} and instead of {{^65550:([0-4]{1,2}|[7-9][8-9]):.*$}}, specify {{^65550:([0-4]|[0-4][0-4]|[7-9][8-9]):.*$}}.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4124376</td>
<td>The SN3700C-S, SN5400, and SN5600 secure boot switch running Cumulus Linux 5.11.0 or later boots with shim 15.8 that adds entries to the SBAT revocations to prevent the switch from booting shim 15.7 or earlier (included in Cumulus Linux 5.10 and earlier).To downgrade a secure boot switch from Cumulus Linux 5.11.0 or later, or to recover a downgraded switch that does not boot, follow the steps in &lt;a href="https://docs.nvidia.com/networking-ethernet-software/cumulus-linux/Installation-Management/Upgrading-Cumulus-Linux/#downgrade-a-secure-boot-switch"&gt;Downgrade a Secure Boot Switch&lt;/a&gt;.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4118970</td>
<td>When running PTP, the performance for 100Gx2 and 400Gx8 can have a high offset in up to 1.5% of the sampling. </td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4105127</td>
<td>Any sFlow configuration changes that require an {{hsflowd}} restart are operational only after an initial delay of 60 seconds.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4100629</td>
<td>NVUE show command outputs show LLDP neighbor changes only after the LLDP update frequency multiplied by the hold time.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4082210</td>
<td>When you change the CPU resource limit with the {{nv set service control rsyslog resource-limit cpu &lt;value&gt;}} command, the {{rsyslog}} agent does not start. To work around this issue, increase the CPU resource limit, then restart the service manually.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4077921</td>
<td>You cannot use package upgrade to upgrade from Cumulus Linux 5.9.2 to Cumulus Linux 5.10.1 or later. You must install the Cumulus Linux image instead.</td>
<td>5.10.1-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4049213</td>
<td>When there are routes that point to a single next hop, an ECMP entry is created in the SDK. After the single next hop from the route is removed, the ECMP entry might stay in the SDK until the time the next hop is present in the kernel.</td>
<td>5.9.2-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4047798</td>
<td>Packet distribution based on ECMP hashing using GTP-TEID does not function as expected in an EVPN Clos topology.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4030380</td>
<td>When you roll back interface configuration to the default setting with the {{nv unset interface}} command, NVUE removes the complete entry for the interface from the {{/etc/network/interface}} file, and puts the interface in admin down. As a result, you cannot configure FEC on the interface at the lower layers.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4005422</td>
<td>When you upgrade Cumulus Linux 5.9.1 to Cumulus Linux 5.10 or later with package upgrade, the NTP service stops. To restart the NTP service, enable, then restart the service in the VRF in which it was running with the {{systemctl enable ntpsec@&lt;vrf&gt;}} and {{systemctl restart ntpsec@&lt;vrf&gt;}} commands.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3985682</td>
<td>On Spectrum-4 switches, multicast flows containing packets smaller than 512 bytes might not reach full line rate. Cumulus Linux supports 512 byte and larger multicast packets.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3966312</td>
<td>When connecting the SN5xxx switch to third party test equipment (such as IXIA) using copper cables at 100GbE, 200GbE, 400GbE, or 800GbE, links do not come up.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3948068</td>
<td>On the SN3700 and SN3700c switch, the {{nv show platform environment voltage}} command output shows a failed state for the {{PSU-n-12V-RAIL-OUT}} sensors.  This is a known hardware limitation that cannot be corrected by the PSU vendor.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3915878</td>
<td>If you configure remote syslog export through a non-default VRF, you might see repeated error logs from the {{rsyslog}} process while the switch is booting:
rsyslogd: create UDP socket bound to device failed: No such device [v8.2302.0]
rsyslogd: No UDP socket could successfully be initialized, some functionality may be disabled.  [v8.2302.0]
The logs occur because the {{rsyslog}} service starts before the networking service creates the configured VRF for syslog export. There is no functional impact with this issue.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3879717</td>
<td>Running {{snmpwalk}} on the switch with the management IP address does not work. To work around this issue, use the localhost option ({{snmpwalk -v 2c -c public28 localhost 1.3.6.1.2.1.14}}) or create a control plane ACL whitelist rule.</td>
<td>5.10.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3878394</td>
<td>When ZTP runs a script that contains {{wget}}, ZTP fails and you see a message similar to the following:
ZTP: ZTP DHCP: Unexpected error: 'ascii' codec can't decode byte 0xe2 in position 181: ordinal not in range(128)
ZTP: Script returned failure 
To work around this issue, use the {{-q}} option with {{wget}}.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3877516</td>
<td>When you connect two NVIDIA switches and configure 400G speed in force mode, links don't come up.To work around this issue, make sure auto-negotiation is always on when connecting NVIDIA to NVIDIA in PAM4.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3875373</td>
<td>When you run the {{nv config apply empty}} command, NVUE removes the {{cumulus user}}. If you are logged in as the {{cumulus}} user when you run the {{nv config apply empty}} command, the command fails.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3861745</td>
<td>On UEFI hardware (where the {{/sys/firmware/efi}} directory exists), using the update-grub program might generate a {{/boot/grub/grub.cfg}} that is incorrect for booting ONIE if the ONIE option is selected on the console while booting. To work around this issue, run {{mount LABEL="EFI System" /boot/efi}} before using update-grub.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3855796</td>
<td>When configuring a Unicast Master Table for clients, the server addresses must be reachable and the route to the destination must exist. The unicast table can have one directly-connected port for a client. This restriction is only for directly connected ports and doesn't apply to Unicast Servers on other devices or switches.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3847439</td>
<td>In rare cases on the Spectrum 1 switch, where a dual connected host transmits all traffic flows to only one switch in a connected MLAG pair, and the host changes behavior to hash all flows to the other MLAG switch, there might be traffic loss if the MAC FDB entry on the original switch ages out.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3819945</td>
<td>When you connect an NVIDIA SN4410, SN4700, or SN5600 switch to any Spectrum 1, Spectrum-2, or Spectrum-3 peer switch (with four lanes) using a 4x breakout configuration and the default lanes per port setting, links do not come up. To work around this issue, provide the lanes per port configuration shown below:
cumulus@switch:~$ nv set interface &lt;interface&gt; link breakout 4x lanes-per-port 1</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3818545</td>
<td>The terminal monitoring software SecureCRT has a known issue when running on both Windows and Mac systems where it gets stuck when monitoring the serial port of the switch as Cumulus Linux boots up.  When this occurs, the serial port stops as shown below and SecureCRT is unable to receive any more serial data from the switch (it is able to transmit).

Mounting dev-hugepages.mount - Huge Pages File System...
Mounting dev-mqueue.mount
</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3774274</td>
<td>When you manually configure the {{/etc/cumulus/datapath/qos/qos_features.conf}} file without applying the QoS configuration with NVUE, running the {{nv config apply empty}} command later does not clean up the QoS configuration. If the QoS configuration includes breakout ports, the {{nv config apply empty}} command fails due to a {{switchd}} reload trigger failure. To work around this issue, clean up the configuration manually in the {{/etc/cumulus/datapath/qos/qos_features.conf}}, then run the {{nv config apply empty}} command.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3773177</td>
<td>When you try to upgrade a switch from Cumulus Linux before 5.6.0 with package upgrade, you might see errors for expired GPG keys that prevent you from upgrading. To work around this issue, install the new keys with the following commands, then upgrade the switch.

cumulus@switch:~$ wget https://download.nvidia.com/cumulus/apt.cumulusnetworks.com/repo/pool/cumulus/c/cumulus-archive-keyring/cumulus-archive-keyring_4-cl5.6.0u5_all.deb
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo apt install ./cumulus-archive-keyring_4-cl5.6.0u5_all.deb
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo apt update
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo apt upgrade
</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3771168</td>
<td>When you perform an ISSU upgrade on a Spectrum 1 switch, the {{switchd}} service might crash.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3677533</td>
<td>Due to resource constraints on the Spectrum 1 switch, {{staticd}} performance drops and  takes longer to read static routes compared to the time BGP takes to complete a graceful restart and advertise routes and EOR to its helpers. As a result, static routes are advertised after the EOR is sent to graceful restart helpers, which delete the stale static routes and relearn them after receiving the EOR from the restarting node. Temporary traffic loss might occur.</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3655681</td>
<td>When you disable, then enable STP auto-edge on a port, the port might not transition to the operational edge even though the port does not receive bpdus. To work around this issue, configure the port as an admin-edge port.</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3637444</td>
<td>Applying an inbound control plane ACL on the eth0 management interface does not take effect. To work around this issue, apply the ACL on the {{mgmt}} interface; for example, {{nv set interface mgmt acl &lt;acl-id&gt; inbound control-plane}}.</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3591918</td>
<td>The {{nv action disconnect system aaa user}} command does not clear all open sessions. To work around this issue, run the command as many times as the number of sessions.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3587393</td>
<td>If you use the NVIDIA SN5600 (Spectrum-4) switch with Ixia test equipment, you might experience delayed link up due to intermittent link flaps. 
To work around this issue when using copper cables:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use Ixia IxOS version 9.37 with HF002156, or version 9.39 or later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the DAC cable on ports 10 through 50.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use NVIDIA cables with the recommended firmware revision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure AN on the Cumulus Linux switch and AN/LT on Ixia.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
To work around this issue when using fiber cables:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Configure 800g/Force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the recommended NVIDIA optical adapters.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3556762</td>
<td>On rare occasions, SPT switchover might not happen cleanly in PIM resulting in some dropped packets. If you use PIM-SM to replicate EVPN BUM traffic, you might see a brief drop of multicast traffic before recovering due to normal PIM-SM traffic timeout.</td>
<td>5.5.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3540510</td>
<td>400Gx8 ports only support traffic line rate with packets that are larger than 172 bytes.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3538321</td>
<td>In rare cases, an STP topology change on PTP over a VLAN can result in the switch losing the slave state and one of the ports might remain in an uncalibrated state. To work around this issue, toggle the port that is in the uncalibrated state up and down so that one of the ports is selected as the slave.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3497622</td>
<td>When you remove PSUs, then plug them back in, you might   experience traffic loss and some ports might be in a down state.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3472163</td>
<td>On a switch with the Spectrum-4 ASIC, packets that are smaller than 256 bytes are not included in multicast flows.  Multicast flows support packets that are 256 bytes or larger.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3444490</td>
<td>Migration from ONYX to Cumulus Linux is supported and tested with ONYX version 3.10.4302 GA only.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3442569</td>
<td>When trying to access the NVUE API, user accounts authenticated with a newly-configured external service, such as TACACS, RADIUS, or LDAP, receive a 401 forbidden error. To work around this issue, after enabling a new authentication service, make sure to restart both {{nginx.service}} and {{nvued.service}} to begin authenticating users against the new authentication service.</td>
<td>5.5.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3430430</td>
<td>When you configure PTP on 50G ports, the offset correction might be higher, which can affect the time synchronization of the node. To work around this issue, configure PTP on 100G ports, or on 10G or 1G ports with PTP shaper enabled.</td>
<td>5.5.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3424967</td>
<td>{{sudo}} for TACACS+ users with privilege level 15 does not work when reaching the TACACS+ server through the {{default}} VRF. To work around this issue, specify the interface name that the {{default}} VRF uses in the {{vrf=}} setting of the {{/etc/tacplus_servers}} file or run the NVUE {{nv set system aaa tacacs vrf}} command. If you don't run either command, a TACACS+ user with privilege level 15 can run {{vrf task exec default sudo ...}} to execute the {{sudo}} command.</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3420056</td>
<td>
The ADVA 5401 SFP module with hardware revision 5.01 does not come up at layer 1 when you use 10G QSA adaptors. To work around this issue, use 25G QSA adaptors.</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3414866</td>
<td>Each VLAN is represented as a bitmap on the underlying port and when you add multiple VLANs together, Cumulus Linux iterates over the existing ones and updates the diff. However, in few corner cases, the same bitmap might be repeated again causing the following error.
sx_sdk: 22985 [BRIDGE] [ERROR  ]: Port(0x200A000D)) already added to a bridge
You can ignore this error; it has no impact on switch functionality.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3362113</td>
<td>If you restore an NVUE {{startup.yaml}} file or run the {{nv config patch}} command after an upgrade that includes breakout ports with QoS configuration, the NVUE configuration fails to apply. Subsequent attempts to run {{nv config apply}} fail with a message similar to {{Invalid config [rev_id: 11] qos config is not supported on the following invalid interface: swp1s0. Supported on swp and bond interface types}}. To work around this issue, run {{nv unset}} on the configured QoS settings, then apply the breakout port configuration before you configure QoS. Alternatively, you can remove the QoS configuration from the {{yaml}} file and patch it separately after applying the breakout configuration.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3347538</td>
<td>When connecting NVIDIA-to-NVIDIA in PAM4, you must enable auto-negotiation.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3341214</td>
<td>If you use the NVUE REST API to configure a local user with a hashed password, the user cannot log in and the {{/etc/nvue.d/startup.yaml}} file shows the password as plain text.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3329518</td>
<td>When using TACACS+, if the {{/etc/nsswitch.conf}} file specifies {{passwd: files tacplus}} (files is listed before tacplus), a user that is present in both the local {{/etc/passwd}} file and the TACACS+ server cannot log into the switch. NVIDIA recommends that when using TACACS+, you list {{tacplus}} before {{files}} in {{/etc/nsswitch.conf}}.  When using NVUE, ensure that {{tacacs}} has priority over {{local}}.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3327477</td>
<td>If you use {{su}} to change to a user specified through TACACS+, the user becomes the local tacacs0 thru tacacs15 user instead of the named user to run {{sudo}} commands. As a result, the named user password might not match the local tacacs0 thru tacacs15 user password.</td>
<td>3.7.0-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3326659</td>
<td>If you have a large number of MAC addresses, they do not age out at the MAC ageing timeout value configured on the switch. It might take up to 30 seconds more for the MAC addresses to age out and be deleted from the hardware. To work around this issue, wait for the ageing timeout value plus 30 seconds.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3253218</td>
<td>Auto-negotiation isn't supported on Spectrum-2 and Spectrum-3 switches using the 1G SFP-T module; FORCE 1G is configured instead. </td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3241567</td>
<td>When you apply switch configuration for the first time on a freshly booted switch and you run the {{nv config apply}} command after setting the hostname with {{nv set system hostname}}, you might see the error message {{Failed to start Hostname Service}}. To work around this issue, run the {{nv config apply}} command a second time.</td>
<td>5.3.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3226506</td>
<td>The {{l1-show eth0}} command does not show port information and is not supported in this release. </td>
<td>5.3.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3225117</td>
<td>Occasionally, packet loss might occur on 25G ports when the link is raised without FEC.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3172504</td>
<td>When you connect the NVIDIA SN4600C switch to a Spectrum 1 or Spectrum-3 switch with a 40GbE passive copper cable (Part Number: MC2210126-005) on edge ports 1-4 and 61-64, there is an Effective BER of 1E-12 in PHY.</td>
<td>5.2.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3147782</td>
<td>You cannot use NVUE to configure an SNMP view to include a subtree beginning with a period. For example:

cumulus@switch:~$ nv set service snmp-server viewname cumulusOnly included .1.3.6.1.4.1.40310
Error: GET /nvue_v1/service/snmp-server/viewname/cumulusOnly/included?pointers=%5B%22%2Fparameters%22%2C+%22%2Fpatch%2FrequestBody%2Fcontent%2Fapplication~1json%2Fschema%22%2C+%22%2Fpatch%2Fparameters%22%2C+%22%2Fpatch%2Fresponses%2F200%2Flinks%22%5D responded with 404 NOT FOUND

To work around this issue, reference the OID without the preceding period ( {{.}} ) in the command.</td>
<td>5.3.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3145869</td>
<td>On a Spectrum-3 switch, the PTP offset in 10GbE changes between plus or minus 27. The average offset is around 7.</td>
<td>5.2.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3135952</td>
<td>PAM4 split cables (such as 2x100G, 4x100G, and 4x50G) do not work with a forced speed setting (when auto-negotiation is off) as the default speed enabled is for NRZ mode (such as 100G_4X). To work around this issue,  set the appropriate lanes for forced speed (with auto-negotation off) with the {{ethtool -s swpX speed &lt;port_speed&gt; autoneg off lanes &lt;no_of_lanes&gt;}} command. For example: 

cumulus@switch:~$ sudo ethtool -s swp1 speed 100000 autoneg off lanes 2
</td>
<td>5.2.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3115242</td>
<td>When you configure two VNIs in the same VLAN, ifupdown2  shows a {{vlan added to two or more VXLANS}} warning, which is only issued after the VNI is already added to the bridge. This leaves the new VNI in the PVID even if there is already an existing VNI configured in that PVID.</td>
<td>5.1.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3103821</td>
<td>On the NVIDIA SN4700 switch, inserting and removing the PSU might cause loss of frames.</td>
<td>5.2.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3084476</td>
<td> After you disable traffic shaping in the {{/etc/cumulus/datapath/qos/qos_features.conf}} file, the default QOS traffic shaping configuration does not restore. To work around this issue, restart {{switchd}}.</td>
<td>4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td>4.4.4-4.4.5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3084027</td>
<td>Under a high load, you might see ingress drop counters increase. The drops are classified as {{HwIfInDiscards}} in ethtool and shown as {{ingress_general}} in hardware.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3071652</td>
<td>On rare occasions, after you reboot or restart {{switchd}} on a Spectrum 1 switch, any 25G connections with Direct Attach Copper (DAC) cables that connect from the switch to a non-NVIDIA device might flap continuously. To work around this issue, bring the affected link administratively down for a few seconds on the non-NVIDIA device, then bring the link back up.</td>
<td>4.4.4-4.4.5, 5.1.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3061656</td>
<td>When the CPU load is high during a warm boot, bonds with a slow LACP rate fail to forward layer 2 traffic for up to 60 seconds (depending on the duration of the CPU load) and static bonds fail to forward layer 2 traffic for up to 5 seconds.</td>
<td>5.1.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2972540</td>
<td>With RADIUS enabled for user shell authentication, there might be a delay in local user authentication for non cumulus user accounts.</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2951110</td>
<td>The {{net show time ntp servers}} command does not show any output with the management VRF.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.1.1-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2904450</td>
<td>When you run the {{ethtool -m}} or the {{l1-show}} command, the 400G interface optical values do not show. 

</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2885305</td>
<td>Certain Murata PSU attributes show intermittently in the sensors command output. To work around this issue, upgrade to the latest PSU firmware on Murata.</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2867042</td>
<td>When connecting the NVIDIA SN4600 switch to another NVIDIA Spectrum switch, you must use auto-negotiation mode (not force mode); otherwise the switch might use the wrong Tx configuration.</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2823307</td>
<td>Cumuls Linux does not support a bond with more than 64 ports.  Any configuration with more than 64 ports in a bond changes all ports to down when you apply the configuration. </td>
<td>5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2736108</td>
<td>When you change the VRRP advertisement interval on the master, the {{master advertisement interval}} field in the {{show vrrp}} command output does not show the updated value.</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2684925</td>
<td>The NVUE {{nv show vrf default router bgp peer}} command produces a 404 not found error.</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2671652</td>
<td>In VXLAN routing environments, you might experience sub-optimal route convergence delays (longer than five seconds) when a prefix transitions to a new ECMP next-hop group. This condition might occur when a VTEP loses ECMP routes through all uplink peerings, then installs the routes through a different path, such as an MLAG peerlink.</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.5.0-5.15.1</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</table>
<table name="Fixed Issues in 5.15.0">
<tr>
<th> Issue ID </th>
<th> Description </th>
<th> Affects </th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4731804</td>
<td>NVUE might fail to apply a configuration due to a mishandling of ranges during a race condition and shows a message similar to the following (the issue is not limited to the transceiver ID or swp ranges):
{{ Invalid config [rev_id: 2]
  The transceiver id[swp1-64] is not valid.}} 
To work around this issue, restart the {{nvued.service}}. To avoid this issue, call each interface in the configuration instead of using ranges.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4686865</td>
<td>An invalid hashed-password string for a local NVUE user causes all {{nv config apply}} operations (including unrelated changes) to fail health checks and raise tracebacks when NVUE attempts to recreate the user. </td>
<td>5.12.0-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4681608</td>
<td>gNMI {{/system/mount-point/}} xPaths unexpectedly return data for {{/dev}}. As {{/dev}} is not a persistent disk, unexpected storage monitoring alerts might be generated.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4680172</td>
<td>In extremely rare circumstances, during a GNMI subscription change for interface or QoS data, a Spectrum ASIC SDK health event ({{SX_HEALTH_FATAL: Health-Check: new failure }}) is observed and the process might become unresponsive. To recover from this issue, reboot the switch.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4667010</td>
<td>When streaming telemetry is enabled, additional logs containing {{ERROR BULK_COUNTER}} might be generated by the switch,  unexpectedly bypassing log suppression rules.</td>
<td>5.12.1-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4663076</td>
<td>When you add or remove routes in a virtual router with numerous configured routes, you might see incorrect routing of certain IP addresses. This can result in packets exiting through incorrect ports or being discarded.</td>
<td>5.3.1-5.11.4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4662494</td>
<td>When there are a very large number of gNMI client subscriptions, the switch might not accept new sessions and metrics might stop generating for existing sessions.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4651578</td>
<td>When you configure a link flap protection threshold to {{0}}, the value is not applied operationally and is not reflected in the {{nv show system link flap-protection}} command.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4647646</td>
<td>If you configure policy-based routing (PBR) rules for more than 32 interfaces, only the rules assigned to the first 32 interfaces are installed in the kernel. </td>
<td>4.4.2-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4647325</td>
<td>Running the {{nv config save}} command while a diff is pending might result in unexpected {{nv config diff}} output. To work around this issue, run the {{nv config diff --verbose}} command.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4643537</td>
<td>The {{nv action clear interface &lt;port&gt;}} command does not clear the in and out packet counters under {{interface/&lt;port&gt;/link/stats}}.</td>
<td>5.12.1-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4641806</td>
<td>When gNMI streaming is enabled and clients are subscribed to system information such as the firmware version with xPath {{&apos;/components/component[name=*]/state/firmware-version&apos;}}, the {{nv config replace}} command might take longer than expected to complete.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4641291</td>
<td>In rare circumstances, the switch stops streaming telemetry data for interface counters, buffers, or phy.</td>
<td>5.13.1-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4640126</td>
<td>LLDP session flaps might result in a PTMD process crash due to a double free memory block.</td>
<td>5.11.2-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4638802</td>
<td>When you attempt to set a new BGP peer group on a neighbor with a current peer group configured, NVUE fails to apply the new configuration. To work around this issue, remove the existing peer group before configuring the new one.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4637200</td>
<td>When more than one IPv4 and/or IPv6 addresses are configured on a remote interface, NVUE LLDP commands such as {{nv show interface lldp-detail}} only reflect one address. To work around this issue, use {{lldpctl}} to view LLDP information. For example, {{sudo lldpctl -d -f json swp1}}. </td>
<td>5.9.0-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4634976</td>
<td>When you run the {{nv action fetch system packages key &lt;key&gt;}} command, the command fails. To work around this issue, use the {{apt-key-adv --fetch-keys &lt;key&gt;}} command instead.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4634819</td>
<td>The switch does not provide any gNMI sensor path metrics. A sync-response message indicates that the gNMI server has finished sending all the update messages but no messages are sent.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4633514</td>
<td>When the switch processes large numbers of mroute updates in an MLAG configuration, FRR might crash.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4629293</td>
<td>The {{nv show system telemetry}} command output shows the global port but not the per destination port, which makes it look like the port configured and displayed do not match.</td>
<td>5.12.1-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4625480</td>
<td>When you configure TACACS+ for the first time on a switch with the {{nv set system aaa tacacs enable on}} command, the {{nvued}} service must be restarted before TACACS+ per-command authorization can be configured with any {{nv set system aaa tacacs authorization} commands.</td>
<td>5.11.2-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4625452</td>
<td>Trying to apply a hashed password of '*' blocks access to the switch instead of rejecting the password and showing an error.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4622487</td>
<td>When you configure an {{exclude_users}} line in {{/etc/tacplus_nss.conf}} containing a long list of users, NSS lookups might fail or behave incorrectly when parsing the configuration. </td>
<td>5.11.1-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4621759</td>
<td>When many BFD sessions are configured at scale, {{ptmd}} might crash when one of the BFD sessions flaps.</td>
<td>5.3.1-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4621717</td>
<td>When you configure TACACS+ for the first time on a switch with the {{nv set system aaa tacacs enable on}} command, the {{nvued}} service must be restarted before TACACS+ per-command authorization can be configured with any {{nv set system aaa tacacs authorization} commands.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4621451</td>
<td>Changing the gateway interface IP address on the DHCP relay causes DHCP relay to not forward the packet. To work around this issue, restart the DHCP relay service corresponding to the VRF on which it is running.</td>
<td>5.13.1-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4618809</td>
<td>When collecting streaming telemetry data for per-process information and statistics from the system, you might see false errors about unavailable process IDs in the logs.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4616352</td>
<td>The NVUE {{nv config diff}} command returns an incorrect exit code of 1 instead of 0 for successfully staged changes. As a result, ansible automation fails, which relies on program return codes to determine whether the commands are successful.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4608007</td>
<td>Load interval configuration changes with the {{nv set system counter rates load-interval}} command do not take effect.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4607997</td>
<td>The values returned by the gNMI metrics {{/components/component/power-supply/state/input-voltage}} and {{power-supply/state/input-current}} do not match the power consumption values in the NVUE command output.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4607838</td>
<td>You might see convergence degradation in remote link failure scenarios due to very chatty LTTng traces.   </td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4607288</td>
<td>You might see convergence degradation in a remote link failure scenario due to very chatty LTTNG traces that add logging overhead.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4605303</td>
<td>The downstream VNI software VXLAN encapsulation path does not derive the source IP address of the outer IP header properly. Instead of using the defined {{vxlan-local-tunnelip}} under the loopback interface, it uses the underlay interface on which the packet egresses the VTEP. In a mixed vendor environment, this might lead to a drop on the decapsulating VTEP if it is not an Nvidia Cumulus Linux switch. To work around this issue, use symmetric VNI configuration instead of downstream VNI or use downstream VNI with an unnumbered underlay.</td>
<td>5.13.0-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4601056</td>
<td>The neighbor manager service memory usage increases significantly after the number of entries in the kernel neighbor table exceeds the {{gc_threshold}}.</td>
<td>5.13.1-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4597334</td>
<td>NVUE shows SRv6 statistics intermittently even though static SID configuration is present.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4597330</td>
<td>The switch sends out IPv6 neighbor discovery (ND) router advertisement through an interface that does not have router advertisement enabled. To prevent this issue, do not change or remove the remote-as of a peer-group that is used by BGP unnumbered peers.  To work around this issue, restart FRR.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4597153</td>
<td>When you use a gateway-interface configuration with the source IP address as the gateway interface, DHCP Relay is unable to send packets to the DHCP server after flapping the gateway interface. To work around this issue, restart the DHCP Relay service or avoid configuring the gateway interface to be same as the uplink or downlink interface on the DHCP Relay node.</td>
<td>5.13.1-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4582566</td>
<td>The {{cnp_pg_map}} and {{roce_pg_map}} fields are missing in the NVUE {{nv show interface &lt;interface&gt; qos roce status}} and {{nv show interface qos-roce-status}} commands.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4579137</td>
<td>TTL exceeded packets might not have the expected source IP address in the forwarding path to the destination when VRF interfaces are present on the forwarding path.</td>
<td>5.13.1-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4570105</td>
<td>During initial configuration of an MLAG switch with no MLAG peer or if both MLAG peers go down and only one recovers, VXLAN traffic arriving on the MLAG switch with a local IP destination might see packet loss. </td>
<td>5.13.1-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4567894</td>
<td>ACL statistics in {{nv show interface acl statistics}} and {{cl-acltool}} command output count packets twice. If packets are transiting the switch, the ACL statistics are correct.</td>
<td>5.13.1-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4566678</td>
<td>If you enable LACP bypass mode on a bond, the switch removes the member ports from the interface and the {{nv show interface &lt;interface-id&gt; qos roce status}} command shows {{Error: The requested item does not exist}}. To work around this issue, run the {{nv show interface &lt;interface-id&gt; qos roce status}} command on the member physical port. </td>
<td>5.13.1-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4562806</td>
<td>When there is a very high volume of MLD traffic in a VXLAN environment, the switch CPU and control protocols might be impacted.</td>
<td>5.12.0-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4557007</td>
<td>Incorrect prefix boundaries are set for traffic class, switch priority, and port groups for the {{qos/interfaces/interface[interface-id]}} metrics, which sends redundant data.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4556729</td>
<td>OTEL SRv6 metrics might not be sent in the correct format after a {{switchd}} service restart.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4554858</td>
<td>The default poll interval for on-change notifications is set to 10 seconds instead of 1 second for gNMI packet trimming metrics.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4550126</td>
<td>Sometimes NVUE does not show SRv6 statistics even though static SID configuration is present.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4498428</td>
<td>Due to a GCC update in Cumulus Linux 5.14, you might see unexpected log messages, such as {{BPF: Invalid name}} when using package upgrade to upgrade to Cumulus Linux 5.14. You can ignore these messages.</td>
<td>5.14.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4472414</td>
<td>After you modify the IP address of an SVI, DHCP relay uses an old cached IP address instead of the changed IP address. This occurs because DHCP relay monitors the link state change not IP address change.</td>
<td>5.11.0-5.14.0</td>
</tr>
</table>
</tables>