<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monitor Network Protocols and Services on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-the-Network/Monitor-Network-Protocols-and-Services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monitor Network Protocols and Services on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-the-Network/Monitor-Network-Protocols-and-Services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor the BGP Service</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-the-Network/Monitor-Network-Protocols-and-Services/Monitor-the-BGP-Service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-the-Network/Monitor-Network-Protocols-and-Services/Monitor-the-BGP-Service/</guid>
      <description>The Cumulus NetQ UI enables operators to view the health of the BGP service on a network-wide and a per session basis, giving greater insight into all aspects of the service. This is accomplished through two card workflows, one for the service and one for the session. They are described separately here.
Monitor the BGP Service (All Sessions) With NetQ, you can monitor the number of nodes running the BGP service, view switches with the most established and unestablished BGP sessions, and view alarms triggered by the BGP service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor the EVPN Service</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-the-Network/Monitor-Network-Protocols-and-Services/Monitor-the-EVPN-Service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-the-Network/Monitor-Network-Protocols-and-Services/Monitor-the-EVPN-Service/</guid>
      <description>The Cumulus NetQ UI enables operators to view the health of the EVPN service on a network-wide and a per session basis, giving greater insight into all aspects of the service. This is accomplished through two card workflows, one for the service and one for the session. They are described separately here.
Monitor the EVPN Service (All Sessions) With NetQ, you can monitor the number of nodes running the EVPN service, view switches with the sessions, total number of VNIs, and alarms triggered by the EVPN service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor the LLDP Service</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-the-Network/Monitor-Network-Protocols-and-Services/Monitor-the-LLDP-Service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-the-Network/Monitor-Network-Protocols-and-Services/Monitor-the-LLDP-Service/</guid>
      <description>The Cumulus NetQ UI enables operators to view the health of the LLDP service on a network-wide and a per session basis, giving greater insight into all aspects of the service. This is accomplished through two card workflows, one for the service and one for the session. They are described separately here.
Monitor the LLDP Service (All Sessions) With NetQ, you can monitor the number of nodes running the LLDP service, view nodes with the most LLDP neighbor nodes, those nodes with the least neighbor nodes, and view alarms triggered by the LLDP service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor the MLAG Service</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-the-Network/Monitor-Network-Protocols-and-Services/Monitor-the-MLAG-Service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-the-Network/Monitor-Network-Protocols-and-Services/Monitor-the-MLAG-Service/</guid>
      <description>The Cumulus NetQ UI enables operators to view the health of the MLAG service on a network-wide and a per session basis, giving greater insight into all aspects of the service. This is accomplished through two card workflows, one for the service and one for the session. They are described separately here.
MLAG or CLAG?
The Cumulus Linux implementation of MLAG is referred to by other vendors as CLAG, MC-LAG or VPC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor the OSPF Service</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-the-Network/Monitor-Network-Protocols-and-Services/Monitor-the-OSPF-Service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-netq-21/Cumulus-NetQ-UI-User-Guide/Monitor-the-Network/Monitor-Network-Protocols-and-Services/Monitor-the-OSPF-Service/</guid>
      <description>The Cumulus NetQ UI enables operators to view the health of the OSPF service on a network-wide and a per session basis, giving greater insight into all aspects of the service. This is accomplished through two card workflows, one for the service and one for the session. They are described separately here.
Monitor the OSPF Service (All Sessions) With NetQ, you can monitor the number of nodes running the OSPF service, view switches with the most full and unestablished OSPF sessions, and view alarms triggered by the OSPF service.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>