<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>System Configuration on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in System Configuration on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Command Line Utility</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Network-Command-Line-Utility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Network-Command-Line-Utility/</guid>
      <description>The Network Command Line Utility, or NCLU, is a command line interface for Cumulus Networks products, implemented in Cumulus RMP 3.1 and later releases, with the goal of simplifying the networking configuration process for all users.
NCLU resides in the Linux user space, as seen below. It provides consistent access to networking commands directly via bash, thereby making configuration and troubleshooting simple and easy — no need to edit files or enter modes and sub-modes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Date and Time</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Setting-Date-and-Time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Setting-Date-and-Time/</guid>
      <description>Setting the time zone, date and time requires root privileges; use sudo.
Setting the Time Zone To see the current time zone, list the contents of /etc/timezone:
cumulus@switch:~$ cat /etc/timezone US/Eastern  Edit the file to add your desired time zone. A list of valid time zones can be found at the following link.
Use the following command to apply the new time zone immediately.
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo dpkg-reconfigure --frontend noninteractive tzdata  Alternative: Use the Guided Wizard to Find and Apply a Time Zone To set the time zone, run dpkg-reconfigure tzdata as root:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Application Daemons</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Managing-Application-Daemons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Managing-Application-Daemons/</guid>
      <description>You manage application daemons in Cumulus RMP in the following ways:
 Identifying active listener ports
 Identifying daemons currently active or stopped
 Identifying boot time state of a specific daemon
 Disabling or enabling a specific daemon
  Using systemd and the systemctl Command In general, you manage services using systemd via the systemctl command. You use it with any service on the switch to start/stop/restart/reload/enable/disable/reenable or get the status of the service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring switchd</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Configuring-switchd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Configuring-switchd/</guid>
      <description>switchd is the daemon at the heart of Cumulus RMP. It communicates between the switch and Cumulus RMP, and all the applications running on Cumulus RMP.
The switchd configuration is stored in /etc/cumulus/switchd.conf.
The switchd File System switchd also exports a file system, mounted on /cumulus/switchd, that presents all the switchd configuration options as a series of files arranged in a tree structure. You can see the contents by parsing the switchd tree; run tree /cumulus/switchd.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>