<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cumulus VX Getting Started Guide on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-vx-30/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cumulus VX Getting Started Guide on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-vx-30/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Cumulus VX with KVM</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-vx-30/Using-Cumulus-VX-with-KVM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-vx-30/Using-Cumulus-VX-with-KVM/</guid>
      <description>Once you install the hypervisor and download the qcow2 image, you will clone it a few times to create a two-leaf/two-spine virtual network using QEMU/KVM on a Linux server:
This configuration was tested on a server running Debian 3.2.60-1+deb7u3 x86_64 GNU/Linux with 3.2.0-4-amd64 #1 SMP processors.
 The interfaces are connected as follows:
 leaf1:swp1&amp;mdash;&amp;gt; spine1:swp1
 leaf1:swp2&amp;mdash;&amp;gt;spine2:swp1
 leaf2:swp1&amp;mdash;&amp;gt;spine1:swp2
 leaf2:swp2&amp;mdash;&amp;gt;spine2:swp2
  Copy the qcow2 file you downloaded earlier onto a Linux server four times, and name them as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Cumulus VX with Vagrant</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-vx-30/Using-Cumulus-VX-with-Vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-vx-30/Using-Cumulus-VX-with-Vagrant/</guid>
      <description>Requirements  Cumulus VX requires Vagrant 1.7 or newer
 Understand these VirtualBox considerations
  Setting Up the Vagrant Environment You can use Cumulus VX within a Vagrant environment, running the VMs with VirtualBox. To get started you need to download some software as well as the Cumulus VX Vagrant box. You can download all of the source code used to build Cumulus VX for Vagrant, the vagrant-cumulus plugin and the pre-configured demos from the Cumulus Networks public Github repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Cumulus VX with Other Cumulus Networks Products</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-vx-30/Comparing-Cumulus-VX-with-Other-Cumulus-Networks-Products/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-vx-30/Comparing-Cumulus-VX-with-Other-Cumulus-Networks-Products/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus VX has the same foundation as other Cumulus Networks products; that is, Cumulus Linux and Cumulus RMP. Cumulus VX includes all the control plane elements of Cumulus Linux or Cumulus RMP but does not have an actual ASIC or NPU for line rate performance or hardware acceleration. Essentially, switchd is not a part of Cumulus VX.
Thus, Cumulus VX is not a production-ready virtual switch or virtual router. It isn&amp;rsquo;t meant to run on production switches or carry production data traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring the Network Interfaces and Quagga</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-vx-30/Configuring-the-Network-Interfaces-and-Quagga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-vx-30/Configuring-the-Network-Interfaces-and-Quagga/</guid>
      <description>This section covers configuring the network interfaces and Quagga for a 2 leaf/2 spine topology. The steps below assume that the VMs have been set up. Refer to earlier sections of this guide to set up the VMs.
Configuring leaf1 VM To configure leaf1:
 Log into the VM using the following credentials:
 username: cumulus
 password: CumulusLinux!
  Configure the interfaces:
 Log in as root, using the password CumulusLinux!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>