<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monitoring and Troubleshooting on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_35/Monitoring_and_Troubleshooting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monitoring and Troubleshooting on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_35/Monitoring_and_Troubleshooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Single User Mode - Boot Recovery</title>
      <link>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_35/Monitoring_and_Troubleshooting/Single_User_Mode_-_Boot_Recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_35/Monitoring_and_Troubleshooting/Single_User_Mode_-_Boot_Recovery/</guid>
      <description>Use single user mode to assist in troubleshooting system boot issues or for password recovery. To enter single user mode, follow the steps below.
 Boot the switch, as soon as you see the GRUB menu.
 GNU GRUB version 2.02~beta2-22+deb8u1 +----------------------------------------------------------------------------+ |*Cumulus Linux GNU/Linux | | Advanced options for Cumulus Linux GNU/Linux | | ONIE | | | +----------------------------------------------------------------------------+  Use the ^ and v arrow keys to select Advanced options for Cumulus Linux GNU/Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resource Diagnostics Using cl-resource-query</title>
      <link>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_35/Monitoring_and_Troubleshooting/Resource_Diagnostics_Using_cl-resource-query/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_35/Monitoring_and_Troubleshooting/Resource_Diagnostics_Using_cl-resource-query/</guid>
      <description>You can use cl-resource-query to retrieve information about host entries, MAC entries, L2 and L3 routes, and ECMPs (equal-cost multi-path routes, see Load Balancing) that are in use. This is especially useful because Cumulus Linux syncs routes between the kernel and the switching silicon. If the required resource pools in hardware fill up, new kernel routes can cause existing routes to move from being fully allocated to being partially allocated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Virtual Device Counters</title>
      <link>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_35/Monitoring_and_Troubleshooting/Monitoring_Virtual_Device_Counters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_35/Monitoring_and_Troubleshooting/Monitoring_Virtual_Device_Counters/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus Linux gathers statistics for VXLANs and VLANs using virtual device counters. These counters are supported on Tomahawk, Trident II+ and Trident II-based platforms only; see the Cumulus Networks HCL for a list of supported platforms.
You can retrieve the data from these counters using tools like ip -s link show, ifconfig, /proc/net/dev, or netstat -i.
Sample VXLAN Statistics VXLAN statistics are available as follows:
 Aggregate statistics are available per VNI; this includes access and network statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buffer Monitoring</title>
      <link>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_35/Monitoring_and_Troubleshooting/Buffer_Monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_35/Monitoring_and_Troubleshooting/Buffer_Monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring packet buffers and their utilization is vital for proper traffic management on a network. It is quite useful for:
 Identifying microbursts that result in longer packet latency
 Giving early warning signs of packet buffer congestion that could lead to packet drops
 Quickly identifying a network problem with a particular switch, port or traffic class
  You can use buffer utilization monitoring to quickly filter out non-problematic switches so you can focus on the ones causing trouble on the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Best Practices</title>
      <link>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_35/Monitoring_and_Troubleshooting/Monitoring_Best_Practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_35/Monitoring_and_Troubleshooting/Monitoring_Best_Practices/</guid>
      <description>The following monitoring processes are considered best practices for reviewing and troubleshooting potential issues with Cumulus Linux environments. In addition, several of the more common issues have been listed, with potential solutions included.
Overview This document describes:
 Metrics that you can poll from Cumulus Linux and use in trend analysis
 Critical log messages that you can monitor for triggered alerts
  Trend Analysis Using Metrics A metric is a quantifiable measure that is used to track and assess the status of a specific infrastructure component.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>