<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installation, Upgrading and Package Management on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-31/System-Management/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Installation, Upgrading and Package Management on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-31/System-Management/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Cumulus RMP Disk Images</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-31/System-Management/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Managing-Cumulus-RMP-Disk-Images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-31/System-Management/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Managing-Cumulus-RMP-Disk-Images/</guid>
      <description>The Cumulus RMP operating system resides on a switch as a disk image. This section discusses how to manage them.
Cumulus RMP comes preinstalled on your switch. However there may be instances where you need to perform a full image installation. Before you install Cumulus RMP, the switch can be in two different states:
 The switch already has Cumulus RMP installed on it, so you only need to upgrade it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding and Updating Packages</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-31/System-Management/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Adding-and-Updating-Packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-31/System-Management/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Adding-and-Updating-Packages/</guid>
      <description>You use the Advanced Packaging Tool (APT) to manage additional applications (in the form of packages) and to install the latest updates.
Commands  apt-get
 apt-cache
 dpkg
  Updating the Package Cache To work properly, APT relies on a local cache of the available packages. You must populate the cache initially, and then periodically update it with apt-get update:
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo apt-get update Get:1 http://repo3.cumulusnetworks.com CumulusRMP-3 InRelease [7,624 B] Get:2 http://repo3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero Touch Provisioning</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-31/System-Management/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Zero-Touch-Provisioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-31/System-Management/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Zero-Touch-Provisioning/</guid>
      <description>Zero touch provisioning (ZTP) enables network devices to be quickly deployed in large-scale environments. Data center engineers only need to rack and stack the switch, connect it to the management network, then install Cumulus RMP via ONIE; the initial configuration gets invoked via ZTP. Alternatively, you can insert a USB stick with the configuration so the provisioning process can start automatically.
The provisioning framework allows for a one-time, user-provided script to be executed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>