<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Static VXLAN Configurations on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_36/Network_Virtualization/Static_VXLAN_Configurations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Static VXLAN Configurations on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_36/Network_Virtualization/Static_VXLAN_Configurations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Static VXLAN Tunnels</title>
      <link>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_36/Network_Virtualization/Static_VXLAN_Configurations/Static_VXLAN_Tunnels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_36/Network_Virtualization/Static_VXLAN_Configurations/Static_VXLAN_Tunnels/</guid>
      <description>In VXLAN-based networks, there are a range of complexities and challenges in determining the destination virtual tunnel endpoints (VTEPs) for any given VXLAN. At scale, various solutions, including Lightweight Network Virtualization (LNV), controller-based options like Midokura MidoNet or VMware NSX and even new standards like EVPN are attempts to address these complexities, however do retain their own complexities.
Enter static VXLAN tunnels, which simply serve to connect two VTEPs in a given environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static MAC Bindings with VXLAN</title>
      <link>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_36/Network_Virtualization/Static_VXLAN_Configurations/Static_MAC_Bindings_with_VXLAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/version/Cumulus_Linux_36/Network_Virtualization/Static_VXLAN_Configurations/Static_MAC_Bindings_with_VXLAN/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus Linux includes native Linux VXLAN kernel support.
Requirements A VXLAN configuration requires a Broadcom switch with the Tomahawk, Trident II+, or Trident II ASIC running Cumulus Linux 2.0 or later, or a Mellanox switch with the Spectrum ASIC running Cumulus Linux 3.2.0 or later.
For a basic VXLAN configuration, make sure that:
 The VXLAN has a network identifier (VNI); do not use 0 or 16777215 as the VNI ID, which are reserved values under Cumulus Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>