<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installation, Upgrading and Package Management on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Installation, Upgrading and Package Management on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Cumulus RMP Disk Images</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Managing-Cumulus-RMP-Disk-Images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Managing-Cumulus-RMP-Disk-Images/</guid>
      <description>The Cumulus RMP operating system resides on a switch as a disk image. This section discusses how to manage them.
Cumulus RMP comes preinstalled on your switch. However there may be instances where you need to perform a full image installation. Before you install Cumulus RMP, the switch can be in two different states:
 The switch already has Cumulus RMP installed on it, so you only need to upgrade it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Snapshots</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Using-Snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Using-Snapshots/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus RMP supports the ability to take snapshots of the complete file system as well as the ability to roll back to a previous snapshot. Snapshots are performed automatically right before and after you upgrade Cumulus RMP and right before and after you commit a switch configuration using NCLU. In addition, you can take a snapshot at any time. You can roll back the entire file system to a specific snapshot or just retrieve specific files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding and Updating Packages</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Adding-and-Updating-Packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Adding-and-Updating-Packages/</guid>
      <description>You use the Advanced Packaging Tool (apt) to manage additional applications (in the form of packages) and to install the latest updates.
Before running any apt-get commands or after changing the /etc/apt/sources.list file, you need to run apt-get update.
Updating the Package Cache To work properly, APT relies on a local cache of the available packages. You must populate the cache initially, and then periodically update it with apt-get update:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero Touch Provisioning</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Zero-Touch-Provisioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-rmp-321/System-Configuration/Installation-Upgrading-and-Package-Management/Zero-Touch-Provisioning/</guid>
      <description>Zero touch provisioning (ZTP) enables network devices to be quickly deployed in large-scale environments. On first boot, Cumulus RMP invokes ZTP, which executes the provisioning automation used to deploy the device for its intended role in the network.
The provisioning framework allows for a one-time, user-provided script to be executed. You can develop this script using a variety of automation tools and scripting languages, providing ample flexibility for you to design the provisioning scheme to meet your needs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>