<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monitor the Network on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>http://example.org/Cumulus_NetQ/Cumulus_NetQ_UI_User_Guide/Monitor_the_Network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monitor the Network on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/Cumulus_NetQ/Cumulus_NetQ_UI_User_Guide/Monitor_the_Network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Network Health</title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus_NetQ/Cumulus_NetQ_UI_User_Guide/Monitor_the_Network/Monitor_Network_Health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus_NetQ/Cumulus_NetQ_UI_User_Guide/Monitor_the_Network/Monitor_Network_Health/</guid>
      <description>As with any network, one of the challenges is keeping track of all of the moving parts. With the NetQ GUI, you can view the overall health of your network at a glance and then delve deeper for periodic checks or as conditions arise that require attention. For a general understanding of how well your network is operating, the Network Health card workflow is the best place to start as it contains the highest view and performance rollups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validate Network Protocol and Service Operations</title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus_NetQ/Cumulus_NetQ_UI_User_Guide/Monitor_the_Network/Validate_Network_Protocol_and_Service_Operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus_NetQ/Cumulus_NetQ_UI_User_Guide/Monitor_the_Network/Validate_Network_Protocol_and_Service_Operations/</guid>
      <description>With the NetQ UI, you can validate the operation of the network protocols and services running in your network either on demand or on a scheduled basis. There are three card workflows to perform this validation: one for creating the validation request (either on-demand or scheduled) and two validation results (one for on-demand and one for scheduled).
This release supports validation of the following network protocols and services: Agents, BGP, CLAG, EVPN, Interfaces, License, and NTP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Network Inventory</title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus_NetQ/Cumulus_NetQ_UI_User_Guide/Monitor_the_Network/Monitor_Network_Inventory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus_NetQ/Cumulus_NetQ_UI_User_Guide/Monitor_the_Network/Monitor_Network_Inventory/</guid>
      <description>With NetQ, a network administrator can monitor both the switch hardware and its operating system for misconfigurations or misbehaving services. The Devices Inventory card workflow provides a view into the switches and hosts installed in your network and their various hardware and software components. The workflow contains a small card with a count of each device type in your network, a medium card displaying the operating systems running on each set of devices, large cards with component information statistics, and full-screen cards displaying tables with attributes of all switches and all hosts in your network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Events</title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus_NetQ/Cumulus_NetQ_UI_User_Guide/Monitor_the_Network/Monitor_Events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus_NetQ/Cumulus_NetQ_UI_User_Guide/Monitor_the_Network/Monitor_Events/</guid>
      <description>Two event workflows, the Alarms card workflow and the Info card workflow, provide a view into the events occurring in the network. The Alarms card workflow tracks critical severity events, whereas the Info card workflow tracks all warning, info, and debug severity events.
To focus on events from a single device perspective, refer to Monitor Switches .
Monitor Alarms You can easily monitor critical events occurring across your network using the Alarms card.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitor Network Connectivity</title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus_NetQ/Cumulus_NetQ_UI_User_Guide/Monitor_the_Network/Monitor_Network_Connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus_NetQ/Cumulus_NetQ_UI_User_Guide/Monitor_the_Network/Monitor_Network_Connectivity/</guid>
      <description>It is helpful to verify that communications are freely flowing between the various devices in your network. You can verify the connectivity between two devices currently or for a time in the past. You can also view connectivity in both an adhoc fashion and specifically define connectivity checks to occur on a scheduled basis. There are three card workflows which enable you to view connectivity, the Trace Request, On-demand Trace Results, and Scheduled Trace Results.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>