<tables>
<table name="Open Issues in 4.0.0">
<tr>
<th> Issue ID </th>
<th> Description </th>
<th> Affects </th>
<th> Fixed </th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2711101</td>
<td>When RoCE (RDMA over Converged Ethernet) data collection is enabled in Cumulus Linux 4.3.z and 4.4.z, you can experience high dual uplink convergence times.
To work around this issue, disable RoCE monitoring:

1. Edit &apos;/etc/netq/commands/cl4-netq-commands.yml&apos; and comment out the following lines:
        #- period: "60"
        #  key: "roce"
        #  isactive: true
        #  command: "/usr/lib/cumulus/mlxcmd --json roce counters"
        #  parser: "local"

2. Delete the &apos;/var/run/netq/netq_commands.yml&apos; file:
        $ sudo rm /var/run/netq/netq_commands.yml

3. Restart the NetQ agent:
       $ netq config agent restart</td>
<td>4.0.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2690469</td>
<td>While upgrading an on-premises deployment from version 2.4.x to 3.x.y then to 4.x, the upgrade fails during the NetQ application stage.
To work around this issue, run the following command on the NetQ telemetry server, then start the upgrade again:
&apos;netq install opta activate-job config-key EhVuZXRxLWVuZHBvaW50LWdhdGV3YXkYsagDIiw3T2sweW9kR3Y4Wk9sTHU3MkwrQTRjNkhhQkU3bVpBNVlZVjEvWWgyZGJBPQ==&apos;</td>
<td>3.2.1-3.3.1, 4.0.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2663534</td>
<td>Validation check filtering is only applied to errors in validation results and is not applied to warnings in validation results.</td>
<td>4.0.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2663274</td>
<td>You cannot set a validation filter for sensor validations.</td>
<td>4.0.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2661988</td>
<td>Rerunning a validation in the UI or the CLI can return the same error if the query includes special characters, such as **+** or **:**.</td>
<td>4.0.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555854</td>
<td>NetQ Agent: If a NetQ Agent is downgraded to the 3.0.0 version from any higher release, the default commands file present in the _/etc/netq/commands/_ also needs to be updated to prevent the NetQ Agent from becoming rotten.</td>
<td>3.0.0-3.3.1, 4.0.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555197</td>
<td>NetQ CLI: Occasionally, when a command response contains a large number of objects to be displayed the NetQ CLI does not display all results in the console. When this occurs, view all results using the {{json}} format option.</td>
<td>3.3.0-3.3.1, 4.0.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2549649</td>
<td>NetQ UI: Warnings might appear during the post-upgrade phase for a Cumulus Linux switch upgrade job. They are caused by services that have not yet been restored by the time the job is complete. Cumulus Networks recommend waiting five minutes, creating a network snapshot, then comparing that to the pre-upgrade snapshot. If the comparison shows no differences for the services, the warnings can be ignored. If there are differences, then troubleshooting the relevant service(s) is recommended.</td>
<td>3.0.0-3.3.1, 4.0.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</table>
<table name="Fixed Issues in 4.0.0">
<tr>
<th> Issue ID </th>
<th> Description </th>
<th> Affects </th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2611898</td>
<td>Fixed an issue where deleting a snapshot does not remove the snapshot card from the workbench. However, the workbench might refresh before the deleted snapshot’s card is removed. During the refresh, you may notice a brief flashing. This is expected behavior and you can safely ignore the flashing.</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553453</td>
<td>The {{netqd}} daemon logs a traceback to _/var/log/netqd.log_ when the OPTA server is unreachable and {{netq show}} commands are run.</td>
<td>3.1.0-3.3.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2549319</td>
<td>NetQ UI: The legend and segment colors on Switches and Upgrade History card graphs sometimes do not match. These cards appear on the lifecycle management dashboard (Manage Switch Assets view). Hover over graph to view the correct values.</td>
<td>3.0.0-3.3.1</td>
</tr>
</table>
</tables>