<tables>
<table name="Open Issues in 5.10.0">
<tr>
<th> Issue ID </th>
<th> Description </th>
<th> Affects </th>
<th> Fixed </th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4043575</td>
<td>If a ZTP script includes a directive to reboot, the reboot might stop the running ZTP process before it is able to disable itself from running again. As a result, the ZTP process starts again when the system comes back up. To work around this issue, run {{shutdown -r +1}} to schedule a reboot after one minute so that the ZTP process can successfully complete disabling the {{ztp.service}} systemd service.</td>
<td>5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4037462</td>
<td>The Open telemetry interface statistic description for {{nvswitch_histogram_interface_egress_buffer}} has a typographical error; engress should be egress.</td>
<td>5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4037224</td>
<td>ASIC monitoring histogram collection might not work because of a crash in the {{asic-monitor}} service. To work around this issue, see the &lt;a href="https://docs.nvidia.com/networking-ethernet-software/cumulus-linux-510/Whats-New/#release-considerations"&gt;Release Considerations section of the What’s New&lt;/a&gt;.</td>
<td>5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4035681</td>
<td>The {{nv show interface &lt;interface&gt;}} commands show RX and TX Power values from the wrong lanes on breakout ports.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4023318</td>
<td>If you run {{nv set}} commands after you perform an upgrade but before a reboot, NVUE creates a revision based off the pre-upgrade version. After reboot, the revision contains pre-upgrade data that might cause it to fail during {{config apply}}.  To work around this issue, detach the stale revision after upgrade with the {{nv config detach}} command.</td>
<td>5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4007612</td>
<td>If you have SVIs with the same VLANs across more than one bridge, Cumulus Linux installs the router MAC for the first bridge only in the SDK. This can cause reachability issues within that VRF towards this switch from remote VTEPs. To work around this issue, bounce the second bridge with the {{sudo ifdown &lt;bridge&gt;}} and {{sudo ifup &lt;bridge&gt;}} commands. If you reboot the switch, you need to bounce the second bridge again.</td>
<td>5.9.1-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4007590</td>
<td>When you upgrade Cumulus Linux 5.9.1 to Cumulus Linux 5.10 with package upgrade, the NTP service stops. To restart the NTP service, enable, then restart the service in the VRF in which it was running with the {{systemctl enable ntpsec@&lt;vrf&gt;}} and {{systemctl restart ntpsec@&lt;vrf&gt;}} commands.</td>
<td>5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4005422</td>
<td>When you upgrade Cumulus Linux 5.9.1 to Cumulus Linux 5.10 with package upgrade, the NTP service stops. To restart the NTP service, enable, then restart the service in the VRF in which it was running with the {{systemctl enable ntpsec@&lt;vrf&gt;}} and {{systemctl restart ntpsec@&lt;vrf&gt;}} commands.</td>
<td>5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4004898</td>
<td>When you configure the SNMP server listening address to a VRF that has no interfaces, {{snmp.service}} fails.To recover from the failure, set the SNMP server listening address back to the VRF that has interfaces. If you really want to move the SNMP server to the VRF with no interfaces, assign an interface to the VRF and move the SNMP server to the VRF.</td>
<td>5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3990135</td>
<td>If there are multiple relay switches in the path reaching the DHCP server, DHCP packets are duplicated at each transit relay switch and the server receives duplicate packets.</td>
<td>5.9.1-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3879717</td>
<td>Running {{snmpwalk}} on the switch with the management IP address does not work. To work around this issue, use the localhost option ({{snmpwalk -v 2c -c public28 localhost 1.3.6.1.2.1.14}}) or create a control plane ACL whitelist rule.</td>
<td>5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3878394</td>
<td>When ZTP runs a script that contains {{wget}}, ZTP fails and you see a message similar to the following:
ZTP: ZTP DHCP: Unexpected error: 'ascii' codec can't decode byte 0xe2 in position 181: ordinal not in range(128)
ZTP: Script returned failure 
To work around this issue, use the {{-q}} option with {{wget}}.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3875696</td>
<td>The default TX State for 1G Base-X optical modules that are unconfigured or admin down in Cumulus Linux 5.7.0 and later is OFF.  However, on the first boot after upgrade from an earlier release, a module TX power might be ON or OFF depending on the TX State it was before the upgrade. The TX_Disable line is not properly set on first boot. To work around this issue, reboot the switch again, or {{ifup}} or {{ifdown}} the 1G Base-X interface to disable TX Power.</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3861745</td>
<td>On UEFI hardware (where the {{/sys/firmware/efi}} directory exists), using the update-grub program might generate a {{/boot/grub/grub.cfg}} that is incorrect for booting ONIE if the ONIE option is selected on the console while booting. To work around this issue, run {{mount LABEL="EFI System" /boot/efi}} before using update-grub.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3844670</td>
<td>When you configure TACACS with NVUE or merge in an NVUE configuration file including TACACS configuration with the {{nv config patch}} command, you see an unrecoverable error when running additional NVUE commands. To work around this issue, restart the NVUE service with the {{systemctl restart nvued.service}} command.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3773177</td>
<td>When you try to upgrade a switch from Cumulus Linux 5.5 or earlier to 5.8.0 or later with package upgrade, you see errors for expired GPG keys that prevent you from upgrading. To work around this issue, install the new keys with the following commands, then upgrade the switch.

cumulus@switch:~$ wget https://download.nvidia.com/cumulus/apt.cumulusnetworks.com/repo/pool/cumulus/c/cumulus-archive-keyring/cumulus-archive-keyring_4-cl5.6.0u5_all.deb
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo apt install ./cumulus-archive-keyring_4-cl5.6.0u5_all.deb
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo apt update
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo apt upgrade
</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3771168</td>
<td>When you perform an ISSU upgrade on a Spectrum 1 switch, the {{switchd}} service might crash.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3739159</td>
<td>Disabling adaptive routing globally or on interfaces and performing ISSU, has a significant traffic outage. The issue recovers after ISSU completes.</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3685007</td>
<td>Cumulus Linux does not support 802.1X dynamic VLANs on PEAP with MS Windows-based supplicants.</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3677533</td>
<td>Due to resource constraints on the Spectrum 1 switch, {{staticd}} performance drops and  takes longer to read static routes compared to the time BGP takes to complete a graceful restart, and advertise routes and EOR to its helpers. As a result, static routes are advertised after the EOR is sent to graceful restart helpers, which delete the stale static routes and relearn them after receiving the EOR from the restarting node. Temporary traffic loss might occur.</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3637444</td>
<td>Applying an inbound control plane ACL on the eth0 management interface does not take effect. To work around this issue, apply the ACL on the {{mgmt}} interface; for example, {{nv set interface mgmt acl &lt;acl-id&gt; inbound control-plane}}.</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3587393</td>
<td>If you use the NVIDIA SN5600 (Spectrum-4) switch with Ixia test equipment, you might experience delayed link up due to intermittent link flaps. 
To work around this issue when using copper cables:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use Ixia IxOS version 9.37 with HF002156, or version 9.39 or later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the DAC cable on ports 10 through 50.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use NVIDIA cables with the recommended firmware revision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configure AN on the Cumulus Linux switch and AN/LT on Ixia.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
To work around this issue when using fiber cables:
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Configure 800g/Force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the recommended NVIDIA optical adapters.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3556762</td>
<td>On rare occasions, SPT switchover might not happen cleanly in PIM resulting in some dropped packets. If you use PIM-SM to replicate EVPN BUM traffic, you might see a brief drop of multicast traffic before recovering due to normal PIM-SM traffic timeout.</td>
<td>5.5.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3538321</td>
<td>In rare cases, an STP topology change on PTP over a VLAN can result in the switch losing the slave state and one of the ports might remain in an uncalibrated state. To work around this issue, toggle the port that is in the uncalibrated state up and down so that one of the ports is selected as the slave.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3452681</td>
<td>When you run the NVUE {{nv show system aaa tacacs authorization}} commands to show per command authorization for a specific TACACS+ user privilege level, you see an error message similar to {{Error: GET /nvue_v1/system/aaa/tacacs/authorization/1?rev=operational responded with 404 NOT FOUND}}.</td>
<td>5.5.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3442569</td>
<td>When trying to access the NVUE API, user accounts authenticated with a newly-configured external service, such as TACACS, RADIUS, or LDAP, receive a 401 forbidden error. To work around this issue, after enabling a new authentication service, make sure to restart both {{nginx.service}} and {{nvued.service}} to begin authenticating users against the new authentication service.</td>
<td>5.5.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3424967</td>
<td>{{sudo}} for TACACS+ users with privilege level 15 does not work when reaching the TACACS+ server through the {{default}} VRF. To work around this issue, specify the interface name that the {{default}} VRF uses in the {{vrf=}} setting of the {{/etc/tacplus_servers}} file or run the NVUE {{nv set system aaa tacacs vrf}} command. If you don't run either command, a TACACS+ user with privilege level 15 can run {{vrf task exec default sudo ...}} to execute the {{sudo}} command.</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3420056</td>
<td>
The ADVA 5401 SFP module with hardware revision 5.01 does not come up at layer 1 when you use 10G QSA adaptors. To work around this issue, use 25G QSA adaptors.</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3368217</td>
<td>When daylight saving time changes, the MLAG {{initDelay}} timer resets and all MLAG bonds go down.</td>
<td>4.4.4-4.4.5, 5.2.1-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3362113</td>
<td>If you restore an NVUE {{startup.yaml}} file or run the {{nv config patch}} command after an upgrade that includes breakout ports with QoS configuration, the NVUE configuration fails to apply. Subsequent attempts to run {{nv config apply}} fail with a message similar to {{Invalid config [rev_id: 11] qos config is not supported on the following invalid interface: swp1s0. Supported on swp and bond interface types}}. To work around this issue, run {{nv unset}} on the configured QoS settings, then apply the breakout port configuration before you configure QoS. Alternatively, you can remove the QoS configuration from the {{yaml}} file and patch it separately after applying the breakout configuration.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3347538</td>
<td>When connecting NVIDIA-to-NVIDIA in PAM4, you must enable auto-negotiation.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3341214</td>
<td>If you use the NVUE REST API to configure a local user with a hashed password, the user cannot log in and the {{/etc/nvue.d/startup.yaml}} file shows the password as plain text.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3329518</td>
<td>When using TACACS+, if the {{/etc/nsswitch.conf}} file specifies {{passwd: files tacplus}} (files is listed before tacplus), a user that is present in both the local {{/etc/passwd}} file and the TACACS+ server cannot log into the switch. NVIDIA recommends that when using TACACS+, you list {{tacplus}} before {{files}} in {{/etc/nsswitch.conf}}.  When using NVUE, ensure that {{tacacs}} has priority over {{local}}.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3327477</td>
<td>If you use {{su}} to change to a user specified through TACACS+, the user becomes the local tacacs0 thru tacacs15 user instead of the named user to run {{sudo}} commands. As a result, the named user password might not match the local tacacs0 thru tacacs15 user password.</td>
<td>3.7.0-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3326659</td>
<td>If you have a large number of MAC addresses, they do not age out at the MAC ageing timeout value configured on the switch. It might take up to 30 seconds more for the MAC addresses to age out and be deleted from the hardware. To work around this issue, wait for the ageing timeout value plus 30 seconds.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3241567</td>
<td>When you apply switch configuration for the first time on a freshly booted switch and you run the {{nv config apply}} command after setting the hostname with {{nv set system hostname}}, you might see the error message {{Failed to start Hostname Service}}. To work around this issue, run the {{nv config apply}} command a second time.</td>
<td>5.3.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3226506</td>
<td>The {{l1-show eth0}} command does not show port information and is not supported in this release. </td>
<td>5.3.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3172504</td>
<td>When you connect the NVIDIA SN4600C switch to a Spectrum 1 or Spectrum-3 switch with a 40GbE passive copper cable (Part Number: MC2210126-005) on edge ports 1-4 and 61-64, there is an Effective BER of 1E-12 in PHY.</td>
<td>5.2.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3147782</td>
<td>You cannot use NVUE to configure an SNMP view to include a subtree beginning with a period. For example:

cumulus@switch:~$ nv set service snmp-server viewname cumulusOnly included .1.3.6.1.4.1.40310
Error: GET /nvue_v1/service/snmp-server/viewname/cumulusOnly/included?pointers=%5B%22%2Fparameters%22%2C+%22%2Fpatch%2FrequestBody%2Fcontent%2Fapplication~1json%2Fschema%22%2C+%22%2Fpatch%2Fparameters%22%2C+%22%2Fpatch%2Fresponses%2F200%2Flinks%22%5D responded with 404 NOT FOUND

To work around this issue, reference the OID without the preceding period ( {{.}} ) in the command.</td>
<td>5.3.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3145869</td>
<td>On a Spectrum-3 switch, the PTP offset in 10GbE changes between +-27. The average offset is around 7.</td>
<td>5.2.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3135952</td>
<td>PAM4 split cables (such as 2x100G, 4x100G, and 4x50G) do not work with a forced speed setting (when auto-negotiation is off) as the default speed enabled is for NRZ mode (such as 100G_4X). To work around this issue,  set the appropriate lanes for forced speed (with auto-negotation off) with the {{ethtool -s swpX speed &lt;port_speed&gt; autoneg off lanes &lt;no_of_lanes&gt;}} command. For example: 

cumulus@switch:~$ sudo ethtool -s swp1 speed 100000 autoneg off lanes 2
</td>
<td>5.2.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3122301</td>
<td>On the NVIDIA SN4700 switch, inserting and removing the PSU might cause loss of frames.</td>
<td>5.2.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3115242</td>
<td>When you configure two VNIs in the same VLAN, ifupdown2  shows a {{vlan added to two or more VXLANS}} warning, which is only issued after the VNI is already added to the bridge. This leaves the new VNI in the PVID even if there is already an existing VNI configured in that PVID.</td>
<td>5.1.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3103821</td>
<td>On the NVIDIA SN4700 switch, inserting and removing the PSU might cause loss of frames.</td>
<td>5.2.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3084476</td>
<td> After you disable traffic shaping in the {{/etc/cumulus/datapath/qos/qos_features.conf}} file, the default QOS traffic shaping configuration does not restore. To work around this issue, restart {{switchd}}.</td>
<td>4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td>4.4.4-4.4.5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3084027</td>
<td>Under a high load, you might see ingress drop counters increase. The drops are classified as {{HwIfInDiscards}} in ethtool and shown as {{ingress_general}} in hardware.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3071652</td>
<td>On rare occasions, after you reboot or restart {{switchd}} on a Spectrum 1 switch, any 25G connections with Direct Attach Copper (DAC) cables that connect from the switch to a non-NVIDIA device might flap continuously. To work around this issue, bring the affected link administratively down for a few seconds on the non-NVIDIA device, then bring the link back up.</td>
<td>4.4.4-4.4.5, 5.1.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3061656</td>
<td>When the CPU load is high during a warm boot, bonds with a slow LACP rate fail to forward layer 2 traffic for up to 60 seconds (depending on the duration of the CPU load) and static bonds fail to forward layer 2 traffic for up to 5 seconds.</td>
<td>5.1.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3053094</td>
<td>When the CPU load is high during a warm boot, bonds with a slow LACP rate fail to forward layer 2 traffic for up to 60 seconds (depending on the duration of the CPU load) and static bonds fail to forward layer 2 traffic for up to 5 seconds.</td>
<td>5.1.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2972540</td>
<td>With RADIUS enabled for user shell authentication, there might be a delay in local user authentication for non cumulus user accounts.</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2964279</td>
<td>When a VNI flaps, an incorrect list of layer 2 VNIs are associated with a layer 3 VNI. The NCLU {{net show evpn vni detail}} command output shows duplicate layer 2 VNIs under a layer 3 VNI. </td>
<td>3.7.15, 4.4.2-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td>3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2951110</td>
<td>The {{net show time ntp servers}} command does not show any output with the management VRF.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.1.1-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2904450</td>
<td>When you run the {{ethtool -m}} or the {{l1-show}} command, the 400G interface optical values do not show. 

</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2891255</td>
<td>CVE-2021-39925: Buffer overflow in the Bluetooth SDP dissector in Wireshark 3.4.0 to 3.4.9 and 3.2.0 to 3.2.17 allows denial of service via packet injection or crafted capture file.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.6.20-0+deb10u1
Fixed: 2.6.20-0+deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1, 5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2890681</td>
<td>CVE-2021-42771: relative path traversal in Babel, a set of tools for internationalising Python applications, could result in the execution of arbitrary code.
Vulnerable: 2.6.0+dfsg.1-1
Fixed: 2.6.0+dfsg.1-1+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1, 5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2867042</td>
<td>When connecting the NVIDIA SN4600 switch to another NVIDIA Spectrum switch, you must use auto-negotiation mode (not force mode); otherwise the switch might use the wrong Tx configuration.</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2847755</td>
<td>When you use NCLU to remove the configuration for a peer that is a member of a group but also has other peer-specific configuration, you must remove the peer-specific configuration before you delete the peer in a separate NCLU commit.</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2823307</td>
<td>Cumuls Linux does not support a bond with more than 64 ports.  Any configuration with more than 64 ports in a bond changes all ports to down when you apply the configuration. </td>
<td>5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2736108</td>
<td>When you change the VRRP advertisement interval on the master, the {{master advertisement interval}} field in the {{show vrrp}} command output does not show the updated value.</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2684925</td>
<td>The NVUE {{nv show vrf default router bgp peer}} command produces a 404 not found error.</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.0.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2671652</td>
<td>In VXLAN routing environments, you might experience sub-optimal route convergence delays (longer than five seconds) when a prefix transitions to a new ECMP next-hop group. This condition might occur when a VTEP loses ECMP routes through all uplink peerings, then installs the routes through a different path, such as an MLAG peerlink.</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.5, 5.5.0-5.10.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</table>
<table name="Fixed Issues in 5.10.0">
<tr>
<th> Issue ID </th>
<th> Description </th>
<th> Affects </th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4023637</td>
<td>When you disable dynamic NAT manually in the {{/etc/cumulus/switchd.conf}} file instead of using NVUE commands but the dynamic NAT rules still exist in the {{/etc/cumulus/acl/policy,d/.rules}} file, the switch encounters a memory leak. To work around this issue, remove dynamic NAT rules in rules files in {{/etc/cumulus/acl/policy.d}} before you disable dynamic NAT in the {{/etc/cumulus/switchd.conf}} file.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4015327</td>
<td>If you change the hostname in the {{/etc/hostname}} file after the {{asic_monitor@vrf}} service starts, the hostname  is not reflected in the Open Telemetry  exported resource attribute. To work around this issue, restart the {{asic_monitor@vrf}} service.</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4012011</td>
<td>A memory corruption kernel crash might occur due to a {{netfilter}} error. The log message from {{netfilter}} might contain a warning similar to the following:kernel: WARNING: CPU: 1 PID: 0 at net/netfilter/nf_conntrack_core.c:1210 __nf_conntrack_confirm+0x5c7/0x6b0 [nf_conntrack]
kernel: RIP: 0010:__nf_conntrack_confirm+0x5c7/0x6b0 [nf_conntrack]</td>
<td>5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4004453</td>
<td>The NVUE commands to delete SNMP users, and change authentication passwords and encryption passphrases are not successful.</td>
<td>4.3.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3990258</td>
<td>Cumulus Linux incorrectly handles unnumbered neighbor types, which causes discrepancies in the running configuration and session flaps during FRR reload.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3985600</td>
<td>NTP initialization issues prevent the NTP service from starting on a non-default VRF.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3982222</td>
<td>When SPAN is enabled on a bridge member, an ARP or Gratuitous ARP received during a failover event between locally attached redundant devices such as load balancers might fail to update the bridge MAC table to point to the interface with the newly active load balancer.</td>
<td>5.4.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3974890</td>
<td>The {{ntpsec@mgmt}} service does not come up by default when you install an image with ONIE because the trigger to bring up the service is missing.</td>
<td>5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3972715</td>
<td>The fans on the NVIDIA SN2410 switch (Part Number SSG7A80800) might spin at high speed. </td>
<td>5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3970626</td>
<td>When you configure the {{bridge.kernel_mac_refresh_interval}} parameter in the {{switchd.conf}} file, a {{switchd}} restart fails with a core dump.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3966673</td>
<td>In an EVPN multihoming deployment, if you enable multihoming without any local ESI configuration, {{arp-nd-redirect}} remains disabled unless you restart FRR.</td>
<td>5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3965021</td>
<td>The optical DOM information in {{ethtool -m}} command output is incorrect for SFP modules.</td>
<td>5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3957691</td>
<td>After a networking restart, ERSPAN mirror sessions might not start. To work around this issue, run the {{systemctl reload switchd}} command to start the ERSPAN mirror sessions.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3957620</td>
<td> On a Spectrum-4 switch, if you use PTP on a 800G link, jumbo frames traversing the same link might cause a degradation in PTP performance.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3956091</td>
<td>When you modify the default QoS configuration on top of the base RoCE configuration, NVUE reports an {{Invalid}} exception in the {{nv show qos roce}} command output even when the configuration is valid.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3955615</td>
<td>Cumulus Linux does not recognize QSFP_CMIS optical modules correctly.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3954026</td>
<td>Static ARP configured with NVUE commands is deleted when the relevant layer 3 interface flaps.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3951643</td>
<td>The NVUE unset and set command for the same object in a patch file {{nv config patch &lt;file&gt;.yaml}} causes a python exception.</td>
<td>5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3950322</td>
<td>After {{switchd}} restarts,  the sFlow sampling rate set in the hardware might not match with the configured values for about 3 minutes. This issue occurs because interfaces are not yet up during  the initial sampling rate setting.</td>
<td>5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3949367</td>
<td>If you use NVUE to create an SNMP user with a password, then delete and recreate the user with additional encryption passwords (such as DES or AES), SNMP authorization fails for that user.</td>
<td>5.3.1-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3947432</td>
<td>In an EVPN multihoming configuration, if a host bond enters the protodown state due to a link flap, when you try to clear the protodown state, FRR reprograms it.</td>
<td>5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3943834</td>
<td>The default memory configuration for NVIDIA Cumulus VX OVA is too low and needs to be increased.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3941608</td>
<td>The default NIC for the VMWare OVA file is set to vmxnet3 instead of e1000.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3939667</td>
<td>The password on NVIDIA Cumulus VX is not getting reset to the default value of {{cumulus}}.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3935658</td>
<td>SNMP IF-MIB reports all interfaces (including layer 3 and VNIs) as {{ifType=6}} (ethernetCsmacd) instead of IANA MIB-II types. </td>
<td>5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3929440</td>
<td>When you enable or disable MLAG configuration on an interface, Cumulus Linux logs LACP partner MAC address and BPDU guard mismatches incorrectly. This issue does not impact functionality.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3927016</td>
<td>Following an EVPN extended mobility event, where a host with IPA and MACA moves within the fabric and now resides at IPA MACB, you might see traffic destined to this host experience drops as the flow is being software forwarded on the egress VTEP.</td>
<td>5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3926523</td>
<td>When there are multiple interface flaps with sFlow on 100G interfaces, sFlow might use a different value than the one configured.</td>
<td>5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3925259</td>
<td>When you start Cumulus VX in Vagrant with libvirt, VM provisioning might fail with errors that indicate a missing {{ifup@eth0.service}} systemd service.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3917601</td>
<td>If a packet containing an all zero source MAC address (00:00:00:00:00:00) is learned on the ASIC, {{switchd}} sends the learn notification to the kernel but the kernel rejects the MAC address as invalid. The ASIC continuously sends the mac-learn notifications, which wastes CPU resources. To work around this issue, configure ACLs to match on the all-zero source MAC address and drop the invalid packets.</td>
<td>5.5.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3917528</td>
<td>With LACP bypass enabled, Cumulus Linux does not program the MAC address in the bridge FDB for VLAN unaware tagged ports.  With EVPN, the address is not advertised and the remote side might flood the packet instead of unicast.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3915842</td>
<td>A kernel crash due to memory corruption might occur due to a {{netfilter}} error. The log message from {{netfilter}} might contain a warning similar to the following:kernel: WARNING: CPU: 1 PID: 0 at net/netfilter/nf_conntrack_core.c:1210 __nf_conntrack_confirm+0x5c7/0x6b0 [nf_conntrack]
kernel: RIP: 0010:__nf_conntrack_confirm+0x5c7/0x6b0 [nf_conntrack]</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3904516</td>
<td>With Optimized Multicast Flooding (OMF), when you unset multiple multicast router ports in a single commit, multicast traffic still floods one of the ports. To work around this issue, unset multicast router ports one by one instead of in a single commit.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3896967</td>
<td>PTP does not come up with IPv6 over a trunk port because the IPv6 VLAN tag is not sent. PTP over an IPv4 trunk works fine.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3895042</td>
<td>After an NMS station does a full SNMP walk on the switch, you see the following message every 5 minutes:
  snmp : command not allowed ; TTY=unknown ; PWD=/ ; USER=root ; COMMAND=/usr/cumulus/bin/poectl -j -a 
This issue occurs because {{poectl}} is called on non-PoE switches. To work around this issue, remove or comment out the {{poetcl}} call from the {{/etc/snmpd.conf}} file, then restart the {{snmpd}} process with the {{sudo systemctl snmpd restart}} command.
  #snmp ALL = NOPASSWD: /usr/cumulus/bin/poectl -j -a </td>
<td>4.4.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3895017</td>
<td>When ARP suppression is off, remote EVPN VTEPs duplicate ARP packets from local hosts and each remote host receives two copies of the ARP packets. The issue also applies to IPv6 ND packets.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3890993</td>
<td>On the NVIDIA spectrum-4 switch, {{l1-show}} command output does not show Eye opening information for an interface port.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3881789</td>
<td>If you configure the anycast IP address with the {{nv set nve vxlan mlag shared-address &lt;anycast-address&gt;}} command after you configure MLAG, the anycast IP address configuration is not applied and the VXLAN interface is in a protodown state.  To work around this issue, run {{sudo ifreload -a}}. To avoid this issue, either apply the anycast configuration before you apply the MLAG configuration or configure the anycast IP address and MLAG together with a single  {{nv config apply}} command.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3879635</td>
<td>ERSPAN port-mirror sessions might not come up after a {{switchd}} service restart. To work around this issue and bring up the ERSPAN session, either run {{switchd reload}} after a {{switchd restart}} or use an ACL-based ERSPAN session.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3878166</td>
<td>The NVUE {{nv show interface eth0}} and {{nv show vrf}} commands take more than two minutes to run if you have configured hundreds of interfaces because NVUE makes repetitive system calls to get {{vlan/link/tunnel}} bridge information.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3875589</td>
<td>MLAG bonds might report an incorrect DOWN reason of {{lacp partner mac mismatch}} when the bond is out of service for another reason.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3873219</td>
<td>When you remove a port from a bond and add it to the bridge in a single set of NVUE commands, then apply the configuration, the port forwarding state is blocked on all the bridge VLANs. To work around this issue, apply the configuration in two steps. First remove the port from the bond and apply the configuration, then add the port to the bridge and apply the configuration. </td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3854807</td>
<td>When you enable Optimized Multicast Flooding (OMF) and change VLAN configuration, a few ports might carry multicast traffic even when they are not in the MDB or they are not router ports.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3854800</td>
<td>The switch forwards multicast traffic to the CPU when PIM is enabled globally, regardless of the interface configuration.</td>
<td>5.6.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3851499</td>
<td>On the Spectrum A1 switch, when you enable the {{ip-acl-heavy}} TCAM profile, VXLAN tunnel initialization might fail.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3821643</td>
<td>When using SSM and the upstream interface goes away (the source stops sending or the link goes down) the PIMREG interface is added to the outgoing interface list of the S,G and is never removed. As a result, multicast traffic that hits the impacted S,G is forwarded to the CPU and dropped by the switch.</td>
<td>5.9.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3775686</td>
<td>The BGP Suppress Route Advertisement feature under scale (more than 30000 routes) advertises partial updates to downstream neighbors. Because FRR does not read kernel route updates fast enough, the netlink socket receive buffer gets full and further update notifications are dropped.</td>
<td>5.8.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3763543</td>
<td>The NVIDIA SN4600C switch fails to boot fully after  you upgrade from Cumulus Linux 4.2.1 to 5.7 with ONIE install. To work around this issue, perform an intermediate step image upgrade; for example, upgrade the switch from Cumulus Linux 4.2.1 to 5.2.1 to 5.7.0.</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3711913</td>
<td>When you set an IPv4 ACL with a log action, logs do not appear under syslog after a match. This issue affects bridged packets when the rule is installed in iptables. To work around this issue, set the ACL with a MAC rule type so that it is installed in ebtables and the packets are logged correctly in {{syslog}}.The following shows an example configuration:
cumulus@switch:~$ nv set acl one rule 1 action log log-prefix NVIDIA
cumulus@switch:~$ nv set acl one rule 1 match ip protocol udp
cumulus@switch:~$ nv set acl one rule 1 match ip source-ip 10.0.14.2
cumulus@switch:~$ nv set acl one rule 1 match ip udp source-port 34
cumulus@switch:~$ nv set acl one rule 1 match mac protocol ipv4
cumulus@switch:~$ nv set acl one type mac
</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3636266</td>
<td>When an unresolved next hop is present in a next hop group, especially over an SVI interface, the switch checks if the neighbor MAC address is in the forwarding table. If the neighbor's MAC address is not there, the switch skips this next hop from backend programming and you see the {{switchd}} error {{ERR NH: l3 nhg v6 l3 nhg contains one or more unresolvable nexthops}}. There is no impact to switch functionality as unresolved neighbors are not programmed in hardware until they are resolved.</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3610591</td>
<td>After configuring the system level pre-login and post-login banner messages, the messages do not return to their default settings when you run the {{nv unset system}} command or the {{nv config apply empty}} command.</td>
<td>5.7.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3393966</td>
<td>When you configure OSPF network statements using NVUE with the {{nv set vrf &lt;vrf&gt; router ospf area &lt;area&gt; network &lt;subnet&gt;}} command, subsequent configuration changes with NVUE might bring down all OSPF neighbors. To work around this issue, create an NVUE snippet to configure the network statement, or use the {{nv set interface &lt;interface&gt; router ospf area &lt;area&gt;}} command to enable OSPF on interfaces instead of using a network statement.</td>
<td>5.5.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2705056</td>
<td>When configured with NVUE, SVIs do not inherit the pinned MAC address of the bridge.</td>
<td>4.3.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2543915</td>
<td>When you enable a service in the management VRF, {{systemctl}} issues a warning similar to the following:

Warning: The unit file, source configuration file or drop-ins of ntp@mgmt.service changed on disk. Run 'systemctl daemon-reload' to reload unit

You can safely ignore this warning.</td>
<td>4.0.0-5.9.1</td>
</tr>
</table>
</tables>