<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vSphere - ESXi 5.5</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/VMware-vSphere-ESXi-5.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/VMware-vSphere-ESXi-5.5/</guid>
      <description>The following sections describe how to import and set up a two-leaf/two-spine Cumulus VX topology with VMware vSphere.
These sections assume a basic level of VMware vSphere experience. For detailed instructions, refer to the VMware vSphere documentation.
 Create a Cumulus VX VM with VMware vSphere - ESXi 5.5 This section assumes that you have downloaded the Cumulus VX disk image for VMware hypervisors and that the VMware vSphere is installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Fusion</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/VMware-Fusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/VMware-Fusion/</guid>
      <description>The following sections describe how to import and set up a two-leaf/two-spine Cumulus VX topology with VMware Fusion.
These sections assume a basic level of VMware Fusion experience. For detailed instructions, refer to the VMware Fusion documentation.
 Create a Cumulus VX VM with VMware Fusion This section assumes that the you have downloaded the Cumulus VX disk image for VMware hypervisors and that VMware Fusion is installed. For more download locations and steps, refer to the Getting Started page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Workstation</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/VMware-Workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/VMware-Workstation/</guid>
      <description>The following sections describe how to import and set up a two-leaf/two-spine Cumulus VX topology with VMware Workstation.
These sections assume a basic level of VMware Workstation experience. For detailed instructions, refer to the VMware Workstation documentation.
 Create a Cumulus VX VM with VMware Workstation This section assumes that you have downloaded the Cumulus VX disk image for VMware hypervisors and that VMware Workstation is installed. For more download locations and steps, refer to the Getting Started page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VirtualBox</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/VirtualBox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/VirtualBox/</guid>
      <description>The following sections describe how to import and set up a two-leaf/two-spine Cumulus VX topology with VirtualBox.
These sections assume a basic level of VirtualBox experience. For detailed instructions, refer to the VirtualBox documentation.
 Create a Cumulus VX VM with VirtualBox This section assumes that you have downloaded the Cumulus VX disk image for VirtualBox and that VirtualBox is installed. For more download locations and steps, refer to the Getting Started page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libvirt and KVM - QEMU</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/Libvirt-and-KVM-QEMU/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/Libvirt-and-KVM-QEMU/</guid>
      <description>The following sections describe how to set up a two-leaf/two-spine Cumulus VX topology with QEMU/KVM on a Linux server.
These sections assume a basic level of Linux and KVM experience. For detailed instructions, refer to the QEMU and KVM documentation.
 Overview Performing virtualization in Linux requires three components:
 Libvirt provides an abstraction language to define a VM. It uses XML to represent and define the VM.
 KVM w orks exclusively with QEMU and p erforms hardware acceleration for x86 VMs with Intel and AMD CPUs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ONIE Virtual Machine</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/ONIE-Virtual-Machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Getting-Started/ONIE-Virtual-Machine/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus VX images now include the GRUB boot loader and Open Network Install Environment (ONIE) preinstalled. You can install Cumulus Linux on switch hardware using a binary image. You can test this process by installing a Cumulus VX binary image with ONIE in a virtual environment.
Installation via ONIE is supported in Cumulus VX 3.x and later versions.
 This section assumes that you have downloaded and installed a hypervisor, downloaded the Cumulus VX binary image, and configured the VM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>