<tables>
<table name="Open Issues in 4.3.0">
<tr>
<th> Issue ID </th>
<th> Description </th>
<th> Affects </th>
<th> Fixed </th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3098936</td>
<td>When withdrawal and advertisement processing occurs in short succession, type-2 routes with an IP are not imported into layer 2 VNIs.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3096918</td>
<td>The {{cl-resource-query}} command output shows ECMP nextHop Table exhaustion (above 100 percent utilization) and the {{switchd.log}} file contains ECMP resource errors with routes and next hops failing to install.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3093863</td>
<td>Slow memory leak caused by snmpd process using Zabbix template "Template Net Mellanox SNMP"</td>
<td>3.7.16, 4.2.1-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3091561</td>
<td>CVE-2022-24903: rsyslog modules for TCP syslog eception have a potential heap buffer overflow when octet-counted framing is used.  Modules &apos;imtcp&apos;, &apos;imptcp&apos;, &apos;imgssapi&apos;, and &apos;imhttp&apos; are used for regular syslog message reception. It is best practice not to directly expose them to the public. When this practice is followed, the risk is considerably lower. Module &apos;imdiag&apos; is a diagnostics module primarily intended for testbench runs. We do not expect it to be present on any production installation. Octet-counted framing is not very common. Usually, it needs to be specifically enabled at senders. If users do not need it, they can turn it off for the most important modules. This will mitigate the vulnerability.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 8.1901.0-1+deb10u1
Fixed: 8.1901.0-1+deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3089165</td>
<td>A slow memory leak might occur in {{switchd}}} if the route fails to install in hardware when hardware resources are exhausted.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3085280</td>
<td>CVE-2022-26691: in cups, a logic error in the validation of the secret key used in the "local" authorisation mode of the CUPS printing
system may result in privilege escalation.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.2.10-6+deb10u5
Fixed: 2.2.10-6+deb10u6</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3082555</td>
<td>CVE-2022-29824: several buffer handling functions in buf.c (xmlBuf*) and tree.c (xmlBuffer*) don't check for integer overflows. This can result in out-of-bounds memory writes. Exploitation requires a victim to open a crafted, multi-gigabyte XML file. 
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.9.4+dfsg1-7+deb10u3
Fixed: 2.9.4+dfsg1-7+deb10u4</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3077723</td>
<td>CVE-2022-29155: In OpenLDAP 2.x before 2.5.12 and 2.6.x before 2.6.2, a SQL injection vulnerability exists in the experimental back-sql backend to slapd, via a SQL statement within an LDAP query. This can occur during an LDAP search operation when the search filter is processed, due to a lack of proper escaping.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.4.47+dfsg-3+deb10u6
Fixed: 2.4.47+dfsg-3+deb10u7</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3077694</td>
<td>CVE-2022-1292: The c_rehash script does not properly sanitise shell metacharacters to
prevent command injection.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 1.1.1n-0+deb10u1
Fixed: 1.1.1n-0+deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3072613</td>
<td>When  you delete a bond interface with NCLU, BGP peer group configuration is removed.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3066704</td>
<td>The {{hostapd}} service stops working if an 802.1X interface goes up and down many times over a long period of time.
To work around this issue, restart the {{hostapd}} service with the {{systemctl restart hostapd}} command.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3060400</td>
<td>In an OSPF configuration, after you change the IPv6 subnet mask, the old address remains in the RIB as a connected OSPF route.
To resolve this issue, restart FRR with the {{sudo systemctl restart frr}} command.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3053063</td>
<td>The {{update-ports.service}} fails because a blank space in the comment lines of the {{/etc/cumulus/ports.conf}} file causes parsing errors.
To work around this issue, remove the blank spaces in the commented lines, then restart the {{update-ports}} and {{switchd}} services.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3046023</td>
<td>The {{cl-resource-query}} command output shows ECMP nextHop Table exhaustion (above 100 percent utilization) and the {{switchd.log}} file contains ECMP resource errors with routes and next hops failing to install.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3031235</td>
<td>Static VXLAN configuration prevents NCLU from working.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3021693</td>
<td>When ARP suppression is off, Cumulus Linux sends GARPs from {{neighmgrd}} for remote neighbors over VXLAN.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3021692</td>
<td>GARPs from {{neighmgrd}} for remote neighbors are sent over VXLAN when ARP suppression is off.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3020254</td>
<td>GARPs from {{neighmgrd}} for remote neighbors are sent over VXLAN when ARP suppression is off.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3010291</td>
<td>CVE-2021-25220: When using forwarders, bogus NS records supplied by, or via, those forwarders may be cached and used by named if it needs to recurse for any reason, causing it to obtain and pass on potentially incorrect answers.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 9.11.5.P4+dfsg-5.1+deb10u6
Fixed: 9.11.5.P4+dfsg-5.1+deb10u7</td>
<td>4.0.0-5.0.1</td>
<td>5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3007564</td>
<td>After you delete the last {{vxlan-remoteip}} configuration line from the {{/etc/network/interfaces}} file and run the {{ifreload -a}} command, the corresponding BUM flood entry is not removed.</td>
<td>3.7.15-5.0.1</td>
<td>5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2999342</td>
<td>CVE-2020-36311, CVE-2021-3609, CVE-2021-33909, CVE-2021-34693
Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Linux kernel that may lead to a privilege escalation, denial of service or information leaks.
Fixed: 4.19.194-3</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.1, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2999341</td>
<td>CVE-2021-3570
The ptp4l program in linuxptp, an implementation of the Precision Time Protocol (PTP), does not validate the messageLength field of incoming messages, allowing a remote attacker to cause a denial of service, information leak, or potentially remote code execution.
Fixed: 1.9.2-1+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2999253</td>
<td>If you remove NGINX from the switch, then run {{apt autoremove}}, switchd does not reload. 
This occurs because removing NGINX also removes the libyaml-0-2 and python-yaml packages, which are required for the {{switchd}} consistency check.</td>
<td>4.3.0-5.0.1</td>
<td>5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2993960</td>
<td>CVE-2021-43612: in lldpd, by sending short SONMP packets, an attacker can make the decoder crash
by reading too much data on the heap.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 1.0.4-0-cl5.1.0u7, 1.0.4-0-cl4.4.0u0, 1.0.4-0-cl4.3.0u2, 1.0.4-0-cl3u15
Fixed:</td>
<td>3.7.0-3.7.15, 4.0.0-5.0.1</td>
<td>3.7.16, 5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2993773</td>
<td>When a VNI goes into a protodown state, MLAG updates the VTEP IP address, which results in {{switchd}} changing the tunnel SIP in hardware.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2993471</td>
<td>When {{switchd}} restarts, the port watch daemon ({{portwd}}) attempts to send requests to {{switchd}} before {{switchd}} is ready. As a result, {{portwd}} goes into a failed state because there is no response from {{switchd}}.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2991501</td>
<td>The snmpd process will slowly leak memory when you poll TCP-MIB objects. To work around this issue, restart the snmpd service to free memory with the {{systemctl restart snmpd}} command.</td>
<td>4.2.1-5.0.1</td>
<td>5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2972540</td>
<td>With RADIUS enabled for user shell authentication, there might be a delay in local user authentication for non cumulus user accounts.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.2.1-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2972538</td>
<td>With RADIUS enabled for user shell authentication, there might be a delay in local user authentication for non cumulus user accounts.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.2.1-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2971344</td>
<td>CVE-2021-45960 CVE-2021-46143 CVE-2022-22822 CVE-2022-22823 CVE-2022-22824 CVE-2022-22825 CVE-2022-22826 CVE-2022-22827 CVE-2022-23852 CVE-2022-23990: Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in Expat, an XML parsing C library, which could result in denial of service or potentially the execution of arbitrary code, if a malformed XML file is processed.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.2.6-2+deb10u1
Fixed: 2.2.6-2+deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.2</td>
<td>4.4.3, 5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2968495</td>
<td>If {{switchd}} requires more time to update port or bond configuration after the port or bond flaps, the {{systemd}} watchdog times out. As result, {{systemd}} might assume that {{switchd}} is unresponsive and restarts it.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.2, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td>4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2965759</td>
<td>On the EdgeCore AS4610-54T switch, the fan speed reports a minimum threshold in the logs.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2961080</td>
<td>CVE-2021-28965 CVE-2021-31799 CVE-2021-31810 CVE-2021-41817 CVE-2021-41819 CVE-2021-32066: Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in the interpreter for the Ruby language and the Rubygems included, which may result on result in XML roundtrip attacks, the execution of arbitrary code, information disclosure, StartTLS stripping in IMAP or denial of service.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.5.5-3+deb10u3
Fixed: 2.5.5-3+deb10u4</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.2</td>
<td>4.4.3, 5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2961008</td>
<td>SNMP reports the same {{ifType}} of {{ethernetCsmacd(6)}} for loopback interfaces.</td>
<td>3.7.15-4.4.2, 5.0.0-5.0.1</td>
<td>4.4.3, 5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2959067</td>
<td>ECMP produces errors indicating {{No More Resources}} and {{switchd}} crashes even when ECMP utilization is low.</td>
<td>3.7.14.2-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2951110</td>
<td>The {{net show time ntp servers}} command does not show any output with management VRF.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.1.1-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2949514</td>
<td>CVE-2022-22747: Incorrect parsing of pkcs7 sequences in nss, the Mozilla Network Security Service library, may result in denial of service.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2:3.42.1-1+deb10u4
Fixed: 2:3.42.1-1+deb10u5</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.2</td>
<td>4.4.3, 5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2949512</td>
<td>On the EdgeCore AS4610-54T switch, the fan speed reports a minimum threshold in the logs.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2947679</td>
<td>If the {{clagd}} service stops during {{initDelay}}, the peerlink flag does not clear from any VNIs that become dual connected during this time. {{switchd}} uses the peerlink flag to program MLAG loop prevention. As a result of the overlapping stale flags, traffic destined for the VXLAN might drop.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2943222</td>
<td>Cumulus Linux lets you add more than one VXLAN interface to same VLAN on the same bridge. This is an invalid configuration as certain Cumulus Linux components, such as {{switchd}}, expect a single VNI for a given bridge or VLAN.</td>
<td>3.7.15, 4.2.1-5.0.1</td>
<td>3.7.16, 5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2940063</td>
<td>Under certain high scale conditions, various modules might experience timetouts during cl-support collection, which results in missing data in the cl-support file.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.15, 4.1.1-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.16, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2940051</td>
<td>In an MLAG configuration with traditional bridges, MAC addresses are  seen over peer link during {{ifreload}} when adding new VLANS or bridges. </td>
<td>3.7.14.2-3.7.15, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.16, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2935122</td>
<td>After building VLAN or VXLAN interfaces, MLAG becomes unstable.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2935121</td>
<td>When you configure 199 VXLANs plus 199 VLANs, {{clagd}} crashes every few seconds. </td>
<td>3.7.15, 4.3.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>3.7.16, 4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2932121</td>
<td>When {{switchd}} restarts, the port watch daemon ({{portwd}}) attempts to send requests to {{switchd}} before {{switchd}} is ready. As a result, {{portwd}} goes into a failed state because there is no response from {{switchd}}.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2902013</td>
<td>The NCLU commit  command adds a five second delay.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2899413</td>
<td>Broadcom switches return a table full error when creating VXLAN gports, which causes {switchd}} to crash.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2896733</td>
<td>Traffic failover in a multicast topology with redundancy has the mroute stuck in a prune state and PIM join messages continue to send.
To work around this issue, run the vtysh {{clear ip mroute}} command.</td>
<td>3.7.15-5.0.1</td>
<td>5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2896672</td>
<td>When you add a new VLAN, the VLAN interface type shows as {{unknown}} and cannot be reached.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2891257</td>
<td>CVE-2021-39925: Buffer overflow in the Bluetooth SDP dissector in Wireshark 3.4.0 to 3.4.9 and 3.2.0 to 3.2.17 allows denial of service via packet injection or crafted capture file.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.6.20-0+deb10u1
Fixed: 2.6.20-0+deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2890683</td>
<td>CVE-2021-42771: relative path traversal in Babel, a set of tools for internationalising Python applications, could result in the execution of arbitrary code.
Vulnerable: 2.6.0+dfsg.1-1
Fixed: 2.6.0+dfsg.1-1+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2879645</td>
<td>When you add a new VLAN, the VLAN interface type shows as {{unknown}} and cannot be reached.</td>
<td>3.7.15, 4.3.0-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td>3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2877797</td>
<td>CVE-2021-43527: The NSS package is vulnerable to a heap overflow when verifying DSA/RSA-PSS DER-encoded signatures.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 3.42.1-1+deb10u3
Fixed: 3.42.1-1+deb10u4</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2875338</td>
<td>In a scaled EVPN-MLAG configuration (observed with 400 or more VNIs and 20K or more MAC addresses – the actual scale might vary), when the peer link flaps causing all VNIs to come up at the same time, there might be high CPU utilization on the system for several minutes and the FRR service might restart. After FRR restarts or the CPU utilization settles down, the system functions normally.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2875301</td>
<td>When an IPv4 address is not configured on a tenant VRF loopback interface, the {{switchd}} process slowly leaks memory, which results in unresolved next hops. 
To work around this issue, configure an IPv4 address on all VRF interfaces.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2875296</td>
<td>On the Mellanox Spectrum-2 switches, after running the {{systemctl restart networking service}} command on the MLAG primary switch, the secondary switch also closes its ports.
To work around this issue, run the {{ifreload -a}} command to restart networking.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2875279</td>
<td>In a scaled EVPN-MLAG configuration (observed with 400 or more VNIs and 20K or more MAC addresses – the actual scale might vary), when the peer link flaps causing all VNIs to come up at the same time, there might be high CPU utilization on the system for several minutes and the FRR service might restart. After FRR restarts or the CPU utilization settles down, the system functions normally.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td>3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2873323</td>
<td>CVE-2020-21913: International Components for Unicode (ICU-20850) v66.1 was discovered to contain a use after free bug in the pkg_createWithAssemblyCode function in the file tools/pkgdata/pkgdata.cpp.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2873185</td>
<td>In an MLAG configuration with traditional bridges, MAC addresses are  seen over the peer link during {{ifreload}} when you add new VLANS or bridges. </td>
<td>3.7.14.2-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2866097</td>
<td>Under certain high scale conditions, various modules might experience timetouts during cl-support collection, which results in missing data in the cl-support file.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.1.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2866084</td>
<td>When a VTEP is rebooted, MAC address entries might become out of sync between the kernel FDB table and the EVPN MAC VNI table on remote VTEPs. The impacted MAC entries are installed against the rebooted VTEP IP address in the kernel FDB and the correct VTEP IP is present in the EVPN MAC VNI table.
To work around this issue:

1. Clear all corrupted MAC address entries in the kernel FDB with the {{ bridge fdb del &lt;address&gt; dev &lt;interface&gt; [dst|via] &lt;interface|IP&gt; &lt;flags&gt; }} command.

2. In the {{/etc/network/ifupdown2/policy.d/vxlan.json}} file, add {{"vxlan-learning": "off"}}:

$ cat /etc/network/ifupdown2/policy.d/vxlan.json

   {
        "vxlan": {
            "module_globals": { "vxlan-purge-remotes": "no" },
            "defaults": {
                "vxlan-ageing": "1800",
                "vxlan-port": "4789", &lt;==== This comma needs to be added at the end of this line
                "vxlan-learning": "off" &lt;= This line needs to be added
             }
        }
   }

3. Reboot the affected switches.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2866080</td>
<td>On the Maverick S4148T switch with MLAG, Cumulus Linux drops LACP, ARP, LLDP and BGP traffic.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2862214</td>
<td>{{switchd}} can leak memory leak during VXLAN route updates during high frequency.</td>
<td>3.7.14.2-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2862210</td>
<td>On NVIDIA Spectrum ASICs in a layer 2 bridge scaled configuration (more than 800 VLANs), {{clagd.service}} enters a failed state after a reboot or a {{switchd}} restart.
To work around this issue, load the port configuration in a staggered manner (groups of five downlink ports).</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.15, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.16, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2859177</td>
<td>The {{cl-route-check --layer3}} command fails with a memory error. For example:

cumulus@switch:~$ sudo cl-route-check --layer3
Traceback (most recent call last):
 File "/usr/cumulus/bin/cl-route-check", line 1270, in &lt;module&gt;
  routing.collect_data()
 File "/usr/cumulus/bin/cl-route-check", line 528, in collect_data
  self.collect_data_bgp_ipv4()
 File "/usr/cumulus/bin/cl-route-check", line 711, in collect_data_bgp_ipv4
  bgp_ipv4 = json.loads(output)
 File "/usr/lib/python2.7/json/__init__.py", line 338, in loads
  return _default_decoder.decode(s)
 File "/usr/lib/python2.7/json/decoder.py", line 366, in decode
  obj, end = self.raw_decode(s, idx=_w(s, 0).end())
 File "/usr/lib/python2.7/json/decoder.py", line 382, in raw_decode
  obj, end = self.scan_once(s, idx)
MemoryError
</td>
<td>3.7.15-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2854787</td>
<td>An unexpected software system shutdown can occur due to a thermal zones issue in the {{hw-management}} package. The following message might appear in {{/var/log/syslog}} before the shutdown:

thermal thermal_zoneX: critical temperature reached (33 C), shutting down
</td>
<td>4.3.0-5.0.1</td>
<td>5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2854784</td>
<td>After building VLAN or VXLAN interfaces, MLAG becomes unstable.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2853630</td>
<td>In an MLAG and VXLAN Active Active configuration, when you add a new VNI on the primary MLAG switch only, you see packet loss over the old VNI. </td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2849529</td>
<td>The NTP system clock is unable to synchronize with the NTP server.
To work around this issue, use the {{chrony}} implementation of NTP instead of {{ntpd}}.  {{chrony}} synchronizes the system clock faster and with better accuracy.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2848219</td>
<td>On Dell S3048 switches configured for 802.1x auth, you might see file descriptor exhaustion with Hostapd messages indicating that Cumulus Linux is unable to open {{/dev/urandom}} or write out the transient ACL files.
To work around this issue, reboot the switch.</td>
<td>3.7.15, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2845538</td>
<td>CVE-2020-19143: A flaw was discovered in tiff, a Tag Image File Format library, which may result in denial of service or the execution of arbitrary code if malformed image files are processed.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 4.1.0+git191117-2~deb10u2
Fixed: 4.1.0+git191117-2~deb10u3</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2845531</td>
<td>If you update the MAC address of an SVI when the SVI is in a {{protodown}} state (for example, when no bridge ports that carry this VNI are operationally up or if the MAC address of the SVI's parent bridge changes), {{clagd}} does not notice the change. The MLAG peer incorrectly maintains a PERMANENT neighbor entry for the SVI IP that points to the old MAC address.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2845290</td>
<td>The following vulnerabilities in gdb, as embedded in the crash handling program, have been announced:
CVE-2019-1010180: Buffer overflow which can be triggered by debugging an ELF file.
CVE-2017-9778: Vulnerability to a negative length field in DWARF section, resulting in excessive memory allocation.
Vulnerable: crash 7.2.8-1+cl4u1 and 7.2.8-1+cl3u1 with embedded gdb 7.6
Fixed: crash 7.2.8-1+cl5.0.0u6</td>
<td>3.7.15-4.4.3</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2840819</td>
<td>CVE-2021-25219: The lame server cache in BIND, a DNS server implementation, can be abused by an attacker to significantly degrade resolver performance, resulting in denial of service (large delays for responses for client queries and DNS timeouts on client hosts).</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2839140</td>
<td>After building VLAN or VXLAN interfaces, MLAG becomes unstable.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2837378</td>
<td>The switch duplicates DHCP packets that pass through the VTEP.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2829196</td>
<td>After bringing up a bridge port, there is a multi second delay before the bridge port is able to learn any MAC addresses or neighbors, which causes a forwarding delay (about six seconds with 300 or more VLANs).</td>
<td>3.7.15, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2821869</td>
<td>The {{cl-route-check --layer3}} command fails with a memory error. For example:

cumulus@switch:~$ sudo cl-route-check --layer3
Traceback (most recent call last):
 File "/usr/cumulus/bin/cl-route-check", line 1270, in &lt;module&gt;
  routing.collect_data()
 File "/usr/cumulus/bin/cl-route-check", line 528, in collect_data
  self.collect_data_bgp_ipv4()
 File "/usr/cumulus/bin/cl-route-check", line 711, in collect_data_bgp_ipv4
  bgp_ipv4 = json.loads(output)
 File "/usr/lib/python2.7/json/__init__.py", line 338, in loads
  return _default_decoder.decode(s)
 File "/usr/lib/python2.7/json/decoder.py", line 366, in decode
  obj, end = self.raw_decode(s, idx=_w(s, 0).end())
 File "/usr/lib/python2.7/json/decoder.py", line 382, in raw_decode
  obj, end = self.scan_once(s, idx)
MemoryError
</td>
<td>3.7.15-4.4.3</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2820565</td>
<td>SNMP does not start and you see errors similar to the following:

cumulus@switch:~$ sudo systemctl status snmpd.service 
snmpd.service - Simple Network Management Protocol (SNMP) Daemon.
   Loaded: loaded (/lib/systemd/system/snmpd.service; enabled; vendor preset: enabled)
   Active: failed (Result: exit-code) since Mon 2021-10-11 14:38:13 UTC; 1min 8s ago
  Process: 1987 ExecStart=/usr/sbin/snmpd $SNMPDOPTS -f (code=exited, status=1/FAILURE)
 Main PID: 1987 (code=exited, status=1/FAILURE)

To work around this issue, run the {{sudo systemctl restart snmpd.service}} command.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2816069</td>
<td>On the EdgeCore AS7326 switch, unicast ARP requests are not forwarded to the control plane.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2815645</td>
<td>In an EVPN configuration, an FRR restart on a border leaf VRRP master causes a stale route for the VRRP VIP on some remote VTEPs to point to the VRRP backup after convergence.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.15, 4.3.0-5.0.1</td>
<td>3.7.16, 5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2803044</td>
<td>In an EVPN configuration with IP or MAC mobility, higher MM EVPN routes do not remove the old ARP entries during VIP migration between VTEP racks.</td>
<td>3.7.14.2-3.7.15, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2794766</td>
<td>The Mellanox 3700C switch reports a slow memory leak in sx_sdk. Memory increases by about 240B/hour and does not free up.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2792750</td>
<td>If you change the {{clagd-vxlan-anycast-ip}} setting on both MLAG peers at the same time, both peers use their unique VTEP address indefinitely.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2792616</td>
<td>If a neighbor entry (ARP or NDP) is used as a next hop of a route that is synchronized into hardware, the neighbor entry is not removed from hardware after the neighbor is no longer reachable.  As a result, routed traffic matching this prefix is incorrectly hardware forwarded through the stale neighbor information.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2786264</td>
<td>When the {{switchd}} service restarts, any dropped traffic registered by WJH change to unregistered and WJH stops reporting all dropped traffic. This occurs because the  WJH service does not restart automatically when the {{switchd}} service restarts.
To work around this issue, manually restart WJH with the {{sudo systemctl restart what-just-happened.service}} command every time  the {{switchd}} service restarts.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2783611</td>
<td>If you remove ports from a bridge and add IP addresses in one {{ifreload}}, connected routes are bound to the wrong routing information field.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2782035</td>
<td>The following vulnerabilities have been announced in the openssl packages:
CVE-2021-3711: buffer overflow vulnerability in SM2 decryption.
CVE-2021-3712: buffer overrun when processing ASN.1 strings in the X509_aux_print() function.
More details at https://www.openssl.org/news/secadv/20210824.txt .
Vulnerable: &lt;= 1.1.1d-0+deb10u6
Fixed: 1.1.1d-0+deb10u7</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2771871</td>
<td>IPv4 and IPv6 neighbor entries in a FAILED state are incorrectly programmed into hardware as FORWARD entries instead of TRAP entries. Traffic is forwarded to these neighbors with a destination MAC address of 00:00:00:00:00:00 instead of trapping them to the CPU to resolve the correct MAC address.

This affects failed neighbor entries on routed interfaces that are not SVIs.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2770030</td>
<td>When you modify the default pre-auth policy located in {{/etc/cumulus/acl/policy.d/dot1x_preauth_dacl}}, after restarting {{hostapd}} the {{/etc/cumulus/acl/policy.d/dot1x_preauth_dacl}} directory is deleted and recreated with the default rule set that comes from the {{hostapd}} binary.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2754791</td>
<td>Remote MAC addreses in zebra are out of sync with {{bgpd}}. The zebra MAC addresses point to an incorrect (old) VTEP IP  address and the sequence number is one higher than in BGP. </td>
<td>3.7.14.2-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2754723</td>
<td>When {{route_preferred_over_neigh}} is set to {{FALSE}} in the {{/etc/cumulus/switchd.conf}} file, host routes (/32 or /128) are used for forwarding in hardware instead of a local neighbor entry.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2754692</td>
<td>CVE-2021-3672: in c-ares, a library that performs DNS requests and name resolution asynchronously, missing input validation of hostnames returned by DNS servers can lead to output of wrong hostnames (leading to Domain Hijacking).
Vulnerable: 1.14.0-1
Fixed: 1.14.0-1+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2754686</td>
<td>CVE-2021-38165: lynx, a non-graphical (text-mode) web browser, does not properly handle the userinfo subcomponent of a URI, which can lead to leaking of credential in cleartext in SNI data.
Vulnerable: 2.8.9rel.1-3
Fixed: 2.8.9rel.1-3+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2754680</td>
<td>CVE-2020-26558 / CVE-2021-0129: Bluez does not properly check permissions during pairing operation, which could allow an attacker to impersonate the initiating device.
CVE-2020-27153: a double free flaw in the disconnect_cb() routine in the gattool. A remote attacker can take advantage of this flaw during service discovery for denial of service, or potentially, execution of arbitrary code.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 5.50-1.2~deb10u1
Fixed: 5.50-1.2~deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2747606</td>
<td>CVE-2021-3246: a buffer overflow in libsndfile, a library
for reading/writing audio files, which could result in denial of service
or potentially the execution of arbitrary code when processing a
malformed audio file.
Vulnerable: 1.0.28-6
Fixed: 1.0.28-6+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2739690</td>
<td>CVE-2021-22918: An out-of-bounds read was discovered in the uv__idna_to_ascii() function of Libuv, an asynchronous event notification library, which could result in denial of service or information disclosure.
Vulnerable: 1.24.1-1
Fixed: 1.24.1-1+deb 10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2739640</td>
<td>CVE-2021-36222: It was discovered that the Key Distribution Center (KDC) in krb5, the MIT implementation of Kerberos, is prone to a NULL pointer dereference flaw. An unauthenticated attacker can take advantage of this flaw to cause a denial of service (KDC crash) by sending a request containing a PA-ENCRYPTED-CHALLENGE padata element without using FAST.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 1.17-3+deb10u1
Fixed: 1.17-3+deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2739402</td>
<td>The destination MAC address of ERSPAN GRE packets is set to all zeros.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2738625</td>
<td>When you configure the switch with the minimum reserved VLAN of 150 and the internal VLANs are exhausted, the MLAG peer does not  forward the VLAN.</td>
<td>3.7.15, 4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2736260</td>
<td>After an apt upgrade, the OPTIONS configuration line in {{/etc/default/isc-dhcp-relay}} might be removed. To work around this issue, reconfigure the desired options in the file after the upgrade completes.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.15, 4.2.1-4.3.0</td>
<td>3.7.16, 4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2734126</td>
<td>CVE-2021-33910: The Qualys Research Labs discovered that an attacker-controlled allocation using the alloca() function could result in memory
corruption, allowing to crash systemd and hence the entire operating system.  Details can be found at https://www.qualys.com/2021/07/20/cve-2021-33910/denial-of-service-systemd.txt .
Vulnerable: &lt;= 241-7~deb10u7
Fixed: 241-7~deb10u8</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2734119</td>
<td>The ESI line in the {{show bgp l2vpn evpn route}} command output always shows VNI: 0. This is a cosmetic software issue.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2734107</td>
<td>When withdrawal and advertisement processing occurs in short succession, type-2 routes with an IP are not imported into layer 2 VNIs.</td>
<td>3.7.12-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2734103</td>
<td>{{ACL [No More Resources]}} messages keep appearing and you can't reinstall the ACL.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2732587</td>
<td>The bridge MAC address is updated during a port change on bridge interfaces.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2730225</td>
<td>When withdrawal and advertisement processing occurs in short succession, type-2 routes with an IP are not imported into layer 2 VNIs.</td>
<td>3.7.12-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2728207</td>
<td>CVE-2021-3570: A flaw was found in the ptp4l program of the linuxptp package. A missing length check when forwarding a PTP message between ports allows a remote attacker to cause an information leak, crash, or potentially remote code execution. The highest threat from this vulnerability is to data confidentiality and integrity as well as system availability. </td>
<td>3.7.0-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2728206</td>
<td>CVE-2021-3570: A flaw was found in the ptp4l program of the linuxptp package. A missing length check when forwarding a PTP message between ports allows a remote attacker to cause an information leak, crash, or potentially remote code execution. The highest threat from this vulnerability is to data confidentiality and integrity as well as system availability. </td>
<td>3.7.0-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2728205</td>
<td>CVE-2021-3570: A flaw was found in the ptp4l program of the linuxptp package. A missing length check when forwarding a PTP message between ports allows a remote attacker to cause an information leak, crash, or potentially remote code execution. The highest threat from this vulnerability is to data confidentiality and integrity as well as system availability. </td>
<td>3.7.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2728119</td>
<td>When VRF devices are deleted and reconfigured (for example, during a networking service restart), dynamic BGP neighbors might fail to reestablish. 
To work around this issue, restart FRR with the {{sudo systemctl restart frr}} command.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2724191</td>
<td>On the Celestica Seastone switch, when you run {{ smonctl -v}}, the DIMM 1 Temp Sensor shows as absent.
This is a cosmetic software issue and not indicative of a hardware failure on the system.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2716829</td>
<td>In an EVPN multihoming configuration, the VTEP continues to advertise a stale route after an extended MAC mobility event.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.1</td>
<td>4.4.2-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2716822</td>
<td>The {{/etc/cumulus/ports.conf}} file on the Dell Z9264F-ON switch does not show that Cumulus Linux does not support the 2x10G SFP+ ports.</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2713888</td>
<td>With the {{ip-acl-heavy}} TCAM profile, the following message might appear after you install an ACL with NCLU or cl-acltool and the ACL might not work correctly.

hal_flx_acl_util.c:378 ERR hal_flx_acl_resource_release resource region 0 size 7387 create failed: No More Resources

To work around this issue, change the TCAM profile to {{acl-heavy}} or {{ip-acl-heavy}} with ACL non-atomic mode.</td>
<td>3.7.15-5.0.1</td>
<td>5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2711533</td>
<td>On the AS7326-56X switch, the link lights for 25G ports configured to work at 1G do not illuminate.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2710208</td>
<td>The {{net show bgp neighbor}} command output shows the BFD status as UP even when the BGP neighbor is not established, such as when the interface is down.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2701000</td>
<td>A default route learned from DHCP on eth0 in the management VRF might install in the default VRF if eth0 is disconnected and the original next hop is reachable in the default VRF.
To work around this issue, delete the DHCP lease file for eth0 with the {{sudo rm /var/lib/dhcp/dhclient.eth0.leases}} command.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2700767</td>
<td>Following an event that causes the peerlink bond MAC address to change, such as a slave port state change, MLAG interfaces might be suspended due to a "peer-ip-mismatch."  This behavior is seen when you use a "clagd-peer-ip linklocal" configuration.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.15, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2699399</td>
<td>When you run the vtysh {{show ip bgp vrf &lt;name&gt; &lt;afi&gt; &lt;safi&gt; statistics}} command, the {{bgpd}} service crashes if you use {{vrf all}}. For example:

spine01# show ip bgp vrf all statistics 
vtysh: error reading from bgpd: Success (0)Warning: closing connection to bgpd because of an I/O error!

To workaround this issue, run the command against each VRF independently.</td>
<td>3.7.15, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2699378</td>
<td>Following an event that causes the peerlink bond MAC address to change, such as a slave port state change, MLAG interfaces might be suspended due to a "peer-ip-mismatch."  This behavior is seen when you use a "clagd-peer-ip linklocal" configuration.</td>
<td>4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2695527</td>
<td>CVE-2021-3580 CVE-2021-20305: Multiple vulnerabilities were discovered in nettle, a low level cryptographic library, which could result in denial of service (remote crash in RSA decryption via specially crafted ciphertext, crash on ECDSA signature verification) or incorrect verification of ECDSA signatures.
Vulnerable: 3.4.1-1
Fixed: 3.4.1-1+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2695314</td>
<td>In a VRRP configuration, BGP unnumbered sessions for VRFs fail to establish after a networking restart.</td>
<td>4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2691590</td>
<td>CVE-2021-0089 CVE-2021-26313 CVE-2021-28690 CVE-2021-28692: Multiple vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Xen hypervisor, which could result in denial of service or information leaks.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 4.11.4+99-g8bce4698f6-1
Fixed: 4.11.4+107-gef32c7afa2-1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2687160</td>
<td>CVE-2018-25009 CVE-2018-25010 CVE-2018-25011 CVE-2018-25013 CVE-2018-25014 CVE-2020-36328 CVE-2020-36329 CVE-2020-36330 CVE-2020-36331 CVE-2020-36332: Multiple vulnerabilities were discovered in libwebp, the implementation of the WebP image format, which could result in denial of service, memory disclosure or potentially the execution of arbitrary code if malformed images are processed.
Vulnerable: 0.6.1-2
Fixed: 0.6.1-2+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2685994</td>
<td>When you use the NVUE command {{nv set interface lo router ospf area}} to configure OSPF on a loopback interface, the configuration fails to apply.
To work around this issue, configure the loopback interface in the desired OSPF area with the {{nv set vrf default router ospf area 0 network}} command and reference the assigned prefix of the loopback interface. For example:

cumulus@leaf01:~$ nv set vrf default router ospf area 0 network 10.10.10.1/32
</td>
<td>4.0.0-5.0.1</td>
<td>5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2685584</td>
<td>A host migrated to an 802.1x port within the same broadcast domain does not have the correct static FDB entry installed if a dynamic FDB entry for that MAC address exists from previous connectivity in the broadcast domain.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2684418</td>
<td>If you configure items in a VRF that has been created, deleted, then re-created, {{staticd}} crashes.</td>
<td>4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2682976</td>
<td>CVE-2021-28902, CVE-2021-28903, CVE-2021-28904, CVE-2021-28905, CVE-2021-28906: Several vulnerabilities have been announced in libyang that can cause a crash.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 1.0.184-2+cl4.3.0u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2682973</td>
<td>CVE-2020-12762: integer overflow in the json-c JSON library, which could result in denial of service or potentially the execution of arbitrary code if large malformed JSON files are processed.
Vulnerable: 0.12.2+cl4u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2682780</td>
<td>Adding a route map configuration after a MAC access list configuration line causes the route map configuration to be applied incorrectly.
To work around this issue, add the MAC access list configuration to the end of the {{/etc/frr/frr.conf}} file.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2679949</td>
<td>CVE-2021-25217: parsing of stored leases by dhclient or dhcpd has an incorrect length check that may cause a crash.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 4.3.1-6-cl3.7.14u1
Fixed: 4.3.1-6-cl3.7.16u1</td>
<td>3.7.0-3.7.15, 4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>3.7.16, 4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2671668</td>
<td>CVE-2021-23017: off-by-one in Nginx, a high-performance web and reverse proxy server, which could
result in denial of service and potentially the execution of arbitrary code.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 1.14.2-2+deb10u3
Fixed: 1.14.2-2+deb10u4</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2669858</td>
<td>OpenSSH is vulnerable to CVE-2020-14145, as described in https://www.fzi.de/fileadmin/user_upload/2020-06-26-FSA-2020-2.pdf.  
This is an information leak in algorithm negotiation that can allow man-in-the-middle attacks on initial connection attempts without a previously stored server host key on the client. If desired, mitigation using UpdateHostKeys and HostKeyAlgorithms is also given in that paper.</td>
<td>3.7.14-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2669073</td>
<td>On Spectrum, Spectrum-2, and Spectrum-3 switches, the {{l1-show}} command shows the wrong data when the MST service is stopped.
To work around this issue, start the MST service with the {{sudo mst start}} command.</td>
<td>4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2668543</td>
<td>SVIs do not inherit the pinned MAC address of the bridge.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2666839</td>
<td>CVE-2021-31535: missing length validation in various functions provided by libx11, the X11 client-side library, allow to inject X11 protocol commands on X clients, leading to authentication bypass, denial of service or potentially the execution of arbitrary code.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 1.6.7-1+deb10u1
Fixed: 1.6.7-1+deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2663480</td>
<td>CVE-2021-3520: integer overflow flaw in lz4, a fast LZ compression algorithm library, resulting in memory corruption.
Vulnerable: 1.8.3-1
Fixed: 1.8.3-1+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2663119</td>
<td>If you update the MAC address of an SVI using {{ifreload}} and {{hwaddress}}, the kernel maintains a stale permanent fdb entry for the old MAC address.</td>
<td>3.7.15, 4.3.0-4.4.3, 5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
<td>3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2660583</td>
<td>In an MLAG configuration, the secondary MLAG switch does not use a unique address instead of the MLAG system MAC address when there is a double-failure (peer link failure and backup IP failure)</td>
<td>3.7.14-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2656530</td>
<td>CVE-2020-18032: A buffer overflow was discovered in Graphviz, which could potentially result in the execution of arbitrary code when processing a malformed file.
Vulnerable: 2.40.1-6
Fixed: 2.40.1-6+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2654715</td>
<td>The {{cl-acltool}} takes a significant amount of time to run, which can slow down automation scripts.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2653493</td>
<td>After running the {{systemctl restart networking service}} command on the MLAG primary switch, the secondary switch also closes its ports.
To work around this issue, run the {{ifreload -a}} command to restart networking.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2653400</td>
<td>When 802.1x MAB and a parking VLAN are configured on an interface, hostapd might install a static fdb entry if the interface is down.  To work around this issue, delete 802.1x from the interface with the {{net del interface &lt;interface&gt; dot1x}} command, then add back the 802.1x configuration.</td>
<td>3.7.10-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2652003</td>
<td>When 802.1x MAB and a parking VLAN are configured on an interface, hostapd might install a static fdb entry if the interface is down.  To work around this issue, delete 802.1x from the interface with the {{net del interface &lt;interface&gt; dot1x}} command, then add back the 802.1x configuration.</td>
<td>3.7.10-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2648658</td>
<td>If you try to use more than one percent of {{max-ecmp-nexthops}}, you get an error indicating a failure.</td>
<td>3.7.15-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2648587</td>
<td>The received PVST BPDU for a VLAN is flooded even though the ingress port doesn't have the VLAN tagged.</td>
<td>3.7.8-3.7.14.2, 4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2644071</td>
<td>When you stop {{clagd}} on the MLAG primary switch (for example, when you reboot the switch), in rare conditions the MLAG secondary switch might fail to properly assert itself as the MLAG primary switch. To work around this issue, change the primary designation by configuring the {{clagd}} priorities to ensure that you only reboot a switch that is in the MLAG secondary role.</td>
<td>3.7.15, 4.3.0</td>
<td>3.7.16, 4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2644054</td>
<td>The following vulnerabilities have been announced in BIND:
CVE-2021-25214: a malformed incoming IXFR transfer could trigger an assertion failure in named, resulting in denial of service.
CVE-2021-25215: named could crash when a DNAME record placed in the ANSWER section during DNAME chasing turned out to be the final answer to a client query.
CVE-2021-25216: the SPNEGO implementation used by BIND is prone to a buffer overflow vulnerability. This update switches to use the SPNEGO implementation from the Kerberos libraries.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 9.11.5.P4+dfsg-5.1+deb10u4
Fixed: 9.11.5.P4+dfsg-5.1+deb10u5</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2643822</td>
<td>On the Mellanox Spectrum-2 switches, after running the {{systemctl restart networking service}} command on the MLAG primary switch, the secondary switch also closes its ports.
To work around this issue, run the {{ifreload -a}} command to restart networking.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2639303</td>
<td>When you use NCLU to delete a bond, then add an interface, NCLU reports an error similar to the following:
ERROR: 'NoneType' object has no attribute 'conf_key_value_multiple_values'
See /var/log/netd.log for more details.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2638106</td>
<td>The NCLU {{net show route vrf &lt;vrf&gt; summary}} and vtysh {{show ip route vrf &lt;vrf&gt; summary}} commands don't return any output.</td>
<td>4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2633245</td>
<td>On the Dell N3048EP-ON switch, the SPF+ ports remain down after a power cycle.</td>
<td>3.7.10-3.7.16, 4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2633062</td>
<td>The following vulnerability affects the libgstreamer-plugins-base1.0-0 package.  There is no CVE yet; the Debian advisory number is DSA-4903-1.
Multiple vulnerabilities were discovered in plugins for the GStreamer media framework, which may result in denial of service or potentially the execution of arbitrary code if a malformed media file is opened.
Vulnerable: 1.14.4-2
Fixed: 1.14.4-2+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2632379</td>
<td>When you upgrade the switch with {{apt-get upgrade}}, the {{kexec-tools}} package is not installed, which causes the Smart System Manager fast restart mode to work incorrectly.</td>
<td>4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2628514</td>
<td>CVE-2020-12695: hostapd does not properly handle UPnP subscribe messages under certain conditions, allowing an attacker to cause a denial of service.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.8.0-cl3.7.15u2
Fixed: 2.8.0-cl3.7.15u3</td>
<td>3.7.14-3.7.14.2, 4.3.0</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2618227</td>
<td>The NCLU {{net show bridge macs}} command displays permanent MAC addresses for trunked VLANs.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2617001</td>
<td>CVE-2021-26933 CVE-2021-27379
Multiple vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Xen hypervisor, which could result in denial of service, privilege escalation or memory disclosure.
Vulnerable: &lt; 4.11.4+99-g8bce4698f6-1
Fixed: 4.11.4+99-g8bce4698f6-1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2616999</td>
<td>CVE-2021-23358: missing input sanitising in the template() function of the Underscore JavaScript library could result in the execution of arbitrary code.
Vulnerable: 1.9.1~dfsg-1
Fixed: 1.9.1~dfsg-1+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2616988</td>
<td>CVE-2020-6851 CVE-2020-8112 CVE-2020-15389 CVE-2020-27814 CVE-2020-27823 CVE-2020-27824 CVE-2020-27841 CVE-2020-27842 CVE-2020-27843 CVE-2020-27845: Multiple vulnerabilities have been discovered in openjpeg2, the open-source JPEG 2000 codec, which could result in denial of service or the execution of arbitrary code when opening a malformed image.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.3.0-2+deb10u1
Fixed: 2.3.0-2+deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2616977</td>
<td>Multiple vulnerabilities were discovered in cURL, an URL transfer library:
CVE-2020-8169: partial password leak to DNS servers.
CVE-2020-8177: malicious server could cause curl -J -i to overwrite a local file.
CVE-2020-8231: libcurl with CURLOPT_CONNECT_ONLY information leak due to wrong connection.
CVE-2020-8284: PASV response could trick curl into connecting back to an arbitrary IP address and port.
CVE-2020-8285: libcurl could run out of stack space using FTP wildcard matching (CURLOPT_CHUNK_BGN_FUNCTION).
CVE-2020-8286: failure to verify that OSCP response matches intended certificate.
CVE-2021-22876: libcurl did not strip user credentials from URL when populating Referer HTTP request header.
CVE-2021-22890: libcurl using HTTPS proxy with TLS1.3 could use the wrong session ticket and bypass server TLS certificate check.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 7.64.0-4+deb10u1
Fixed: 7.64.0-4+deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2616968</td>
<td>CVE-2021-28957: lxml, a Python binding for the libxml2 and libxslt libraries, did not properly sanitize its input. This would allow a malicious user to mount a cross-site scripting attack.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 4.3.2-1+deb10u2
Fixed: 4.3.2-1+deb10u3</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2616965</td>
<td>CVE-2021-27291: Pygments, a syntax highlighting package written in Python 3, used regular expressions which could result in denial of service.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.3.1+dfsg-1+deb10u1
Fixed: 2.3.1+dfsg-1+deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2616955</td>
<td>CVE-2021-3449: A NULL pointer dereference was found in the signature_algorithms processing in OpenSSL, a Secure Sockets Layer toolkit, which could result in denial of service.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 1.1.1d-0+deb10u5
Fixed: 1.1.1d-0+deb10u6</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2614016</td>
<td>The switch firmware incorrectly identifies Lenovo LR4 transceivers (part number 00YD278) and does not set the laser levels properly, which can prevent the link from coming up or might cause the transceiver to be identified as a 1G module.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2599274</td>
<td>On Mellanox Spectrum switches, when there is an MSTP forwarding state change on a bonds (for example, when the state changes from blocking to forwarding), the MSTP hardware table might set some VLANs to blocking when they should be forwarding. A a result, all packets on these VLANs drop at ingress.
To recover from this state, flap the bond interface (not the physical swp) by running {{ifdown &lt;bond_name&gt; ; sleep 1 ; ifup &lt;bond_name&gt;}}.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2582639</td>
<td>On NVIDIA Spectrum switches, BUM traffic might be dropped during VXLAN decapsulation in an EVPN multihoming environment after multiple PIM uplink interfaces flap.</td>
<td>4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2578872</td>
<td>CVE-2021-20270: It was discovered that Pygments, a syntax highlighting package written in Python, could be forced into an infinite loop, resulting in denial of service.
Vulnerable: 2.3.1+dfsg-1
Fixed: 2.3.1+dfsg-1+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2578869</td>
<td>CVE-2020-35523 CVE-2020-35524: Two vulnerabilities have been discovered in the libtiff library and the included tools, which may result in denial of service or the execution of arbitrary code if malformed image files are processed.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 4.1.0+git191117-2~deb10u1
Fixed: 4.1.0+git191117-2~deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2577499</td>
<td>QSFP+ 40G optics do not work on Spectrum platforms.</td>
<td>4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2574368</td>
<td>When you run the NCLU {{net add bgp maximum-paths ibgp}} command, FRR restarts unexpectedly.
To work around this issue, either use the {{vtysh}} commands or edit the {{/etc/frr/frr.conf}} file directly, then run {{systemctl reload frr}}.</td>
<td>4.1.1-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2566879</td>
<td>CVE-2021-27803: A vulnerability was discovered in how p2p/p2p_pd.c in wpa_supplicant before 2.10 processes P2P (Wi-Fi Direct) provision discovery requests. It could result in denial of service or other impact (potentially execution of arbitrary code), for an attacker within radio range.</td>
<td>3.7.14-3.7.14.2, 4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2564838</td>
<td>Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in the GRUB2 bootloader:
CVE-2020-14372: It was discovered that the acpi command allows a privileged user to load crafted ACPI tables when Secure Boot is enabled.
CVE-2020-25632: A use-after-free vulnerability was found in the rmmod command.
CVE-2020-25647: An out-of-bound write vulnerability was found in the grub_usb_device_initialize() function, which is called to handle USB device initialization.
CVE-2020-27749: A stack buffer overflow flaw was found in grub_parser_split_cmdline.
CVE-2020-27779: It was discovered that the cutmem command allows a privileged user  to remove memory regions when Secure Boot is enabled.
CVE-2021-20225: A heap out-of-bounds write vulnerability was found in the short form option parser.
CVE-2021-20233: A heap out-of-bound write flaw was found caused by mis-calculation of space required for quoting in the menu rendering.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556816</td>
<td>When ARP suppression is enabled, RARP packets sometimes get dropped and are not flooded by the local VTEP. 
To work around this issue, disable ARP suppression.</td>
<td>3.7.14-3.7.14.2, 4.3.0</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556783</td>
<td>CVE-2021-0326: An issue has been found in wpa, a set of tools to support WPA and WPA2 (IEEE 802.11i). Missing validation of data can result in a buffer over-write, which might lead to a DoS of the wpa_supplicant process or potentially arbitrary code execution.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.8.0-cl3.7.14u1, &lt;= 2.8.0-cl4.2.1u1</td>
<td>3.7.14-3.7.14.2, 4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556778</td>
<td>CVE-2021-26937: A  flaw in the handling of combining characters in screen, a terminal multiplexer with VT100/ANSI terminal emulation can result in denial of service, or potentially the execution of arbitrary code via a specially crafted UTF-8 character sequence.
Vulnerable: 4.6.2-3
Fixed: 4.6.2-3+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556776</td>
<td>CVE-2021-27212: A vulnerability in the Certificate List Exact Assertion validation was discovered in OpenLDAP, a free implementation of the Lightweight Directory Access Protocol. An unauthenticated remote attacker can take advantage of this flaw to cause a denial of service (slapd daemon crash) via specially crafted packets.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.4.47+dfsg-3+deb10u5
Fixed: 2.4.47+dfsg-3+deb10u6</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556775</td>
<td>DSA-4859-1 (no CVE): zstd, a compression utility, was vulnerable to a race condition: it temporarily exposed, during a very short timeframe, a world-readable version of its input even if the original file had restrictive permissions.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 1.3.8+dfsg-3+deb10u1
Fixed: 1.3.8+dfsg-3+deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556772</td>
<td>The {{net show clag verify-vlans}} command fails with the following log: 

WARNING: '/usr/bin/clagctl verifyvlans' failed due to:
Command '['/usr/bin/clagctl', 'verifyvlans']' returned non-zero exit status 1

To work around this issue, run the {{/usr/bin/clagctl verifyvlans}} command or the {{net show clag verbose}} command.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556764</td>
<td>In a configuration with both traditional and vlan-aware bridges, the VLAN membership check on a vlan-aware switch does not drop PVST BPBUs that come from a traditional bridge.</td>
<td>3.7.14-3.7.14.2, 4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>3.7.15-3.7.16, 4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556731</td>
<td>CVE-2020-8625: A buffer overflow vulnerability was discovered in the SPNEGO implementation affecting the GSSAPI security policy negotiation in BIND, a DNS server implementation, which could result in denial of service (daemon crash), or potentially the execution of arbitrary code.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 9.11.5.P4+dfsg-5.1+deb10u2
Fixed: 9.11.5.P4+dfsg-5.1+deb10u3</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556691</td>
<td>The following vulnerabilities have been announced in the openssl packages:
CVE-2021-23840: Calls to EVP_CipherUpdate, EVP_EncryptUpdate and EVP_DecryptUpdate may overflow the output length argument in some cases where the input length is close to the maximum permissable length for an integer on the platform. In such cases the return value from the function call will be 1 (indicating success), but the output length value will be negative. This could cause applications to behave incorrectly or crash.
CVE-2021-23841: The OpenSSL public API function X509_issuer_and_serial_hash() attempts to create a unique hash value based on the issuer and serial number data contained
within an X509 certificate. However it fails to correctly handle any errors that may occur while parsing the issuer field (which might occur if the issuer field is maliciously constructed). This may subsequently result in a NULL pointer deref and a crash leading to a potential denial of service attack.
CVE-2019-1551: There is an overflow bug in the x64_64 Montgomery squaring procedure used in exponentiation with 512-bit moduli. No EC algorithms are affected. Analysis suggests that attacks against 2-prime RSA1024, 3-prime RSA1536, and DSA1024 as a result of this defect would be very difficult to perform and are not believed likely. Attacks against DH512 are considered just feasible. However, for an attack the target would have to re-use the DH512 private key, which is not recommended anyway. Also applications directly using the low level API BN_mod_exp may be affected if they use BN_FLG_CONSTTIME.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 1.1.1d-0+deb10u4
Fixed: 1.1.1d-0+deb10u5</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556659</td>
<td>CVE-2020-35498: A vulnerability was found in openvswitch. A limitation in the implementation of userspace packet parsing can allow a malicious user to send a specially crafted packet causing the resulting megaflow in the kernel to be too wide, potentially causing a denial of service. The highest threat from this vulnerability is to system availability.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.8.90-1-cl4u5
Fixed: 2.8.90-1-cl4u6, 2.8.90-1-cl4.4.0u1, 2.8.90-1-cl5.0.0u8</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3, 5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556591</td>
<td>After upgrading to Cumulus Linux, MLAG ports might remain down with {{clagctl}} and {{net show clag}} reporting {{bridge-priority-mismatch}}.
To work around this issue, run the {{sudo ifreload -a}} command on both peers, or configure {{bridge-bridgeprio}} to be the same value as {{mstpctl-treeprio}} on the bridge interface in the {{/etc/network/interfaces}} file, then run {{sudo ifreload -a}}.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556569</td>
<td>DSA-4850-1 (no CVE): libzstd adds read permissions to files while being compressed or uncompressed.
Vulnerable: 1.3.8+dfsg-3
Fixed: 1.3.8+dfsg-3+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556500</td>
<td>Cumulus Linux does not support bond members at 200G or greater.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556474</td>
<td>CVE-2020-25681 CVE-2020-25682 CVE-2020-25683 CVE-2020-25684 CVE-2020-25685 CVE-2020-25686 CVE-2020-25687: Several vulnerabilities in dnsmasq, a small caching DNS proxy and DHCP/TFTP server, could result in denial of service, cache poisoning or the execution of arbitrary code.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556462</td>
<td> When you remove a fan tray, {{smonctl}} and {{sensors}} display different information about the removed fans.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556456</td>
<td>CVE-2020-36221, CVE-2020-36222, CVE-2020-36223, CVE-2020-36224, CVE-2020-36225, CVE-2020-36226, CVE-2020-36227, CVE-2020-36228, CVE-2020-36229, CVE-2020-36230:  Several vulnerabilities were discovered in OpenLDAP, a free implementation of the Lightweight Directory Access Protocol. An unauthenticated remote attacker can take advantage of these flaws to cause a denial of service (slapd daemon crash, infinite loops) via specially crafted packets.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.4.47+dfsg-3+deb10u4
Fixed: 2.4.47+dfsg-3+deb10u5</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556369</td>
<td>If you use NCLU to configure an ACL for eth0, you can't designate it as an INPUT rule; the rule is automatically created as a FORWARD rule in the {{/etc/cumulus/acl/policy.d/50_nclu_acl.rules}} file.
To work around this issue, manually create an ACL in the {{/etc/cumulus/acl/policy.d/}} file with "-A INPUT -i eth0".</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556353</td>
<td>You can enable and disable debugs from either exec mode or global configuration mode (config t) in vtysh. When disabling OSPF debugs from exec mode, the debug is disabled at runtime but left in the running configuration.
To work around this issue, disable OSPF debugs from global configuration mode.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556249</td>
<td>On a Mellanox switch configured with the {{max acl-heavy}} or {{ip-acl-heavy}} profile, the {{cl-resource-query -j}} command takes a long time to run.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556082</td>
<td>The NCLU {{net del vrf}} command does not delete a numbered VRF. For example:

cumulus@leaf01:~$ net del vrf 55
ERROR: Command not found
</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556081</td>
<td>You cannot set the time zone can with NCLU commands.</td>
<td>4.1.1-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555932</td>
<td>On Mellanox switches, you can't ping the SVI of the MLAG peer over the peer link after the packet is VXLAN decapsulated.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555873</td>
<td>On Mellanox switches, egress ACLs with VLAN keys do not filter layer 2 multicast or broadcast traffic.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555763</td>
<td>The NCLU {{net del bgp neighbor}} command does not delete the neighbor and displays an error similar to the following:

ERROR: --- /run/nclu/frr/frr.conf.scratchpad.baseline   2021-01-04 17:23:59.250463331 +0000
+++ /run/nclu/frr/frr.conf.scratchpad    2021-01-04 17:25:59.213673980 +0000

To work around this issue, use the FRR command to delete a neighbor.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555613</td>
<td>The {{net show configuration commands}} command incorrectly displays the NCLU syntax to disable IPv6 forwarding on interfaces. For example:

# net show configuration commands
net add vlan 1 ip6-forward off 

The correct NCLU command to disable IPv6 forwarding is {{net add vlan 1 ipv6 forward off}} (without the hyphen).</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555318</td>
<td>If you try to enable BGP graceful restart when it is already enabled, you see an error similar to the following in the {{frr.log}} file:

2020-12-07T19:20:26.004333+00:00 cumulus bgpd[4954]: VRF default: Handle GR command GLOBAL_GR_CMD, current GR state GLOBAL_GR, new GR state GLOBAL_INVALID

This error has no functional impact.</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554986</td>
<td>The {{ethtool}} utility doesn't contain the latest values, as a result the {{Revision Compliance}} field shows {{Unallocated}}. </td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554812</td>
<td>If the RMAC of a layer 3 SVI changes, the {{show vrf vni}} command is not updated with the new value. However, the new RMAC is seen in the {{show evpn vni}} command and is present on self-originated EVPN routes.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554798</td>
<td>On the Mellanox SN3700C switch, PIM multicast packets are duplicated at the egress VTEP.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554783</td>
<td>If you apply an outbound route map to a BGP peer that uses {{set as-path prepend last-as}}, advertised locally-originated routes have the ASN of the peer prepended to the AS path.
This might trigger AS path loop prevention on the peer, where the peer ignores locally-originated prefixes.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554709</td>
<td>The IP address specified in the {{ip pim use-source}} command configured on the loopback interface should be inherited by unnumbered interfaces during their Primary IP address selection process.  If {{ip pim use-source}} is configured on the loopback after an unnumbered interface has already selected their Primary IP address, the unnumbered interface does not update its Primary IP address to be the new use-source value until after there is a netlink update for that interface.
To work around this issue, configure {{ip pim use-source}} on each unnumbered interface directly or ensure {{ip pim use-source}} is applied to the loopback before other unnumbered interfaces are enabled for PIM.</td>
<td>3.7.13-3.7.16, 4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554670</td>
<td>When you have a large number of ACLs, the {{cl-acltool -L ip}} and {{cl-resource-query}} commands take a long time to complete.</td>
<td>4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554582</td>
<td>On switches with the Maverick ASIC, control traffic is dropped due to receive buffering.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554533</td>
<td>On the ARM platform, NTP peer associations slowly increase to larger offsets (~500ms).</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554466</td>
<td>Kernel routes added by {{iproute2}} are missing in FRR after an interface flap.
To work around this issue, configure a static route in FRR.
</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554299</td>
<td>In a VRRP configuration, BGP unnumbered sessions for VRFs fail to establish after a networking restart.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554261</td>
<td>On Broadcom switches, when you create a VNI interface, switchd might crash with the following log message: 

   {{switchd[6628]: log.c:72 CRIT backend/bcm/hal_bcm_vxlan.c:1285: &lt;unknown&gt;: Assertion &apos;0' failed.}}</td>
<td>4.3.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554222</td>
<td>The NCLU command to enable bridge learning fails.
As a work around, enable bridge learning in the {{/etc/network/interface}} file. For example:

auto vni-30
iface vni-30
    vxlan-id 30
    bridge-access 30
    bridge-arp-nd-suppress on
    bridge-learning on
    vxlan-local-tunnelip 10.10.10.1
    mstpctl-bpduguard yes
    mstpctl-portbpdufilter yes
    mtu 9166
</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554218</td>
<td>MLAG packets received on the peer link are dropped instead of routed.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554202</td>
<td>The output of the {{net show commit}} command does not show the last commit or the specified commit number but is empty instead.</td>
<td>4.2.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553887</td>
<td>When using TACACS+ configured with a DEFAULT user providing privilege level lower than 16, TACACS+ configured users with privilege level 16 access might not be able to run privilege level 16 NCLU commands, such as {{net add}} and {{net del}} and see an error similar to the following:

ERROR: You do not have permission to execute that command.

To work around this issue, remove the DEFAULT user from the TACACS+ server.</td>
<td>3.7.7-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553677</td>
<td>When you configure an SNMPv3 user with the {{net-snmp-config}} configuration command from the {{libsnmp-dev}} package, you get an error message similar to the one below:

cumulus@switch:mgmt-vrf:~$ sudo net-snmp-config --create-snmpv3-user -a shaauthpass -x aesprivpass -A SHA -X AES userSHAwithAES
adding the following line to /var/lib/snmp/snmpd.conf:           
   createUser userSHAwithAES SHA "shaauthpass" AES "aesprivpass"       
adding the following line to /snmp/snmpd.conf:                           
   rwuser userSHAwithAES                                           
touch: cannot touch ‘/snmp/snmpd.conf’: No such file or directory
/usr/bin/net-snmp-create-v3-user: 144: /usr/bin/net-snmp-create-v3-user: cannot create /snmp/snmpd.conf: Directory nonexistent

To work around this issue, use the NCLU command to configure SNMPv3 user parameters; for example:

cumulus@switch:mgmt-vrf:~$ net add snmp-server username user999 auth-md5 user999password encrypt-des user999encryption

Alternatively, directly edit the {{/etc/snmp/snmpd.conf}} file as described in the documentation.</td>
<td>3.7.13-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553237</td>
<td>The default NTP configuration is to use eth0 as the NTP source interface. In Cumulus Linux 4.0 and later, eth0 is in the management VRF by default; therefore the NTP service runs automatically in the management VRF. 
NVIDIA does not recommend running NTP with a source interface other than eth0 as this can expose a security vulnerability. Changing the NTP source interface name with NCLU to a non-management VRF interface might result in NTP not functioning because the NTP service is still running in the management VRF.

</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553116</td>
<td>When you manually set the link speed or duplex mode with ethtool to an unsupported value, then run a TDR check against the interface, you encounter a {{switchd}} service heartbeat failure.
To work around this issue, reboot the switch to clear the condition. Avoid setting the interface speed or duplex mode directly with ethtool.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553015</td>
<td>If a neighbour contains a special character in PortID for LLDP, the {{net show interface}} command does not display the LLDP information or the command might fail.</td>
<td>3.7.10-3.7.16, 4.2.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552739</td>
<td>Counters for IPROUTER rules do not increase when traffic is forwarded to the CPU because there is no IP neighbor.</td>
<td>3.7.2-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552691</td>
<td>On the EdgeCore AS4610 switch, the eth0 interface remains down when physically connected to a 1G interface.
To work around this issue, configure the link speed to 1000 and set auto-negotiation on for the eth0 interface, then flap eth0 with the {{ip link set eth0 down/up}} command to bring up the port.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552453</td>
<td>On the Mellanox switch, RoCE with PFC configuration is not applied to all ports in hardware when a range is used in the {{traffic.conf}} file.
To work around this issue, use NCLU to configure RoCE with PFC or list individual ports in the {{traffic.conf}} file.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552309</td>
<td>The following messages are seen on an Edgecord Minipack-AS8000 running Cumulus Linux 4.2.0:

{code}
Hal_bcm_console.c:294 MMU config profile 0 prigroup 0: Service Pool 0 has no space and cannot be assigned
Hal_bcm_console.c:294 MMU config port 0 idx 0: Pool 0 has no space and cannot be assigned
{code}

These messages are for internal validation purposes only and can be safely ignored.

</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552294</td>
<td>NCLU restarts FRR when removing a BGP VRF IPv4 aggregate-address command.
 </td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552266</td>
<td>OpenSSH scp is vulnerable to CVE-2020-15778, where clients that have authorized access to the SSH server can execute commands on the server by copying maliciously named files.
The two scenarios where an exploit may be useful to an attacker:
-The user is authorized to {{scp}} but not {{ssh}} (based on the {{command}} option in the {{authorized_keys}} file), so this vulnerability can allow executing a remote command on the target computer when not authorized to do so.
-An attacker plants a maliciously named file in a directory tree that someone later uses {{scp -r}} to copy over to the target computer.
Be aware that restricting users to {{scp}} by using the {{command}} option in the {{authorized_keys}} file is not effective in preventing those users from executing arbitrary commands on the server.
If you want to use {{scp -r}} to copy directory trees, avoid copying directory trees to which attackers may have added maliciously-named files. Archiving the directory tree with {{tar}}, {{zip}}, or a similar program, then copying the archive over to be extracted on the server avoids having to use {{scp -r}} altogether. In addition, OpenSSH provides {{sftp}}, which you can use instead of {{scp}} to copy files.
To disable scp completely, use {{/bin/chmod 0 /usr/bin/scp}} .</td>
<td>3.7.14-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552212</td>
<td>The Mellanox SN2700 and SN2410 switch intermittently reports PSU fan state changes with {{Unable to read from device/fan1_input/pwm1}} syslog messages.</td>
<td>3.7.11-3.7.14, 4.1.1-4.3.0</td>
<td>3.7.14.2-3.7.16, 4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2551666</td>
<td>If you modify an interface name, then reuse the previous interface name for a different VLAN, the {{ifreload -a}} command generates an error similar to the following:

warning: &lt;interface-name&gt;: interface not recognized - please check interface configuration

</td>
<td>4.1.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2551578</td>
<td>When you configure a bridge in the {{/etc/network/interfaces}} file, then try to reconfigure the bridge to be a VRF interface with the same name, {{ifreload}}/{{ifup}} commands fail with an {{invalid table id}} or {{unable to get vrf table id}} error.</td>
<td>3.7.12-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2551565</td>
<td>If you toggle VRRP priority values between VRRP routers, then restart {{switchd}}, a few IPv6 VRRP instances might not converge. As a result, both the VRRP routers act as master routers for the impacted IPv6 VRRP instances. IPv4 VRRP instances are not affected.
To work around this issue, remove, then add back the VRRP configuration with NCLU or vtysh commands.</td>
<td>3.7.13-3.7.16, 4.2.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2551335</td>
<td>When TACACS+ is configured and the management VRF is enabled, users with privilege level 13 are prevented from running {{ip}} and {{cat}} commands.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2551305</td>
<td>The {{net show configuration}} command provides the wrong {{net add}} command for ACL under the VLAN interface.

</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.1.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2551273</td>
<td>On a Mellanox SN2010 switch, the Locator LED is on after you upgrade Cumulus Linux.</td>
<td>4.1.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550974</td>
<td>On the Dell S3000 switch, after installing the Cumulus Linux 4.1.1 disk image without a license, the switch sends a link beat if a remote host port is configured.</td>
<td>3.7.11-3.7.16, 4.1.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550793</td>
<td>The NCLU {{net show bridge spanning-tree}} command displays the aging timer incorrectly. </td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550713</td>
<td>Configuring the subinterface of a VXLAN uplink under another traditional bridge, which also has the VXLAN VNI enslaved, causes {{switchd}} to use high CPU due to very frequent VXLAN tunnel sync events.
To work around this issue, do not enslave the subinterface of a VXLAN layer 3 uplink under a traditional bridge in a VXLAN configuration.</td>
<td>4.1.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550704</td>
<td>On the Mellanox SN3420 switch, 25G SR optics only link up in force mode.</td>
<td>4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550444</td>
<td>Tab completion for the {{net show rollback description}} command returns information about a snapshot instead of context help.
To work around this issue, run the {{net show commit history}} command to find descriptions instead of the {{net show rollback description}} command.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550443</td>
<td>The {{net show rollback description &lt;string&gt;}} command returns an error even if the string matches a commit description.
To work around this issue, look for your string in the output of the {{net show commit history}} command (or grep for it there) instead.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550243</td>
<td>When you use {{nginx}} and {{restserver}} in management VRF to provide a REST API for the switch, {{nginx}} starts but {{restserver}} fails to start.
To work around this issue, comment out the {{Requires=}} line in the {{/lib/systemd/system/restserver.service}}. For example:

#Requires=nginx.service restserver.socket
</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550056</td>
<td>The ACCTON-DIAG option under the Cumulus Linux GRUB menu does not work. When you select this option, you see the following error:

error: invalid signature.
Press any key to continue...
</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.1.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2549925</td>
<td>When you run an Ansible script to replace the {{/etc/network/interfaces}} file, then run the {{ifreload -a}} command, you see errors similar to the following:

error: swp1s1.2: netlink: cannot set link swp1s1.2 up: operation failed with 'Network is down' (100)
warning: cmd '/bin/ip addr del 10.0.0.1/24 dev eth0' failed: returned 2 (RTNETLINK answers: Cannot assign requested address

To work around this issue,  run the {{ifreload -a}} command a second time.</td>
<td>3.7.12-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2549872</td>
<td>If you have an SVI with multiple VRR IP addresses and try to delete one of the VRR configurations, {{net commit}} or {{ifreload -a}} returns an error.</td>
<td>3.7.12-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2549782</td>
<td>The JSON format output of the {{net show bgp l2vpn evpn summary}} command shows the incorrect neighbour state. </td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2549731</td>
<td>When you create SPAN or ERSPAN rules in ebtables, the action fails to install if it is not in lowercase. Make sure that the SPAN or ERSPAN action is all lowercase; for example:

[ebtables]
-A FORWARD --in-interface swp10 -j span --dport swp1
</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.1.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2549392</td>
<td>When you configure an RD or RT with NCLU, you see duplicate VNI stanzas in the {{/etc/frr/frr.conf}} file. 
To work around this issue, manually edit the {{etc/frr/frr.conf}} file to define {{advertise-all-vni}} before the RD or RT configuration within the l2vpn EVPN address family, then reload the FRR service with the {{sudo systemctl reload frr}} command.</td>
<td>4.1.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2549371</td>
<td>When Optimized Multicast Flooding (OMF) is enabled with the {{bridge.optimized_mcast_flood = TRUE}} setting in the {{/etc/cumulus/switchd.conf}} file, the switch continues to flood IPv6 multicast traffic to all slave ports when there is no MLD join receive.</td>
<td>3.7.11-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2548924</td>
<td>On the EdgeCore Minipack AS8000, storm control does not restrict unknown unicast, broadcast, or multicast traffic.</td>
<td>4.1.1-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2548315</td>
<td>The following security advisory has been announced for bash: 
CVE-2019-18276 Qualys scan QID 372268 setuid vulnerability
When bash or bash scripts are run setuid, bash is supposed to drop privileges, but does so incorrectly, so that an attacker with command access to the shell can use {{enable -f}} for runtime loading of a new builtin that calls {{setuid()}} to regain dropped privileges.
To work around this issue, do not make bash or bash scripts {{setuid}}.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2548260</td>
<td>The {{net add routing route-map &lt;name&gt; permit &lt;seq&gt; set community &lt;comm&gt;}} command does not add the set statement into the {{/etc/frr/frr.conf}} file.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2548243</td>
<td>On switches with the Trident2+ ASIC, adding SPAN rules disables PBR rules.</td>
<td>3.7.3-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2548117</td>
<td>In OVSDB traditional bridge mode, adding or removing a VLAN binding causes a traffic forwarding outage for around 20 seconds or more on adjacent VLAN bindings. Cumulus Linux does not support _traditional_ bridge mode with VMware NSX.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2548062</td>
<td>When ports are split to 4x25G, RS FEC needs to explicitly configured on both ends (especially when interoperating with non-Mellanox switches).</td>
<td>4.1.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2548044</td>
<td>When a remote VTEP withdraws a type-3 EVPN route, Cumulus Linux purges all MAC address and neighbor entries installed in the corresponding layer 2 VNI through that remote VTEP from the local EVPN and kernel forwarding tables. This purge occurs even if the remote VTEP does not withdraw type-2 routes carrying the MAC address or neighbor entries. The entries stay missing from the local EVPN and kernel forwarding tables until BGP updates the MAC address and neighbor.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.15, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2547903</td>
<td>CVE-2019-19956: xmlParseBalancedChunkMemoryRecover in parser.c in libxml2 before 2.9.10 has a memory leak related to newDoc-&gt;oldNs.
Vulnerable: 2.9.4+dfsg1-7
Fixed: 2.9.4+dfsg1-7+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2547890</td>
<td>QinQ across VXLAN on a traditional bridge does not work.</td>
<td>4.1.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2547706</td>
<td>When you configure ganged ports in the {{ports.conf}} file, the change does not take effect after you restart {{switchd}}. 
To work around this issue, reboot the switch.</td>
<td>3.7.11-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2547405</td>
<td>When you restart the {{hsflowd}} service, you see a {{systemd}} warning message similar to the following:

Warning: The unit file, source configuration file or drop-ins of hsflowd@mgmt.service changed on disk. Run 'systemctl daemon-reload'.
</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2546991</td>
<td>The FRR service does not provide a way for automation to know if the configuration applied properly.
To work around this issue, execute the {{vtysh -f &lt;file&gt;}} command in the automation file before starting the FRR service to validate the functional configuration and return an error code.</td>
<td>3.7.11-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2546895</td>
<td>If you have configured a higher number of ports and VLANs (ports x VLANs) or the switch is a lower-powered (CPU) platform, the {{switchd}} service might fail to send a {{systemd keepalive}} within the watchdog timeout value (2 minutes by default) and you see an error similar to the following:

bq. systemd[1]: switchd.service watchdog timeout (limit 2min)!

To workaround this issue, either reduce the number of configured interfaces and, or VLANs, or increase the {{systemd}} timeout for {{switchd.service}}.
To increase the {{systemd}} timeout:

1.Edit the {{/etc/systemd/system/switchd.service.d/override.conf}} file and increase the {{WatchdogSec}} parameter.
2.Restart the {{switchd}} service with the {{sudo systemctl restart switchd.service}} command.
{{systemd}} attempts to restart the {{switchd}} service automatically (after the watchdog timeout). If the restart fails multiple times in a short time period, run the {{sudo systemctl reset-failed}} command followed by the {{sudo systemctl restart switchd}} command.</td>
<td>3.7.11-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2546874</td>
<td>On the Dell S5232F, S5248F, S5296F, and S3048 switch, using the {{poweroff}} or {{halt}} commands does not fully power off the switch.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2545837</td>
<td>If you use the NCLU commands to configure NTP and run the {{net add time ntp source &lt;interface&gt;}} command before you run the {{net add time ntp server &lt;server&gt; iburst}} command, the {{/etc/ntp.conf}} file is misconfigured.
To work around this issue, run the {{net add time ntp server &lt;server&gt; iburst}} command before you run the {{net add time ntp source &lt;interface&gt;}} command.</td>
<td>3.7.10-3.7.11, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2545520</td>
<td>The length of the netlink message is not set properly for non-bridge family type messages. The same length is used for both bridge and non-bridge even though the bridge family type message has an extra attribute. This causes extra bytes to be left over in non-bridge family type netlink messages.</td>
<td>3.7.10, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.11-3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2545239</td>
<td>On the Mellanox switch with the Spectrum-2 ASIC, Precision Time Protocol (PTP) is not currently supported. </td>
<td>4.0.0-4.3.0</td>
<td>4.4.0-4.4.3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2545233</td>
<td>On the Delta AG9032v1 switch, smonctl and sensors report inaccurate PSU current and power.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2545125</td>
<td>If you configure more than one VRR interface on an SVI interface, deleting one of the VRR addresses does not remove the interface/address. </td>
<td>3.7.10-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2544978</td>
<td>If you delete an undefined bond, then add a bond slave, the {{net commit}} command fails.</td>
<td>3.7.9-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2544968</td>
<td>FRR configuration commands for an SVI interface might have the {{\n}} misplaced in the output.  For example:

sudo sh -c "printf 'interface 50\nvrf TEST description L3 routing interface\n' &gt;&gt; /etc/frr/frr.conf"

should be:

sudo sh -c "printf 'interface 50 vrf TEST\ndescription L3 routing interface\n' &gt;&gt; /etc/frr/frr.conf"

To work around this issue, configure the interface manually in the {{/etc/frr/frr.conf}} file.</td>
<td>3.7.9-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2544957</td>
<td>NCLU incorrectly allows you to apply port security configuration on layer 2 and layer 3 ports that are not part of a bridge.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2544953</td>
<td>When you update the hostname of a switch with the NCLU {{net add hostname &lt;hostname&gt;}} command, then run {{net commit}}, the {{lldpd}} service does not restart and other devices still see the old hostname.
To work around this issue, run the {{sudo systemctl restart lldpd.service}} command.</td>
<td>3.7.10-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2544880</td>
<td>When you run the NCLU {{net show commit last}} or {{net show commit &lt;number&gt;}} command, where {{&lt;number&gt;}} is the last commit, no output is shown. </td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2544723</td>
<td>Setting ProtoDown on ports populated with SFP modules providing RJ-45 1000BASE-T interfaces does not cause the carrier to be dropped. The kernel shows carrier down; however, the remote device still shows a link.</td>
<td>3.7.6-3.7.10, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.11-3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2544463</td>
<td>Auto-negotiation does not work with the QSFP28 cables and a remote system operating at 10G. Attempting to enable auto-negotiation with {{ethtool -s swp&lt;#&gt; autoneg on}} returns {{Operation not supported}}.
To work around this issue, do not use auto-negotiation and set the local port speed to 10G.</td>
<td>3.7.9-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2544456</td>
<td>The NCLU {{net show lldp}} command displays the speed of a ganged port group as the speed of one of the individual links, rather than the sum of their speeds.</td>
<td>3.7.9-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2544311</td>
<td>Applying a policy-based routing (PBR) rule for all traffic from a host might disrupt ARP refresh for that connected host.</td>
<td>3.7.5-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2544155</td>
<td>NCLU requires you to specify an interface with multiple {{address-virtual}} statements in ascending MAC address order. 

</td>
<td>3.7.5-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2544113</td>
<td>Mac learning is not disabled by default on a double tagged peer link interface resulting in the MAC address changing between the MLAG bond and the peer link.
To work around this issue, disable MAC learning on QinQ VLANs by adding {{bridge-learning off}} to the VLAN stanza in the {{etc/network/interfaces}} file.</td>
<td>3.7.9-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2543937</td>
<td>An interface alias configured outside FRR using {{iproute2}} is imported into the FRR running configuration and overrides the internal description. After an FRR reload, this causes FRR to delete the interface alias in an inefficient way. Depending on how many interfaces with aliases you have configured, this can cause a FRR reload to time out.
To work around this issue, remove the interface alias description from {{iproute2}}.</td>
<td>3.7.8-3.7.10, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.11-3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2543900</td>
<td>On the Mellanox switch, static VXLAN tunnels incorrectly allow traffic from any remote tunnel IP address.</td>
<td>3.7.8-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2543841</td>
<td>The {{net show evpn vni detail json}} command includes an extra empty dictionary at the end of the output. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.8-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2543816</td>
<td>On the Dell S5248F-ON switch, {{smond}} might generate syslog messages indicating that the fan input RPM is lower than the normal low speed of 2500 RPM. Speeds as low as 1700 RPM are acceptable in normal thermal environments; therefore, you can ignore these messages.
</td>
<td>3.7.6-3.7.11, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2543781</td>
<td>NCLU does not allow you to configure OSPF NSSAs. For example: 

cumulus@switch:~$ net add ospf area 0.0.0.1 nssa 
ERROR: Command not found. 
net add ospf area 0.0.0.1 nssa

To work around this issue, use FRR instead. For example: 

switch# configure terminal 
switch(config)# router ospf 
switch(config-router)# area 0.0.0.1 nssa 
</td>
<td>3.7.7-3.7.10, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.11-3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2543724</td>
<td>If a hostname contains utf-8 characters, the NCLU {{net show lldp}} command outputs the following error: 

ERROR: 'ascii' codec can't encode character u'\xe9' in position 3: ordinal not in range(128) 
See /var/log/netd.log for more details.  
</td>
<td>3.7.7-3.7.10, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.11-3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2543646</td>
<td>In an ebtables rule, ERSPAN (upper case) does not work. You need to specify erspan (lower case).</td>
<td>3.7.6-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2543211</td>
<td>In some cases, the {{switchd}} service might warn of excessive MAC moves from one switch port to itself (for example, from swp18 to swp18).
</td>
<td>3.7.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>5.0.0-5.1.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2543164</td>
<td>The MTU of an SVI cannot be higher than the MTU on the bridge. Changing the MTU on the SVI with NCLU does not update the bridge MTU. The {{net commit}} command succeeds even though the MTU is not changed as expected.
To work around this issue, change the MTU on all SVIs and the bridge manually in the {{/etc/network/interfaces}} file, then apply the change with the {{ifreload -a}} command.</td>
<td>3.7.7-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2543096</td>
<td>When an SVI with a virtual MAC is configured with a layer 2 VNI in an EVPN environment, if you replace the {{/etc/network/interfaces}} file with a different file that does not have the SVI and layer 2 VNI configuration, the original virtual MAC is not populated through the EVPN route until FRR is restarted. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.6-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2542945</td>
<td>On the Broadcom Maverick switch with a QinQ configuration, the packets coming into the CPU might be tagged incorrectly; for example, 802.1ad + 802.1q tags are expected in the packets but the packets have 802.1q + 802.1q tags. 
To work around this issue, configure the bridge with {{bridge-vlan-protocol 802.1ad}}: 

cumulus@switch:~$ net add bridge mybridge vlan-protocol 802.1ad 
 </td>
<td>3.7.6-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2542837</td>
<td>On Mellanox switches, policer iptables are not working as expected. For example, when using a policer with mode KB/MB/GB to rate-limit interfaces, the syntax is accepted but the data plane transfer speed is not affected by the rule. </td>
<td>3.7.6-3.7.8, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.9-3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2542305</td>
<td>If an SVI exists in the configuration before you assign it an IP address, when you do assign the IP address with the NCLU command, the {{vlan-id}} and the raw-device bridge stanzas are not added automatically. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.6-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2542301</td>
<td>When first creating a bond and enslaving an interface, NCLU hides some of the bridge command suggestions, although they are still accepted. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.3-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2541212</td>
<td>The {{maximum-prefix}} configuration under the IPv4 address family has an optional restart value, which you can configure. This configuration is ignored and, instead of restarting the sessions every x minutes, the peer constantly changes between established and idle due to the prefix count being exceeded. </td>
<td>3.7.5-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2541029</td>
<td>On switches with the Trident2 ASIC, 802.1Q-encapsulated control plane traffic received on an interface with 802.1AD configured subinterfaces might be dropped. 
This issue only affects QinQ configurations. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.5-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2540753</td>
<td>If the interface alias contains a single or double quotation mark, or an apostrophe, the {{net show configuration}} commands fail with the following error: 
  
 ERROR: No closing quotation 
 See /var/log/netd.log for more details. 
  
 </td>
<td>3.7.5-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2540444</td>
<td>SNMP incorrectly requires engine ID specification. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.4-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2540352</td>
<td>When you use NCLU to configure a route map, the parser allows for glob matching of interfaces for a _match interface_ condition when there can only be a single interface matched. The proper syntax is to use multiple route map clauses, each matching a single interface, instead of a single clause matching multiple interfaces. 
 For example, this command is incorrect: 
  
 net add routing route-map Proxy-ARP permit 25 match interface swp9-10 
  
 These commands are correct: 
  
 net add routing route-map Proxy-ARP permit 25 match interface swp9 
 net add routing route-map Proxy-ARP permit 30 match interface swp10 
  
 </td>
<td>3.7.2-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2540340</td>
<td>NCLU allows for the configuration of addresses on VRF interfaces, but tab completion for the {{net add vrf &lt;name&gt;}} command just displays &lt;ENTER&gt;. For example: 
  
 cumulus@switch:~$ net add vrf mgmt 
 &lt;ENTER&gt; 
  
 Tab completion for the {{net add vrf &lt;name&gt; ip address &lt;address&gt;}} command works correctly. </td>
<td>3.7.4-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2540274</td>
<td>On the Maverick switch, CPU forwarded packets might be dropped when there is no route to a leaked host route.</td>
<td>3.7.5-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2540204</td>
<td>When links come up after FRR is started, VRF connected routes do not get redistributed.</td>
<td>3.7.4-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2540192</td>
<td>The {{net del bridge bridge mcsnoop yes}} command does not return the value to the default of disabled. 
To work around this issue, use the {{net add bridge bridge mcsnoop no}} command to delete the {{mcsnoop attribute}} and return to the default value.</td>
<td>3.7.4-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2540155</td>
<td>On the Broadcom switch, when moving configuration from bridged to routed (or toggling from routed to bridged to routed), some traffic is not seen by the kernel. This can cause BGP to not establish on a transit node. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.3-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2540042</td>
<td>When you try to configure the VRRP priority and advertisement-interval with NCLU on a traditional mode bridge, the {{net commit}} command fails. 
 To work around this issue, use the vtysh command (inside FRR) to change the VRRP priority or advertisement-interval on traditional bridges. For example: 
  
 cumulus@switch:~$ sudo vtysh 
 switch# configure terminal 
 switch(config)# interface br0.100 
 switch(config-if)# vrrp 1 priority 110 
 switch(config-if)# vrrp 1 advertisement-interval 
 switch(config-if)# end 
 switch# write memory 
 switch# exit 
 cumulus@switch:~ 
  
 </td>
<td>3.7.4-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2540041</td>
<td>On SVIs in a VLAN-aware bridge, you cannot change the VRRP priority with NCLU. 
 To work around this issue, run the vtysh command inside FRR to change the default priority. For example: 
  
 cumulus@switch:~$ sudo vtysh 
 switch# configure terminal 
 switch(config)# interface vlan100 
 switch(config-if)# vrrp 1 priority 110 
 switch(config-if)# end 
 switch# write memory 
 switch# exit 
 cumulus@switch:~ 
  
 </td>
<td>3.7.4-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2540040</td>
<td>Cumulus Linux uses VRRPv3 as the default version, and enables both preempt and accept mode by default. You cannot change these default values with NCLU. 
To work around this issue, run the vtysh commands (inside FRR) to change the default values. For example: 
  
 cumulus@switch:~$ sudo vtysh 
 switch# configure terminal 
 switch(config)# interface swp4 
 switch(config-if)# vrrp 1 version 2 
 switch(config-if)# no vrrp 1 preempt 
 switch(config-if)# end 
 switch# write memory 
 switch# exit 
 cumulus@switch:~ 
  
 </td>
<td>3.7.4-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2540031</td>
<td>NCLU does not honor {{auto all}} in the {{/etc/network/interfaces}} file and removes the existing configuration if no individual {{auto &lt;iface&gt;}} lines exist. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.3-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2539994</td>
<td>When you try to remove a BGP peer group configuration with NCLU, the command fails but no warning message is shown. For example: 
 
cumulus@switch:~$ net del bgp neighbor fabric peer-group
'router bgp 65001' configuration does not have 'neighbor fabric peer-group' 
 
 </td>
<td>3.7.2-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2539962</td>
<td>When an LDAP user that does not have NCLU privileges (either in the {{netshow}} or {{netedit}} group, or in the {{/etc/netd.conf}} file) runs an NCLU command, a traceback occurs instead of a permissions error. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.0-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2539670</td>
<td>On the Edgecore 4610-54P switch, automatic medium-dependent interface crossover (auto-MDIX) stops working on a 100M full duplex interface and does not detect the required cable connection type. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.2-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2539124</td>
<td>The {{net add interface &lt;interface&gt; ptm-enable}} command adds {{no ptm-enable}} for that interface in the {{frr.conf}} file. 
 Running the {{net add}} or the {{net del}} command does not remove {{no ptm-enable}} from the {{frr.conf}} file. You have to remove it manually using vtysh. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.2-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2538790</td>
<td>NCLU automatically adds the VLAN ID (for the layer 3 VNI/SVI) to the bridge when you run {{net add vxlan &lt;layer3-vni&gt; bridge access &lt;vlan&gt;}}. This configuration breaks network connectivity in an EVPN symmetric routing configuration using MLAG. 
To restore connectivity, remove the VLAN ID from the bridge. </td>
<td>3.7.2-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2538590</td>
<td>When you configure a control plane ACL to define permit and deny rules destined to the local switch, NCLU programs the control plane ACL rules into the FORWARD chain. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.2-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2538562</td>
<td>On an RMP/1G-T switch, when you remove {{link-speed 100}} with the NCLU command or by editing the {{etc/network/interfaces}} file to revert the 100M interface to the default (1G auto), the interface fails to recover and does not come back up.
After you remove the link-speed, {{ethtool}} shows the advertised link modes as not reported and Speed/Duplex as unknown.
To work around this issue and bring the interface back up, either restart {{switchd}} or use ethtool to configure the speed, advertised, duplex or MDI-X settings. 
Note: The advertised link mode gets set incorrectly if you include 1000baseT/Half. The port will come up successfully at 1G.</td>
<td>3.7.2-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2538294</td>
<td>If you use NCLU to create an iBGP peering across the peer link, running the {{net add bgp l2vpn evpn neighbor peerlink.4094 activate}} command creates a new eBGP neighborship when one has already been configured for iBGP. This is unexpected; the existing iBGP configuration is valid. </td>
<td>3.7.0-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2537699</td>
<td>There is a limitation on the number of SVI interfaces you can specify as DHCP relay interfaces in the {{/etc/default/isc-dhcp-relay}} file. For example, 1500 SVI interfaces causes the {{dhcrelay}} service to exit without a core file and logs similar to the following are generated for the interfaces: 
  
 2018-11-10T23:35:30.992370-08:00 Dev dhcrelay: Listening on LPF/vlan.101/a0:00:00:00:00:51 
 2018-11-10T23:35:30.993472-08:00 Dev dhcrelay: Sending on LPF/vlan.101/a0:00:00:00:00:51 
  
 Eventually the {{dhcrelay}} service stops. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.1-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2536576</td>
<td>If you try to bring down several members of a bond remotely at the same time, the link state of one of the interfaces might not transition correctly to the down state; however, all links show down in hardware. 
 </td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2536384</td>
<td>The BFD packet redirection logic used by OVSDB server high availability mode redirects BUM packets across the peer link. The iptables rule for redirection does differentiate between BFD and non-BFD VXLAN inner packets because the service node sends all frames with its own IP address as the tunnel source IP address. The VXLAN encapsulated BUM packets do not get forwarded to the CPU and do not go through the iptable redirection rule; only VXLAN encapsulated BFD packets get forwarded to the CPU due to the inner MAC DA lookup in hardware. 
 </td>
<td>3.7.0-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2536256</td>
<td>For an unresolved address, the IPROUTER default policer rule has been modified to _not_ match on packets exiting a TUNNEL and headed to the CPU to resolve the address via ARP. As a result, the following default rule no longer matches TUNNEL ingress packets. 
  
 A $INGRESS_CHAIN --in-interface $INGRESS_INTF -m addrtype --dst-type 
 IPROUTER -j POLICE --set-mode pkt --set-rate 400 --set-burst 100 
  
 These packets are now policed by catch all rules. 
 To work around this issue, the VPORT value on a TRIDENT switch must be changed from binary 011 to 100. 
 </td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2536242</td>
<td>On the EdgeCore AS7712 (Tomahawk) switch running in atomic mode, when a layer 3 ECMP path is brought down, traffic traversing the path stops working for about four seconds. When the switch is changed to non-atomic mode, the delay is less than one second. This issue is seen across OSPF and static ECMP routes. </td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2536179</td>
<td>On switches with the Trident 2+ ASIC, counters associated with VLANs and VRFs are not working.</td>
<td>3.7.0-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2535986</td>
<td>At a high CPU transmit traffic rate (for example, if there is unexpected CPU generated flooding or replication in software), when the ASIC packet driver cannot keep up with the transmit rate because there are no free DMA buffers, it can back pressure by suspending the switch port transmit queues. This can fill up the application socket buffers resulting in {{No buffer space available}} error messages on protocol sockets.
When the driver recovers, it automatically resumes the transmit queues. In most cases these error messages are transient. In rare cases, the hardware queues might get stuck, which you can recover with a {{switchd}} restart.</td>
<td>3.7.0-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2535965</td>
<td>On the Trident3 switch, static PIM with IIF based on a layer 2 bridge does not work reliably. PIM Join via signaling is required for IPMC to work properly.
To work around this issue, use dynamic signaling (joins) to manage IP multicast traffic.</td>
<td>3.7.0-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2535723</td>
<td>The source address of the ICMPv6 time exceeded message (traceroute hop) is sourced from the wrong VRF when the traceroute target resides on the same switch but in a different VRF.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2535605</td>
<td>FRR does not add BGP {{ttl-security}} to either the running configuration or to the {{/etc/frr/frr.conf}} file when configured on a peer group instead of a specific neighbor. 
To work around this issue, add {{ttl-security}} to individual neighbors instead of the peer group.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2535209</td>
<td>The {{net show lldp}} command sometimes shows the port description in the {{Remote Port}} field. The {{net show interface}} command shows the correct value in the {{Remote Host}} field.
To work around this issue, use {{net show interface}} command for LLDP output when connected to Cisco equipment.</td>
<td>3.7.5-3.7.10, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td>3.7.11-3.7.16</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2534734</td>
<td>Span rules matching the out-interface as a bond do not mirror packets.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2533691</td>
<td>If you configure a VLAN under a VLAN-aware bridge and create a subinterface of the same VLAN on one of the bridge ports, the bridge and interface compete for the same VLAN and if the interface is flapped, it stops working. Correcting the configuration and running the {{ifreload}} command does not resolve the conflict. 
To work around this issue, correct the bridge VIDs and restart {{switchd}} or delete the subinterface. </td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.16, 4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2533625</td>
<td>PIM and MSDP entries are set to the internal COS value of 6 so they are grouped together with the bulk traffic priority group in the default {{traffic.conf}} file. However, PIM, IGMP, and MSDP are considered control-plane and should be set to the internal COS value of 7. </td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2533337</td>
<td>When you use NCLU to bring a bond admin down ({{net add bond &lt;bond&gt; link down}}), the bond interface goes into admin down state but the switch ports enslaved to the bond remain UP. If you are using bond-lacp-bypass-allow or balance-xor mode, the host might continue to send traffic. This traffic will be dropped because although the bond slaves are UP, they are not members of the bridge.
To work around this issue, use the {{sudo ifdown &lt;bondname&gt;}} command.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2531273</td>
<td>In certain cases, a peer device sends an ARP request from a source IP address that is not on the connected subnet and the switch creates a STALE neighbor entry. Eventually, the switch attempts to keep the entry fresh and sends ARP requests to the host. If the host responds, the switch has REACHABLE neighbor entries for hosts that are not on the connected subnet. 
To work around this issue, change the value of {{arp_ignore}} to 2. See [Address Resolution Protocol in the Cumulus Linux user guide|https://docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-linux/Layer-3/Address-Resolution-Protocol-ARP/] for more information.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.4.3</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</table>
<table name="Fixed Issues in 4.3.0">
<tr>
<th> Issue ID </th>
<th> Description </th>
<th> Affects </th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556334</td>
<td>On the Mellanox SN-4700 switch, when you use a 2x100G configuration, the links do not come up.</td>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556279</td>
<td>CVE-2021-3156: A serious heap-based buffer overflow has been discovered in sudo that is exploitable by any local user. It has been given the name Baron Samedit by its discoverer. The bug can be leveraged to elevate privileges to root, even if the user is not listed in the sudoers file. User authentication is not required to exploit the bug.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 1.8.27-1+deb10u2
Fixed: 1.8.27-1+deb10u3</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556217</td>
<td>The following vulnerability affects lldpd:
CVE-2020-27827: A packet that contains multiple instances of certain TLVs will cause lldpd to continually allocate memory and leak the old memory.  As an example, multiple instances of system name TLV will cause old values to be dropped by the decoding routine.
Fixed: 1.0.4-0-cl4.3.0u2</td>
<td>3.7.14-3.7.14.2, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556215</td>
<td>When you run any of the vtysh {{show bgp ipv4}} or {{show bgp ipv6}} statistics commands, the {{bgpd}} service crashes.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2556010</td>
<td>On Broadcom switches, after repeated VLAN or VXLAN configuration changes, {{switchd}} memory might not free up appropriately, which can lead to a crash. </td>
<td>3.7.14, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555761</td>
<td>The following vulnerabilities were announced in the p11-kit (libp11-kit0) packages:
CVE-2020-29361: Multiple integer overflows have been discovered in the array allocations in the p11-kit library and the p11-kit list command, where overflow checks are missing before calling realloc or calloc.
CVE-2020-29362: A heap-based buffer over-read has been discovered in the RPC protocol used by thep11-kit server/remote commands and the client library. When the remote entity supplies a byte array through a serialized PKCS#11 function call, the receiving entity may allow the reading of up to 4 bytes of memory past the heap allocation.
CVE-2020-29363: A heap-based buffer overflow has been discovered in the RPC protocol used by p11-kit server/remote commands and the client library. When the remote entity supplies a serialized byte array in a CK_ATTRIBUTE, the receiving entity may not allocate sufficient length for the buffer to store the deserialized value.
Vulnerable: 0.23.15-2
Fixed: 0.23.15-2_deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555690</td>
<td>The NET-SNMP-EXTEND-MIB, disabled in Cumulus Linux 4.2.1 and 3.7.14 to prevent security vulnerability CVE-2020-15862, is re-enabled read-only.</td>
<td>3.7.14-3.7.14.2, 4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555588</td>
<td>You can't delete a BGP community list created with NCLU.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555531</td>
<td>QinQ (802.1Q) packets routed to a layer 3 subinterface are still double tagged with the VLAN of the subinterface and the original inner VLAN when they leave the subinterface.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555528</td>
<td>In an EVPN Active/Active configuration, when one of the peers reboots and begins to refresh IP neighbor entries shared by the MLAG peer, some of these ARP messages might be dropped by the MLAG peer's ARP policer.
To work around this issue, increase the burst value of the ARP policers to 200 or higher.</td>
<td>3.7.14-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555506</td>
<td>CVE-2020-29479 CVE-2020-29480 CVE-2020-29481 CVE-2020-29482 CVE-2020-29483 CVE-2020-29484 CVE-2020-29485 CVE-2020-29486 CVE-2020-29566 CVE-2020-29570 CVE-2020-29571
Several security issues affecting Xenstore could result in cross domain access (denial of service, information leaks or privilege escalation) or denial of service against xenstored.
Additional vulnerabilities could result in guest-to-host denial of
service.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 4.11.4+57-g41a822c392-1
Fixed: 4.11.4+57-g41a822c392-2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555492</td>
<td>On Broadcom switches, when WARN level {{switchd}} log messages are generated, {{switchd}} might crash resulting in a core file generated on the system.</td>
<td>3.7.14</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555484</td>
<td>{{ospf6d}} restarts when you run the NCLU {{net show ospf6 databse}} command or the vtysh {{show ipv6 ospf6 database}} command. </td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555428</td>
<td>When you change the SVI {{vlan-id}} value in the {{/etc/network/interfaces}} file, then run {{ifreload -a}}, the 802.1Q ID for the SVI in the kernel does not change.
This operation is not supported in the kernel without recreating the SVI. To apply the change, run {{ifdown}}, then {{ifup}} for the SVI to recreate the interface.</td>
<td>3.7.13-3.7.15, 4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555426</td>
<td>Broadcom switches running Cumulus Linux do not support EVPN Multihoming. When a BGP update with EVPN multihoming attributes is received, {{switchd}} crashes. 
EVPN Multihoming is supported on Mellanox switches only.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555400</td>
<td>On the Edgecore AS7312 switch, eth0 and swp use the same MAC address.</td>
<td>3.7.14-3.7.14.2, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555380</td>
<td>When you start {{asic-monitor}}, you might see increasing memory usage.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555373</td>
<td>CVE-2020-27350: Missing input validation in the ar/tar implementations of APT, the high level package manager, could cause out-of-bounds reads or infinite loops, resulting in denial of service when processing malformed deb files.
CVE-2020-27351: Various memory and file descriptor leaks were discovered in the Python interface to the APT package management runtime library, which could result in denial of service.
Vulnerable: apt &lt;= 1.8.2.1, python-apt &lt;= 1.8.4.1
Fixed: apt 1.8.2.2, python-apt 1.8.4.3</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555339</td>
<td>The following vulnerability has been announced in OpenSSL:
CVE-2020-1971: A flaw in the GENERAL_NAME_cmp() function could cause a NULL dereference when both GENERAL_NAMEs contain an EDIPARTYNAME, resulting in denial of service.  More information can be found at https://www.openssl.org/news/secadv/20201208.txt .
Vulnerable: &lt;= 1.1.1d-0+deb10u3
Fixed: 1.1.1d-0+deb10u4</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555270</td>
<td>CVE-2020-27670 CVE-2020-27671 CVE-2020-27672 CVE-2020-27674 CVE-2020-28368: Multiple vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Xen hypervisor, which could result in denial of service, privilege escalation or information leaks.
Vulnerable: &lt; 4.11.4+57-g41a822c392-1
Fixed: 4.11.4+57-g41a822c392-1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555223</td>
<td>An EVPN route map filter matching a VNI on egress on the originating router might not set a large-community correctly:

route-map TEST-TAG permit 10
  match evpn vni 109001
  set large-community 20:20:333
!

To work around this issue, remove the VNI match to allow the tag to be applied on egress.
The VNI match works if applied at some other non-originating router either in the ingress or egress direction.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2555183</td>
<td>CVE-2020-8927: A buffer overflow exists in the Brotli library versions prior to 1.0.8 where an attacker controlling the input length of a "one-shot" decompression request to a script can trigger a crash, which happens when copying over chunks of data larger than 2 GiB.  If one cannot update to a fixed version, we recommend to use the "streaming" API as opposed to the "one-shot" API, and impose chunk size limits.
Vulnerable: 1.0.7-2
Fixed: 1.0.7-2+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554990</td>
<td>When running traditional mode bridges at scale (for example, when you have more than 200 bridges and a large number of MAC addresses), MLAG bonds flap intermittently from dual to single connected, then back to dual connected, which causes a layer 2 loop and STP state changes.
To work around this issue, either shut down one side of the MLAG bond or prune out VLANS over the bond.</td>
<td>3.7.13-3.7.14.2, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554982</td>
<td>CVE-2020-28196: MIT Kerberos 5 (aka krb5) before 1.17.2 and 1.18.x before 1.18.3 allows unbounded recursion via an ASN.1-encoded Kerberos message because the lib/krb5/asn.1/asn1_encode.c support for BER indefinite lengths lacks a recursion limit.
Vulnerable: 1.17-3
Fixed: 1.17-3+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554866</td>
<td>On the Mellanox SN3420 switch, 1000BaseT and 1000Base-SX/LX modules do not link up.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554834</td>
<td>CVE-2020-25709, CVE-2020-25710: Two vulnerabilities in the certificate list syntax verification and in the handling of CSN normalization were discovered in OpenLDAP, a free implementation of the Lightweight Directory Access Protocol. An unauthenticated remote attacker can take advantage of these flaws to cause a denial of service (slapd daemon crash) via specially crafted packets.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.4.47+dfsg-3+deb10u3
Fixed: 2.4.47+dfsg-3+deb10u4</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554809</td>
<td>Some non-Mellanox ethernet modules do not link up on the Mellanox SN3420 switch with Cumulus PSID in the Hardware revision. To see if a Mellanox SN3420 switch has the Cumulus PSID, check the output of {{mlxfwmanager}} for {{MSN3420-CxxxC_Ax}} in the {{Part Number}} Field.  A Mellanox SN3420 switch with {{MSN3420-CxxxO_Ax}} has an Onie PSID and is unaffected by this issue.
To work around this issue, use Mellanox ethernet modules with the Mellanox SN3420 switch,</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554785</td>
<td>After you reboot a Broadcom switch, {{switchd}} might fail to restart and you see logs in {{switchd.log}} similar to the following:

Nov 12 12:20:05.063876 leaf01 switchd[9867]:
Nov 12 12:20:05.064310 leaf01 switchd[9867]: hal_bcm_console.c:294 0:system_init:
Nov 12 12:20:05.064428 leaf01 switchd[9867]: hal_bcm_console.c:294 system_init: Misc init failed: Operation timed out
Nov 12 12:20:05.064464 leaf01 switchd[9867]:
Nov 12 12:20:05.091995 leaf01 switchd[9867]: hal_bcm_console.c:294 LED: Loading 256 bytes into LED program memory
Nov 12 12:20:05.092029 leaf01 switchd[9867]:
Nov 12 12:20:05.099547 leaf01 switchd[9867]: hal_bcm_console.c:294 PORT: Error: bcm ports not initialized
Nov 12 12:20:05.099579 leaf01 switchd[9867]:
Nov 12 12:20:05.099646 leaf01 switchd[9867]: hal_bcm_console.c:294 Error: file /var/lib/cumulus/rc.datapath_0: line 81 (error code -1): script terminated
Nov 12 12:20:05.099667 leaf01 switchd[9867]:
Nov 12 12:20:05.099775 leaf01 switchd[9867]: hal_bcm_console.c:294 Error: file /etc/bcm.d/rc.soc: line 70 (error code -1): script terminated
Nov 12 12:20:05.099798 leaf01 switchd[9867]:
Nov 12 12:20:05.099871 leaf01 switchd[9867]: hal_bcm_console.c:294 ERROR loading rc script on unit 0
Nov 12 12:20:05.099892 leaf01 switchd[9867]:
Nov 12 12:20:05.099943 leaf01 switchd[9867]: hal_bcm_console.c:299 CRIT loading of rc script failed, aborting!

To work around this issue, configure Cumulus Linux to boot with the {{ntel_iommu=off}} kernel command option:

1. Open the {{/etc/default/grub}} file with a text editor.
2. Edit the {{GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX}} variable by adding the string {{intel_iommu=off}} at the end.  For example: GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX="cl_platform=cel_e1031 console=ttyS1,115200n8 intel_iommu=off"
3. Run the {{update-grub}} command.
4. Reboot the switch.</td>
<td>3.7.11-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554730</td>
<td>In an EVPN multihoming configuration, reloading FRR causes brief traffic loss.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554720</td>
<td>If {{switchd}} successfully signals {{clagd}} that it is going down, {{clagd}} stops responding to keepalive echo requests from the peer instead of sending a good bye to the peer over both the peerlink and the backup switch. Eventually, the keepalive timer expires and the secondary switch becomes the primary, and brings the bonds and VNIs back up. However, if {{switchd}} does not successfully signal it is going down, (in the event of a crash), the primary switch continues to respond to keepalives, and the bonds and VNIs are down on both peers. </td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.14.2, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554711</td>
<td>On the Mellanox SN3700C switch, running {{cl-support}} with a large number of ports configured can cause {{switchd}} to crash.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554707</td>
<td>On the Dell S5048F-ON switch, optical transceivers do not come up and the modules are in reset mode.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554588</td>
<td>If you try to reconfigure a DHCP server after you delete the switch configuration with the {{net del all}} command, the {{dhcpd}} service fails because a duplicate process is running.
To work around this issue, edit the {{/usr/lib/python2.7/dist-packages/nclu/plugins/dhcp.py}} file to change:

DHCPD_PID="-pf {0}" 

to:

DHCPD_PID="-pf {1}"
</td>
<td>3.7.13-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554531</td>
<td>CVE-2020-25692: A vulnerability in the handling of normalization with modrdn was discovered in OpenLDAP, a free implementation of the Lightweight Directory Access Protocol. An unauthenticated remote attacker can use this flaw to cause a denial of service (slapd daemon crash) via a specially crafted packet.
The slapd package is not present in the image or repository, although the OpenLDAP libraries are present.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.4.47+dfsg-3+deb10u2
Fixed: 2.4.47+dfsg-3+deb10u3</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554503</td>
<td>If the peer link does not trunk all VLANs on an MLAG bond, all FDB entries learned through that MLAG bond are not redirected over the peer link when the MLAG bond goes down. As a result,  traffic destined to the MAC addresses that arrives on the MLAG peer with the downed MLAG port is dropped.
To work around this issue, ensure that the peer link trunks all VLANs that exist on all MLAG bonds.

</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554401</td>
<td>On the Mellanox SN4600C switch, the fan speed fluctuates when only one PSU is plugged in.
To work around this issue, use both PSUs.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554369</td>
<td>Certain Dell S4048-ON switches show an incorrect vendor name and hang when you issue the {{reboot}} command. </td>
<td>3.7.12-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554333</td>
<td>The INPUT chain POLICE target acts as ACCEPT instead of continue.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554307</td>
<td>The following vulnerability has been announced in freetype:
CVE-2020-15999: Sergei Glazunov discovered a heap-based buffer overflow vulnerability in the handling of embedded PNG bitmaps in FreeType. Opening malformed fonts may result in denial of service or the execution of arbitrary code.
Vulnerable: &lt;= 2.9.1-3+deb10u1
Fixed: 2.9.1-3+deb10u2</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554292</td>
<td>With traditional bridges, a race condition occurs when Cumulus Linux tries to derive MAC addresses.
To work around this issue, use a static MAC address; specify a MAC address in the {{/etc/network/interfaces}} file under the bridge's stanza.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554282</td>
<td>A security issue was discovered in the MariaDB database server.
Vulnerable: 10.3.25-0
Fixed: 10.3.25-0+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554258</td>
<td>Interfaces configured to get an IP address with DHCP try only three times to secure a DHCP lease (instead of retrying indefinitely). If unsuccessful after the third try, the switch stops trying.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554253</td>
<td>After upgrading the Mellanox SN2410 switch, the FAN is set to full speed.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554246</td>
<td>When you back up and restore a configuration using the conf-backup utility, the switch might hang when rebooted.</td>
<td>4.1.1-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2554131</td>
<td>CVE-2020-14355: Multiple buffer overflow vulnerabilities were found in the QUIC image decoding process of the SPICE remote display system, before spice-0.14.2-1.
Both the SPICE client (spice-gtk) and server are affected by these flaws. These flaws allow a malicious client or server to send specially crafted messages that, when processed by the QUIC image compression algorithm, result in a process crash or potential code execution.
Vulnerable: 0.14.0-1.3
Fixed: 0.14.0-1.3+deb10u1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553952</td>
<td>On Mellanox Spectrum based switches running 4.1.0 or higher, if FORWARD chain ACLs are configured on the system, a switch port breakout action applied with a reload of the switchd service may cause switchd to crash.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553878</td>
<td>Multiple vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Xen hypervisor, which could result in denial of service, guest-to-host privilege escalation or information leaks.  These include the following:CVE-2020-25595, CVE-2020-25596, CVE-2020-25597, CVE-2020-25599, CVE-2020-25600, CVE-2020-25601, CVE-2020-25602, CVE-2020-25603, CVE-2020-25604.
Vulnerable: &lt; 4.11.4+37-g3263f257ca-1
Fixed: 4.11.4+37-g3263f257ca-1</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553747</td>
<td>On switches with the Spectrum ASIC, the IPv6 default route might be present in the kernel but missing in 
hardware when IPv6 RAs are received on SVIs configured with {{ip-forward off}}.</td>
<td>3.7.11-3.7.14.2, 4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553742</td>
<td>The next hop for static routes configured in a non-default VRF might be incorrectly flagged as inactive. Remove and reconfigure the static VRF route to recover from this condition. </td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553731</td>
<td>A ping via a dual-connected bond fails, and the audio stream is not routed or encapsulated through the layer 3 VNI.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.13, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553586</td>
<td>Multicast traffic on a VPN is sent to remote VTEPs that are not part of the VPN and the remote VTEPs receive multicast traffic encapsulated in a VXLAN ID that doesn't exist.
To work around this issue, disable IGMP snooping on the switch.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.13, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553568</td>
<td>After a MAC address moves from one remote VTEP to another, the MAC address continues to point to the old VTEP IP address in hardware.</td>
<td>4.1.1-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553529</td>
<td>In an MLAG configuration with a layer 3 VNI, when you bounce the peer link, all layer 2 VNIs listed under the layer 3 VNI are duplicated. 
To work around this issue, restart FRR with the {{sudo systemctl restart frr.service}} command.

</td>
<td>3.7.10-3.7.13, 4.1.1-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553468</td>
<td>Digital Optical Monitoring (DOM) Data is displayed incorrectly on SFP fiber modules inserted in the Fiberstore N8500-48B6C, Celestica Questone, and Celestica RedstoneV switches.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553449</td>
<td>On the the Dell N3248-PXE switch, when you insert two PSUs at different times, the newly inserted PSU is detected as OK but the fan and temp sensors are ABSENT.
To work around this issue, remove power to both PSUs at the same time, then reinsert power simultaneously.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.13, 4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553349</td>
<td>When you delete a layer 2 VNI and VLAN, the layer 3 VNI reports an incorrect layer 2 VNI number.
To work around this issue, either restart FRR or delete the VNI interface first, then delete the VLAN/SVI.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553278</td>
<td>Leaked routes are sometimes missing from the destination VRF after a reboot.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553228</td>
<td>On the Dell N3248PXE switch, RJ45 fixed copper ports that auto-negotiate with a 100M or 10M neighbor incorrectly negotiate a half-duplex link that generates errors. Half duplex modes are not supported on this platform.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.13, 4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553219</td>
<td>You cannot configure SNMPv3 trap-destinations in non-default VRFs with an authentication username that contains fewer than eight characters.</td>
<td>3.7.12-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2553118</td>
<td>The Dell 100G-LR4 (Innolight) transceiver cannot link up due to a power budget exceeded error on the Mellanox SN4600C switch.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552939</td>
<td>RX_DRP on a bond interface increases without any data traffic while the slave port does not increase.</td>
<td>3.7.12-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552880</td>
<td>IPv6 TCP or UDP connections (sourcing from an ephemeral port in the range 34048 to 35071) are not forwarded if the switch has more than one layer 2 VNI defined. The traffic might be locally switched on the bridge and dropped. 
To work around this issue, disable ARP/ND suppression to remove the internal ACL rule that affects the ports.</td>
<td>3.7.13, 4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552869</td>
<td>On the Dell N3048EP switch, the module information from SFP ports is not displayed in the {{l1-show}} command.
To work around this issue, use the {{ethtool -m &lt;interface&gt;}} command.</td>
<td>3.7.13-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552853</td>
<td>Tenant VRF BGP peers appear in the EVPN RMAC and nexthop tables, which causes the kernel RMAC to point at invalid IP address.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.14.2, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552744</td>
<td>Several vulnerabilities have been discovered in the Linux kernel that may lead to a privilege escalation, denial of service or information leaks.
CVE-2020-14351 CVE-2020-29660 CVE-2020-29661 CVE-2020-25704 CVE-2020-28974 CVE-2020-25705 CVE-2020-28915 CVE-2020-25211 CVE-2019-19338 CVE-2020-0305 CVE-2019-18885 CVE-2019-19072 CVE-2020-12652 CVE-2020-24394 CVE-2020-25641 CVE-2019-3874 CVE-2019-5489. (CVE-2020-27825 CVE-2020-29369 CVE-2020-29372 CVE-2020-29534 are not applicable to Cumulus Linux)
For the detailed security status of linux,  refer to its security tracker page at: https://security-tracker.debian.org/tracker/linux</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552742</td>
<td>On the Mellanox SN2410 switch, you see {{switchd}} core and {{GBIN_MALLOC}} errors.
To work around this issue, restart {{switchd}}.</td>
<td>3.7.12-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552710</td>
<td>The MLAG bonds on a secondary switch do not change to a unique MAC address on the peerlink. As a result, a backup double failure can occur where both peers go down.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552704</td>
<td>In a traditional bridge configuration with {{ip-forward off}}, neighbors are synchronized to hardware with a {{switchd}} restart but are cleared when you flap the bridge interface.</td>
<td>3.7.10-3.7.14.2, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552687</td>
<td>When you boot Cumulus VX 4.2 for the first time, ZTP does not execute because it thinks that the {{/etc/shadow}} file has been modified. This is due to the default password change implemented in CL 4.2.
To work around this issue, boot the switch, manually change the password, then run {{sudo ztp -R}} to reset the ZTP script.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552527</td>
<td>Ingress SPAN/ERSPAN does not mirror packets when the next hop is EVPN encapsulated.</td>
<td>3.7.7-3.7.13, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2552354</td>
<td>On the Mellanox SN4700 switch, you might see _Bad signal integrity_ issues on 200G and 400G ports.</td>
<td>4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2551873</td>
<td>If you have an existing community list of any type, redefining the same sequence number results in the entire community list being deleted.
To work around this issue, delete the community list sequence before trying to adjust it.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2551747</td>
<td>In OVSDB high availability mode, deleting &gt; 200 VLAN bindings might cause {{ovs-vtepd}} to crash.  Limit the deletion to 200 or fewer VLAN bindings.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.13, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2551687</td>
<td>When you run {{cl-ecmpcalc}} to determine a hardware hash result, tests might fail.</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2551422</td>
<td>On Mellanox switches with the Spectrum-2 switch, the lpm-balanced forwarding profile does not work.</td>
<td>4.1.1-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2551187</td>
<td>dot1qVlanIndex in the dot1qVlanStaticTable of the SNMP Q-BRIDGE-MIB does not use VLAN ID and does not comply with RFC 4363.</td>
<td>4.1.1-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2551124</td>
<td>When the dynamic or static flag on a bridge fdb (MAC) entry is changed to the opposite state, the new flag is not set appropriately in hardware. This can allow a static fdb entry to be unexpectedly learned dynamically on a different interface, or can prevent a dynamic entry from being updated or learned elsewhere.
This condition can occur during a manual replacement of a local MAC address or when EVPN updates a dynamic MAC address to add or remove the Sticky Mac flag. Either situation results in the MAC address keeping the original flag in hardware.
To work around this issue, delete or withdraw the fdb entry, then add the static MAC address directly. For example:

bridge fdb del 50:6b:4b:ee:ee:ee dev swp31 vlan 24 master
bridge fdb add 50:6b:4b:ee:ee:ee dev swp31 vlan 24 master [ static | dynamic ]

If you are unable to delete an EVPN-learned remote MAC address, you can replace the dynamic MAC address with a local static one, then delete the static MAC address. For example:

bridge fdb replace 50:6b:4b:ee:ee:ee dev swp31 vlan 24 master static
bridge fdb del 50:6b:4b:ee:ee:ee dev swp31 vlan 24 master
bridge fdb add 50:6b:4b:ee:ee:ee dev swp31 vlan 24 master [ static | dynamic ]
</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550973</td>
<td>After you enable ROCE with the {{net add interface &lt;switch-port&gt; storage-optimized pfc}} command, you cannot verify the command because it is not shown in the {{net show config}} command output.</td>
<td>4.1.1-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550906</td>
<td>After you delete a bond, the deleted bond members have the deleted bond MAC address instead of their original MAC address, which might result in traffic being discarded. 
To work around this issue, perform a full switch restart.</td>
<td>4.1.1-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550796</td>
<td>On a Broadcom switch with the Trident2+ ASIC, ACL rules for VLANs are not applied after a reboot and the counters remain at zero.
To work around this issue, either do not set {{acl.non_atomic_update_mode = TRUE}} in the {{/etc/cumulus/switchd.conf}} file or run the {{cl-acltool -i}} command after the reboot to install the  ACLs.</td>
<td>3.7.12-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550478</td>
<td>VXLAN interface as in-interface or out-interface in an ACL is not supported in Spectrum-based switches.</td>
<td>3.7.7-4.2.0</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550374</td>
<td>CPU utilization may increase when clag-managed bond interfaces are operationally/LACP down but the physical carrier remains up on the bond member switchports. This condition occurs when clag bond redirection is enabled and bond members remain up while the parent bond does not negotiate LACP.

This issue is resolved in Cumulus Linux 3.7.14.</td>
<td>3.7.9-3.7.13, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550348</td>
<td>Due to a known limitation, DHCPv6 snooping is not supported on Mellanox platforms.
Please refer the Mellanox support case</td>
<td>4.2.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2550276</td>
<td>In LLDP, the {{snmp}} subagent loses all subsequent {{lldpRemSysName}} (1.0.8802.1.1.2.1.4.1.1.9) entries after an entry with a missing SysName is added.
All the information from {{lldpctl}} is correct. Only the entries after the entry that is missing a SysName in {{lldpRemSysName}} disappear from the {{snmp}} subagent.</td>
<td>3.7.12-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2549838</td>
<td>In vtysh, if you configure, then remove a layer 3 VNI for a VRF, the VNI is removed from zebra even if the VNI interface still exists in the kernel.
If you configure a layer 2 VNI as a layer 3 VNI by mistake, removing the layer 3 VNI binding removes it from zebra but EVPN-learned MACs and neighbors are not installed into the kernel.
To work around this issue, delete, then re-add the missing VNI. For example:

cumulus@switch:~$ sudo ifdown vni10100
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo ifup vni10100

If you flap the link with the {{ip link set vni10100 down; ip link set vni10100 up}} commands, zebra does not re-add the VNI.</td>
<td>3.7.12-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2549784</td>
<td>On Mellanox switches, when the networking service and {{switchd}} starts up, a rare condition might occur where {{switchd}} crashes and the following log message is generated:

{{CRIT backend/mlx/hal_mlx_nexthop.c:294: hal_mlx_ecmp_data_reinit: Assertion &apos;(num_next_hops)' failed.}}
</td>
<td>4.1.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2549225</td>
<td>You might see the following {{gport}} error messages in {{switchd.log}}:
{code}
2020-04-10T19:50:01.011224+09:00 E1PDX0V1ELF0001 6 switchd[925]: hal_bcm_mdb.c:530 gport 0x800007a find failed
2020-04-10T19:50:01.011631+09:00 E1PDX0V1ELF0001 6 switchd[925]: hal_bcm_mdb.c:530 gport 0x8000009 find failed
{code}
These messages are harmless and can be ignored.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.14.2, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2548930</td>
<td>On Mellanox Spectrum switches that contain an OSPF IP unnumbered neighborship with a high scale of prefixes being learned, a link flap might cause the neighbor entry to not be programmed in hardware.</td>
<td>3.7.11-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2548672</td>
<td>When a multipath route that contains an EVPN path exists together with an IPv4 BGP path in the VRF, the RMAC to VTEP binding is incorrect. This invalid entry occurs because Cumulus Linux treats IPv4 routes received over the eBGP IPv4 peering incorrectly in the VRF.
To work around this issue, remove the unnecessary eBGP IPv4 peering.</td>
<td>3.7.12-3.7.15, 4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2548485</td>
<td>If you configure the aggregate-address &lt;address&gt; summary-only option before injecting a component of the same aggregate into the BGP table with the {{network}} or {{redistribute}} command, when you remove the {{aggregate-address}} configuration, the component stays suppressed; it is not advertised to peers. For example:
Existing configuration:

router bgp 1
 address-family ipv4 unicast
  aggregate-address 50.0.0.0/8 summary-only
 exit-address-family

If you add {{network 50.0.0.1/32}}, you see the following (expected) BGP table entries:

Status codes: s suppressed, d damped, h history, * valid, &gt; best, = multipath,
              i internal, r RIB-failure, S Stale, R Removed
Origin codes: i - IGP, e - EGP, ? - incomplete
   Network          Next Hop            Metric LocPrf Weight Path
*&gt; 50.0.0.0         0.0.0.0                            32768 i
s&gt; 50.0.0.1/32      0.0.0.0                  0         32768 i

Removing {{aggregate-address 50.0.0.0/8 summary-only}} at this point results in the following (unexpected) BGP table entry:

Status codes: s suppressed, d damped, h history, * valid, &gt; best, = multipath,
              i internal, r RIB-failure, S Stale, R Removed
Origin codes: i - IGP, e - EGP, ? - incomplete
   Network          Next Hop            Metric LocPrf Weight Path
s&gt; 50.0.0.1/32      0.0.0.0                  0         32768 i

To work around this issue, remove, then re-add the component prefix routes.</td>
<td>3.7.12-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2548408</td>
<td>{{net show configuration commands}} does not show the RoCE {{net add interface &lt;swp&gt; storage-optimized pfc}} configuration.</td>
<td>4.1.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2547068</td>
<td>Hardware platforms using the Intel D-1500 CPU series might reboot unexpectedly.
To work around this issue, contact your hardware vendor to inquire if a new version of BIOS with a microcode fix is available or manually disable CPU C-states in the kernel as outlined below.
To permanently disable C-states using a kernel boot parameter:
1. Edit {{/etc/default/grub}} to add the argument {{processor.max_cstate=0}} to the variable {{GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX}}. For example, if {{/etc/default/grub}} file contains the line {{GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX="cl_platform=accton_as7726_32x console=tty0 console=ttyS0,115200n8 intel_iommu=off pcie_aspm=off"}}, change it to {{GRUB_CMDLINE_LINUX="cl_platform=accton_as7726_32x console=tty0 console=ttyS0,115200n8 intel_iommu=off pcie_aspm=off processor.max_cstate=0"}}
2. Run {{sudo update-grub}}.
3. Reboot the system with {{sudo reboot}}.
To disable cstates in realtime on the current system, which does not persist through a reboot:
1. Confirm that the libpci3 package is installed. Run {{dpkg-query -l libpci3}} and confirm the following line is displayed:
{{ii  libpci3:amd64      1:3.2.1-3      amd64          Linux PCI Utilities (shared library)}}
The first field above should read {{ii}}. If not, install the libpci3 package by running {{sudo apt upgrade;sudo apt install libpci3}}.
2. Disable C-states by running the command {{./cpupower idle-set -d 2}}.
C-states are disabled by default in Cumulus Linux 4.3.0 and later.</td>
<td>3.7.9-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2543647</td>
<td>ERSPAN in ebtables does not work for VNIs. For example, the following rule does not work:

-A FORWARD -i vni10 -j erspan --src-ip 100.1.1.2 --dst-ip 100.1.1.1 --ttl 64
</td>
<td>3.7.6-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2534977</td>
<td>On the Mellanox switch, the destination MAC address of ERSPAN GRE packets is set to all zeros; therefore, the first transit switch might drop packets.</td>
<td>4.0.0-4.2.1</td>
</tr>
</table>
</tables>