<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Network Troubleshooting on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-linux-31/Monitoring-and-Troubleshooting/Network-Troubleshooting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Network Troubleshooting on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-linux-31/Monitoring-and-Troubleshooting/Network-Troubleshooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using netshow to Troubleshoot Your Network Configuration</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-linux-31/Monitoring-and-Troubleshooting/Network-Troubleshooting/Using-netshow-to-Troubleshoot-Your-Network-Configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-linux-31/Monitoring-and-Troubleshooting/Network-Troubleshooting/Using-netshow-to-Troubleshoot-Your-Network-Configuration/</guid>
      <description>netshow is a tool in Cumulus Linux that quickly returns a lot of information about your network configuration. It&amp;rsquo;s a tool designed by network operators for network troubleshooters since existing command line tools have too many options. netshow addresses this by leveraging the network troubleshooting experience from a wide group of troubleshooters and boiling it down to just a few important options. netshow quickly aggregates basic network information on Linux devices with numerous interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring System Statistics and Network Traffic with sFlow</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-linux-31/Monitoring-and-Troubleshooting/Network-Troubleshooting/Monitoring-System-Statistics-and-Network-Traffic-with-sFlow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-linux-31/Monitoring-and-Troubleshooting/Network-Troubleshooting/Monitoring-System-Statistics-and-Network-Traffic-with-sFlow/</guid>
      <description>sFlow is a monitoring protocol that samples network packets, application operations, and system counters. sFlow collects both interface counters and sampled 5-tuple packet information, enabling you to monitor your network traffic as well as your switch state and performance metrics. An outside server, known as an sFlow collector, is required to collect and analyze this data.
hsflowd is the daemon that samples and sends sFlow data to configured collectors. hsflowd is not included in the base Cumulus Linux installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using netq to Troubleshoot the Network</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-linux-31/Monitoring-and-Troubleshooting/Network-Troubleshooting/Using-netq-to-Troubleshoot-the-Network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/version/cumulus-linux-31/Monitoring-and-Troubleshooting/Network-Troubleshooting/Using-netq-to-Troubleshoot-the-Network/</guid>
      <description>Early Access Feature
netq is an early access feature in Cumulus Linux 3.1. Before you can install netq, you must enable the Early Access repository. For more information about the Cumulus Linux repository, read this knowledge base article.
 netq is a tool for troubleshooting the whole network fabric. Instead of using other tools to troubleshoot node by node, netq aggregates data from across all the nodes in a network, so you can query and diagnose issues affecting the whole network, analyze outages or discover why two or more switches cannot communicate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>