<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authentication, Authorization and Accounting on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authentication, Authorization and Accounting on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH for Remote Access</title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/SSH_for_Remote_Access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/SSH_for_Remote_Access/</guid>
      <description>You can generate authentication keys to access a Cumulus Linux switch securely with the ssh-keygen component of the Secure Shell (SSH) protocol. Cumulus Linux uses the OpenSSH package to provide this functionality. This section describes how to generate an SSH key pair.
Generate an SSH Key Pair  To generate the SSH key pair, run the ssh-keygen command and follow the prompts:
To configure a completely passwordless system, do not enter a passphrase when prompted in the following step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Accounts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/User_Accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/User_Accounts/</guid>
      <description>By default, Cumulus Linux has two user accounts: cumulus and root.
The cumulus account:
 Uses the default password *CumulusLinux\!*  Is a user account in the sudo group with sudo privileges.
 Can log in to the system through all the usual channels, such as console and SSH.
 Along with the cumulus group, has both show and edit rights for NCLU.
  The root account:
 Has the default password disabled by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using sudo to Delegate Privileges</title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/Using_sudo_to_Delegate_Privileges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/Using_sudo_to_Delegate_Privileges/</guid>
      <description>By default, Cumulus Linux has two user accounts: root and cumulus. The cumulus account is a normal user and is in the group sudo.
You can add more user accounts as needed. Like the cumulus account, these accounts must use sudo to execute privileged commands.
sudo Basics sudo allows you to execute a command as superuser or another user as specified by the security policy. See man sudo(8) for details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LDAP Authentication and Authorization</title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/LDAP_Authentication_and_Authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/LDAP_Authentication_and_Authorization/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus Linux uses Pluggable Authentication Modules (PAM) and Name Service Switch (NSS) for user authentication.
NSS specifies the order of information sources used to resolve names for each service. Using this with authentication and authorization, it provides the order and location used for user lookup and group mapping on the system. PAM handles the interaction between the user and the system, providing login handling, session setup, authentication of users, and authorization of user actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TACACS Plus</title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/TACACS_Plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/TACACS_Plus/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus Linux implements TACACS+ client AAA (Accounting, Authentication, and Authorization) in a transparent way with minimal configuration. The client implements the TACACS+ protocol as described in this IETF document. There is no need to create accounts or directories on the switch. Accounting records are sent to all configured TACACS+ servers by default. Use of per-command authorization requires additional setup on the switch.
Supported Features  Authentication using PAM; includes login, ssh, sudo and su</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RADIUS AAA</title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/RADIUS_AAA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus_Linux/System_Configuration/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/RADIUS_AAA/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus Networks offers add-on packages that enable RADIUS users to log in to Cumulus Linux switches in a transparent way with minimal configuration. There is no need to create accounts or directories on the switch. Authentication is handled with PAM and includes login, ssh, sudo and su.
Install the RADIUS Packages The RADIUS packages are not included in the base Cumulus Linux image; there is no RADIUS metapackage.
To install the RADIUS packages:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>