<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development Environments on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Development-Environments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development Environments on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Development-Environments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant and VirtualBox</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Development-Environments/Vagrant-and-VirtualBox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Development-Environments/Vagrant-and-VirtualBox/</guid>
      <description>This document describes how to install and set up Cumulus Linux within a Vagrant environment, using VirtualBox as the hypervisor.
These sections assume a basic level of Vagrant, VirtualBox, and Linux experience. For detailed instructions, refer to the Vagrant documentation and the getting started guide.
 Configure the Vagrant Environment This section assumes that you have installed the VirtualBox hypervisor. For detailed instructions, refer to the VirtualBox installation section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant and Libvirt with KVM or QEMU</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Development-Environments/Vagrant-and-Libvirt-with-KVM-or-QEMU/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Development-Environments/Vagrant-and-Libvirt-with-KVM-or-QEMU/</guid>
      <description>The solution described in this chapter requires four components:
 libvirt provides an abstraction language to define and launch VMs, but is normally used just to launch single VMs. It uses XML to represent and define the VM.
 KVM w orks exclusively with QEMU and p erforms hardware acceleration for x86 VMs with Intel and AMD CPUs. KVM and QEMU are hypervisors that emulate the VMs; t he pair is often called KVM/QEMU or just KVM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 and VirtualBox</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Development-Environments/GNS3-and-VirtualBox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Development-Environments/GNS3-and-VirtualBox/</guid>
      <description>Before you run your virtual network under GNS3, make sure you:
 Download and install VirtualBox.
 Download the VirtualBox OVA image and import all the VMs that you want to run in GNS3 into VirtualBox.
 Download and install GNS3.
  GNS3 overwrites the interface names that are configured in VirtualBox. If you want to use the VMs in VirtualBox and GNS3, consider cloning them first.
 To run your virtual network under GNS3:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNS3 and QEMU - KVM</title>
      <link>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Development-Environments/GNS3-and-QEMU-KVM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>docs.cumulusnetworks.com/cumulus-vx/Development-Environments/GNS3-and-QEMU-KVM/</guid>
      <description>Before you run your virtual network under GNS3, make sure you:
 Download and install KVM.
 Download the the Cumulus VX QCOW2 image.
 Download and install GNS3.
  To run your virtual network under GNS3:
 Start GNS3.
 In GNS3, select GNS3 &amp;gt; Preferences. The Preferences dialog opens. From the left pane, select QEMU VMs, then click New. The VM list shows the KVM VMs that you set up earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>